<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>Bilbao, Spain &#8211; The Fun Plan</title>
	<atom:link href="/en/destinations/spain/bilbao/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/en</link>
	<description>Crafting Moments, Creating Memories: Your Guide to Flawless Events.</description>
	<lastbuilddate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 07:44:04 +0000</lastbuilddate>
	<language>in-GB</language>
	<sy:updateperiod>
	hourly	</sy:updateperiod>
	<sy:updatefrequency>
	1	</sy:updatefrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/09/favi.png</url>
	<title>Bilbao, Spain &#8211; The Fun Plan</title>
	<link>/en</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>5 Historical Jewels You Must See in Casco Viejo Bilbao</title>
		<link>/en/historical-sites-in-old-town-bilbao/</link>
					<comments>/en/historical-sites-in-old-town-bilbao/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 15:35:03 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bilbao, Spain]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=1248</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Imagina pasear por las encantadoras calles del Casco Viejo en Bilbao, descubriendo joyas históricas ocultas que te transportan a una época pasada. Desde la vibrante Plaza Nueva, llena de vida, hasta la impresionante Catedral de Santiago, cada lugar cuenta una historia del rico pasado de la ciudad. Disfruta de las delicias culinarias del Mercado De...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Imagine strolling through the charming streets of Casco Viejo in Bilbao, discovering hidden historical gems that transport you to a bygone era.</p>



<p>From the vibrant Plaza Nueva, full of life, to the impressive Cathedral of Santiago, each place tells a story from the city&#039;s rich past.</p>



<p>Enjoy the culinary delights of Mercado De La Ribera and immerse yourself in the arts at the Teatro Arriaga.</p>



<p>As you cross the iconic La Ribera Bridge, connecting the past and present, you will feel a sense of freedom and liberation.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Key points</h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Plaza Nueva is the heart of Casco Viejo, with its elegant neoclassical buildings and cobblestone streets that create a charming atmosphere.</li>



<li>The Cathedral of Santiago is a Gothic masterpiece, displaying impressive spiers and beautiful stained glass windows.</li>



<li>Mercado De La Ribera is a culinary delight, offering fresh seafood, artisan cheeses, traditional pintxos and vibrant stalls filled with fruits and vegetables.</li>



<li>The Arriaga Theater is a symbol of culture and history, with its impressive neoclassical façade and ornate interior design.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Plaza Nueva: The heart of the Old Town</h2>



<p>If you are looking to explore the heart of Casco Viejo, be sure to visit Plaza Nueva, a historic gem that you cannot miss in Bilbao.</p>



<p>Plaza Nueva has great historical importance, as it was built at the beginning of the 19th century to replace the old medieval market square. This vibrant square has seen important events over the years, such as public meetings, markets and even bullfights.</p>



<p>Its architectural charm is undeniable, with elegant neoclassical buildings surrounding a spacious plaza. Take a stroll through the cobblestone streets and admire the grand facades adorned with intricate details.</p>



<p>Arched porches provide shade and shelter, inviting you to linger and soak up the atmosphere.</p>



<p>Plaza Nueva is not just a place to visit, but a place to feel the energy of Bilbao&#039;s past and present coming together in perfect harmony.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Santiago Cathedral: A Gothic masterpiece</h2>



<p>As you continue your exploration of Casco Viejo, be sure to marvel at the Gothic masterpiece that is the Cathedral of Santiago. This magnificent cathedral has immense historical importance in Bilbao and is a must-see for any history enthusiast.</p>



<p>Built in the 14th century, it has stood the test of time and stands as a testament to the architectural prowess of the era. The cathedral&#039;s towering spiers and intricate stone carvings showcase the details and craftsmanship of Gothic architecture.</p>



<p>Step inside and be captivated by the beautiful stained glass windows that fill the interior with a kaleidoscope of colors. Take a moment to reflect in the quiet serenity of the cathedral and soak up the rich history that surrounds you.</p>



<p>The Cathedral of Santiago is truly a gem that you cannot miss during your visit to Casco Viejo.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Mercado De La Ribera: a culinary delight</h2>



<p>When you visit Casco Viejo Bilbao, you will discover that Mercado De La Ribera is a culinary delight. This bustling market is a hub of gastronomic wonders, offering a wide variety of fresh produce, local delicacies and traditional sweets.</p>



<p>Here are five reasons why Mercado De La Ribera should be on your must-visit list:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Fresh seafood</strong>: The market is famous for its fresh catches from the Bay of Biscay. Enjoy succulent prawns, delicious sardines and juicy cod.</li>



<li><strong>Artisanal cheeses</strong>: Try a variety of rich, creamy cheeses from Basque farms. From mild and tangy to bold and tangy, there&#039;s a cheese for every palate.</li>



<li><strong>Traditional pintxos</strong>: Immerse yourself in local culinary traditions by enjoying pintxos, Basque-style tapas. Try the classic Gilda, made with olives, anchovies and pickled peppers.</li>



<li><strong>Fresh products</strong>: Explore the vibrant stalls filled with seasonal fruits, vegetables and herbs. Bring home some juicy tomatoes or aromatic spices.</li>



<li><strong>Delicious sweets</strong>: Don&#039;t miss the opportunity to savor traditional Basque desserts such as creamy rice pudding and indulgent almond cakes.</li>
</ul>



<p>At Mercado De La Ribera, you will experience the intense flavors and culinary heritage of Bilbao, making it a must-see destination for food lovers.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Teatro Arriaga: Where Culture Meets History</h2>



<p>The Arriaga Theater in Casco Viejo Bilbao is a cultural landmark that impeccably intertwines history and artistic skill. This magnificent theater, named in honor of the renowned composer Juan Crisóstomo Arriaga, is not only a center for cultural performances, but also has great architectural importance.</p>



<p>Built in the late 19th century, the theater displays a stunning neoclassical façade, adorned with intricate details and sculptures. Upon entering, you will be captivated by the grandeur of its interior, with its ornate decorations and elegant design.</p>



<p>The Arriaga Theater has witnessed countless performances, from ballets to operas, and continues to be a symbol of artistic expression and creativity.</p>



<p>Whether you are a theater enthusiast or simply appreciate the beauty of historic buildings, a visit to the Arriaga Theater is a must when exploring Casco Viejo Bilbao.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The La Ribera Bridge: Connecting the Past and the Present</h2>



<p>Now, let&#039;s explore how the La Ribera Bridge seamlessly connects the past and present in Casco Viejo Bilbao. This architectural wonder has great historical importance and serves as a symbol of the city&#039;s evolution over time.</p>



<p>Here are five reasons why the bridge is a must-see:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Connecting architecture</strong>: La Ribera Bridge elegantly combines old and new, with its modern and elegant design that harmonizes perfectly with the historic surroundings.</li>



<li><strong>Historical importance</strong>: The bridge is located on the site of the city&#039;s oldest bridge, which dates back to the 14th century, connecting the medieval neighborhood with the rest of Bilbao.</li>



<li><strong>Impressive sights</strong>: From the bridge, you can enjoy panoramic views of the Nervión River and its picturesque promenade, offering a unique perspective of Bilbao&#039;s urban landscape.</li>



<li><strong>Pedestrian friendly</strong>: La Ribera Bridge prioritizes pedestrians, providing a safe and pleasant crossing experience, allowing visitors to take their time and admire the beauty of the area.</li>



<li><strong>Improved accessibility</strong>: The bridge improves accessibility within Casco Viejo, making it easier for locals and tourists alike to explore the historic district and discover its hidden treasures.</li>
</ul>



<p>The La Ribera Bridge is not only a means of transportation; It is an architectural masterpiece that seamlessly connects the past and present, offering a gateway to the rich history and vibrant culture of Casco Viejo Bilbao.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Frequent questions</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">How do I get to Casco Viejo Bilbao?</h3>



<p>To get to Casco Viejo Bilbao, you have several transportation options. Popular routes include taking a taxi, using public transportation like buses or trains, or simply walking if you are nearby.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Is there a hotel or accommodation near Casco Viejo Bilbao?</h3>



<p>There are many hotels and accommodations near Casco Viejo Bilbao. You&#039;ll find a variety of options to choose from, from affordable to luxurious. You can be sure that you will have a comfortable stay in the heart of this historic neighborhood.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What are some other attractions or landmarks to visit in Bilbao?</h3>



<p>When exploring Bilbao, don&#039;t miss the top-rated restaurants spread throughout the city. And if you&#039;re in Casco Viejo, you&#039;ll find the best shopping spots to satisfy your retail therapy needs. Enjoy!</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Are there any guided tours or walking tours available in Casco Viejo Bilbao?</h3>



<p>Looking for guided tours or walking tours in Casco Viejo Bilbao? You&#039;re lucky! There are many options available so you can explore this historic gem at your own pace and discover its hidden treasures.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Are there any restrictions or guidelines for visiting the historical sites in Casco Viejo Bilbao?</h3>



<p>When visiting the historical sites in Casco Viejo Bilbao, it is important to know and expect certain restrictions and guidelines. Here are some tips for exploring historic gems: be respectful, follow any posted rules, and take care of the sites.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h2>



<p>So there you have it, my friend. These five historic gems in Casco Viejo Bilbao are truly an impressive sight.</p>



<p>From the bustling Plaza Nueva to the majestic Santiago Cathedral, each place has its own charm and unique beauty.</p>



<p>And let&#039;s not forget the irresistible delicacies at the Mercado De La Ribera or the cultural experiences at the Teatro Arriaga.</p>



<p>Finally, the La Ribera Bridge unites everything, connecting the past with the present.</p>



<p>So don&#039;t miss the opportunity to explore these incredible historical treasures during your visit to Casco Viejo Bilbao.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/historical-sites-in-old-town-bilbao/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>