<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>Mallorca, Spain &#8211; The Fun Plan</title>
	<atom:link href="/en/destinations/spain/mallorca/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/en</link>
	<description>Crafting Moments, Creating Memories: Your Guide to Flawless Events.</description>
	<lastbuilddate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 03:15:02 +0000</lastbuilddate>
	<language>in-GB</language>
	<sy:updateperiod>
	hourly	</sy:updateperiod>
	<sy:updatefrequency>
	1	</sy:updatefrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/09/favi.png</url>
	<title>Mallorca, Spain &#8211; The Fun Plan</title>
	<link>/en</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Beaches and coves to get lost in Mallorca</title>
		<link>/en/beaches-coves-get-lost-in-mallorca/</link>
					<comments>/en/beaches-coves-get-lost-in-mallorca/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 10:24:35 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Mallorca, Spain]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=2606</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mallorca es uno de los destinos predilectos de aquellos viajeros que desean huir del bullicio, el gentío y las playas abarrotadas de familias. Si viajáis a Mallorca, tendréis la suerte de encontrar aquellos paraísos escondidos para disfrutar de unas vacaciones de relax y ensueño en las Baleares. Os chivamos nuestras 6 playas y 6 calas...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mallorca is one of the favorite destinations for travelers who want to escape the hustle and bustle, the crowds and the beaches crowded with families. If you travel to Mallorca, you will be lucky enough to find those hidden paradises to enjoy a relaxing and dreamlike vacation in the Balearic Islands. We tell you about our 6 beaches and 6 coves where you will live a summer dream.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">6 beaches to get lost in Mallorca</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">PALM BEACH</h3>



<p>It is the largest beach in the capital. With fine sand and crystal clear water, you will have to make room among the hammocks to find a place and relax. An ideal place to have an aperitif while enjoying the eastern sun. It is also perfect to take advantage and try some water sports.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">SA CALOBRA</h3>



<p>The view from this beach is unbeatable: the Sierra de Tramuntana accompanies the landscape. You will reach it through a tunnel next to the cliffs. You will be impressed with the view after the mouth of the Torrent de Pareis.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">FORMENTOR BEACH</h3>



<p>If you want to enjoy the beach and coves in equal measure, then go to the port of Pollença where you will come across Formentor beach. Transparent waters bathe the sand. If you prefer to escape the hustle and bustle of the crowd, you can walk to Cala del Pi de la Posada or Cala Formentor.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">CAN PERE ANTONI BEACH</h3>



<p>It is located just two kilometers from the capital, La Palma, in a spectacular setting as a backdrop: the palm trees of Pº Marítimo, the silhouette of the Gothic Cathedral of Palma and the Episcopal Palace. You will enjoy an environment that seems straight out of a dream.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">ES TRENC BEACH</h3>



<p>If you like walking, go to Es Trenc Beach. Three and a half kilometers of white sand bathe its waters with a dreamlike landscape. If the weather is good you can see the island of Cabrera and wallow among the dunes at the same time. Send us your selfie to #FunPlanMallorca!</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">CALÓ DES MORO</h3>



<p>Only if you are to the south will you enjoy this beach, present in Santanyí. We recommend getting up early to avoid the crowds since it is one of the busiest beaches during the summer. Be sure to visit Es Pontàs, a rock eroded by the waves that looks like a bridge in the water.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">6 coves to get lost in Mallorca</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">CALA BANYALBUFAR</h3>



<p>A freshwater waterfall tops this dreamlike landscape. To get to it you must travel 17 kilometers from Valldemossa. A hidden place with a special charm, perfect for a summer getaway.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">CALA DEIÀ</h3>



<p>If you like trends and want to know where famous people spend their summers, this is your place. Not only will you enjoy the heat, the sun and the sea, but you may even share a dip with some celebrity. Eye! The white sand disappears giving way to gravel. We recommend you walk through it and soak up its fishing tradition.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">CALA MESQUIDA</h3>



<p>We only give you one piece of information: in 1991 Cala Mesquida was declared a Corner of Special Tourist Interest by the Balearic Parliament. To get to it you must travel 7 kilometers from Capdepera. It&#039;s worth a visit, right?</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">CALA MENDIA</h3>



<p>If you are one of those who like natural environments and the mountains, go to Manacor where you will find Cala Mendia. You will be surprised by its surroundings since it is more like a natural pool bathed in white and blue tones. *Funplaner recommendation: from Cala Mendia you can visit Cala Anguila by swimming.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">CALA COMTESSA</h3>



<p>Another point on the island very frequented by Celebrities. A hidden corner in a landscape of pine trees and rocks that surround this white sand paradise. Place frequented by the island&#039;s VIPs. *Funplaner recommendation: if you want to rub shoulders with high standing, come to Puerto Portals.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">CALA ESTÀNCIA</h3>



<p>Cala Estancia is part of a unique setting. A natural pool 3 meters deep and fine white sand. You can escape if you are passing through for the summer in the tourist area of Can Pastilla.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/beaches-coves-get-lost-in-mallorca/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Nightlife guide: the best nightclubs near Mallorca&#039;s stunning beaches</title>
		<link>/en/nightclubs-open-late-near-the-beaches-of-mallorca-spain/</link>
					<comments>/en/nightclubs-open-late-near-the-beaches-of-mallorca-spain/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 15:31:14 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Mallorca, Spain]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=1243</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Prepárate para bailar toda la noche bajo las estrellas brillantes y sentir el ritmo de la música en tus venas. Las impresionantes playas de Mallorca no son solo para tomar el sol, cobran vida después del anochecer con una animada vida nocturna que liberará tu espíritu. Desde los clubes nocturnos más populares en Palma hasta...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Get ready to dance the night away under the bright stars and feel the rhythm of music in your veins.</p>



<p>Mallorca&#039;s stunning beaches aren&#039;t just for sunbathing, they come to life after dark with lively nightlife that will free your spirit.</p>



<p>From the hottest nightclubs in Palma to the hidden gems in Alcudia, this nightlife guide will take you to the best nightclubs near Mallorca&#039;s stunning coasts.</p>



<p>Get ready to experience the freedom of the night.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Key points</h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Mallorca has a lively night scene with famous clubs attracting international DJs and celebrities.</li>



<li>Palma is home to some of the most popular nightclubs with vibrant atmospheres and pulsating music.</li>



<li>Magaluf is known for its vibrant nightlife and is home to some of the most popular beach clubs in Mallorca.</li>



<li>Alcudia has hidden gems frequented by locals, offering a unique experience.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Club scene in Mallorca</h2>



<p>If you&#039;re looking for an all-night party, Mallorca&#039;s club scene won&#039;t disappoint. Known for its lively nightlife and energetic atmosphere, Mallorca has earned a reputation as one of the top party destinations in Europe. From world-renowned clubs to intimate beachfront venues, there&#039;s something for everyone looking for an unforgettable night out.</p>



<p>Mallorca&#039;s reputation for clubs is well deserved, with some of the most famous clubs attracting international DJs and celebrities. Filled with pulsating beats, dazzling lights, and enthusiastic crowds, these venues create an electrifying experience that will keep you dancing until dawn. Whether you prefer popular hits or underground sounds, you&#039;ll find a wide variety of music genres to suit your taste.</p>



<p>When it comes to nightclub dress etiquette, Mallorca has a relaxed and casual atmosphere. While some clubs may have more specific dress requirements, most venues allow you to express your personal style. So feel free to dress up or down, depending on your mood and the type of club you&#039;re visiting. Just remember to wear comfortable shoes because you will be on your feet all night.</p>



<p>In Mallorca&#039;s club scene, freedom is the key. So get ready to let loose, dance like no one is watching, and create memories that will last a lifetime.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The most popular nightclubs in Palma.</h2>



<p>Get ready to experience the trendiest club scene in Palma, where the hottest nightclubs await you. These clubs are known for their vibrant atmosphere, pulsating music, and energetic crowds.</p>



<p>Talented local DJs will keep you moving all night, ensuring an unforgettable night of dancing and fun.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">More modern club scene</h3>



<p>Discover the most popular nightclubs in Palma, where you can dance all night and experience the hottest club scene on the island. Palma is known for its lively nightlife and offers some of the most exciting late night party trends.</p>



<p>The city is constantly evolving and new trendy places to party are always emerging. Whether you like techno, house music or hip-hop, Palma has something for everyone.</p>



<p>One of the hottest clubs to visit is Pacha Mallorca, an internationally renowned venue that hosts top DJs and epic parties.</p>



<p>Another place you must visit is Tito&#039;s Palma, a legendary nightclub with stunning views of the city and a diverse musical selection.</p>



<p>If you are looking for a more exclusive experience, head to Social Club Mallorca, a hidden gem that offers a luxurious and intimate atmosphere.</p>



<p>Get ready to dance until the wee hours of the morning and be part of the hottest club scene in Palma.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Local DJ talent</h3>



<p>Continue the party at Palma&#039;s most popular nightclubs, where you can enjoy the talent of local DJs and dance the night away.</p>



<p>Palma is known for its lively night scene, and the city is home to some of the most exciting clubs in Mallorca. These clubs showcase the best of local DJ talent, creating an electrifying atmosphere that will keep you dancing all night long.</p>



<p>One of the highlights of nightlife in Palma are the upcoming events featuring renowned DJs from the local scene. These events bring together music lovers and partiers, offering a unique opportunity to witness the incredible talent of local DJs.</p>



<p>You can expect to hear a variety of genres, from house and techno to hip-hop and R&amp;B. Local DJ competitions also add an extra level of excitement to the nightlife scene, as emerging DJs compete for the chance to showcase their skills and gain recognition.</p>



<p>With their pulsating energy and diverse music scene, Palma&#039;s nightclubs are the ideal destination for those looking for an unforgettable night out. So put on your dancing shoes and get ready to experience the incredible talent of local DJs that Palma has to offer.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Clubs next to the beach in Magaluf</h2>



<p>Ready for a beach party? Magaluf is home to some of the hottest seaside clubs in Mallorca. Whether you&#039;re looking for a wild, energetic vibe or a more laid-back vibe, these clubs have you covered.</p>



<p>Get ready to dance the night away and enjoy the electrifying nightlife that Magaluf has to offer.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Recommendations of popular beachside clubs.</h3>



<p>Check out the vibrant beachside clubs in Magaluf for an unforgettable nighttime experience close to Mallorca&#039;s stunning beaches.</p>



<p>Magaluf is known for its lively atmosphere and vibrant nightlife, making it the perfect destination for those looking for an exciting beachside clubbing experience. With its beautiful sandy shores and crystal clear waters, Magaluf offers a unique setting to enjoy partying until the early hours of the morning.</p>



<p>One of the most popular beachside clubs in Magaluf is BCM Planet Dance, which features world-class DJs and a huge dance floor.</p>



<p>Another club you can&#039;t miss is Nikki Beach Mallorca, known for its luxurious beach surroundings and rooftop party spaces. Here you can dance under the stars while enjoying stunning views of the Mediterranean Sea.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Atmosphere and night energy</h3>



<p>Experience the electrifying atmosphere and vibrant vibes at the beachside clubs in Magaluf. When it comes to nightlife trends and party spots, this lively destination does not disappoint. Here&#039;s what you can expect from the atmosphere and nightlife:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Non-stop energy: As the sun sets, the beachside clubs in Magaluf come to life with pulsating music, neon lights and an infectious energy that will have you dancing until the early hours of the morning.</li>



<li>Unforgettable Parties: Get ready for unforgettable nights filled with themed parties, live performances from world-renowned DJs, and a lively crowd ready to have the time of their lives.</li>



<li>Freedom and liberation: The beachside clubs in Magaluf embrace a spirit of freedom, where you can let loose, express yourself and dance like no one is watching.</li>
</ul>



<p>Get ready to immerse yourself in the vibrant atmosphere and unforgettable parties at the best beachside clubs in Magaluf.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Hidden gems in Alcudia</h2>



<p>When you are exploring Alcudia, be sure to visit these hidden gems that are frequented by locals and offer a unique experience.</p>



<p>One of the best ways to really immerse yourself in the local culture is by trying the delicious cuisine of the best local restaurants in Alcudia. From traditional tapas bars to seafood restaurants, there is something for every palate.</p>



<p>El Patio is a charming restaurant hidden in the heart of Alcudia&#039;s Old Town, known for its succulent grilled meats and cozy atmosphere.</p>



<p>For seafood lovers, La Terraza del Sol is a must-visit, offering a stunning view of the port and a menu packed with fresh catches of the day.</p>



<p>These hidden gems will not only satisfy your hunger, but will also leave you with lasting memories of the vibrant food scene in Alcudia.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Vibrant nightlife in Santa Ponsa</h2>



<p>If you&#039;re looking for a vibrant nightlife experience in Santa Ponsa, head to the best nightclubs near Mallorca&#039;s stunning beaches. Get ready to dance the night away and immerse yourself in the energetic atmosphere of this lively city.</p>



<p>Here are the best party spots you can&#039;t miss:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Club Santa Ponsa</strong>: This iconic venue offers a wide range of vibrant nightlife events, from live DJ sets to themed parties. Get ready to move to the rhythm of the latest hits and enjoy their impressive selection of drinks.</li>



<li><strong>Pirates Adventure</strong>: For a unique nightlife experience, head to Pirates Adventure. This interactive dinner show combines acrobatics, dancing and music, creating an unforgettable night of entertainment.</li>



<li><strong>The Square</strong>: Located in the heart of Santa Ponsa, The Square is a popular meeting place for locals and tourists alike. With its lively atmosphere and variety of bars and clubs, it is the perfect place to spend a night out.</li>
</ul>



<p>Get ready to have the time of your life at these vibrant nightlife spots in Santa Ponsa!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Fashion clubs in Cala D&#039;or</h2>



<p>Check out the trendy clubs in Cala D&#039;or and dance the night away to the hottest beats.</p>



<p>Cala D&#039;or is known for its lively night scene, with a variety of trendy bars and clubs offering unique party experiences. Whether you like electronic music, hip-hop or Latin rhythms, you will find a club that suits your tastes in Cala D&#039;or.</p>



<p>A popular spot is the iconic Bar Central, where you can enjoy live music performances and dance until the early hours of the morning.</p>



<p>Another club that you cannot miss is La Havana, a lively place that combines good music with a relaxed atmosphere.</p>



<p>If you&#039;re looking for a more exclusive experience, head to Vogue Club, known for its elegant decor and top-notch DJs.</p>



<p>No matter which club you choose, I guarantee you will have an unforgettable night in Cala D&#039;or.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Party destinations in Playa de Palma.</h2>



<p>Immerse yourself in Playa de Palma&#039;s lively party scene, where you can experience the vibrant energy and excitement of the nightlife. This beach town on the stunning island of Mallorca is a party lover&#039;s paradise.</p>



<p>Here are the best bars in Playa de Palma that will make you dance until dawn:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Megapark</strong>: Known as the largest beer garden in Europe, Megapark is a must-visit for those looking for an unforgettable night out. With live music, DJ sets and a buzzing atmosphere, this venue guarantees an epic party experience.</li>



<li><strong>Bierkonig</strong>: If you are looking for a place to sing and dance to the rhythm of your favorite songs, Bierkönig is the right place. This lively bar offers a mix of live music and DJ performances, ensuring non-stop entertainment.</li>



<li><strong>Oberbayern</strong>: Step into a traditional Bavarian beer hall with a twist in Oberbayern. This popular spot combines German beer culture with a vibrant party atmosphere, making it a favorite with locals and tourists alike.</li>
</ul>



<p>Get ready to let loose and dance the night away at these exciting party destinations in Playa de Palma. The nightlife here will leave you with unforgettable memories and a desire for more.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Frequent questions</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Is there any age restriction to enter nightclubs in Mallorca?</h3>



<p>You will be happy to know that there are age restrictions to enter clubs in Mallorca. This ensures a lively nightlife for adults, while also offering many nighttime activities suitable for the whole family in Mallorca. Enjoy your freedom to explore!</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What is the average price range for drinks and entry fees at Palma&#039;s most popular nightclubs?</h3>



<p>Are you looking for a party in Palma? Wondering about drink prices, cover charges and dress codes? Well, drink prices vary on average, cover charges can vary and yes, some clubs have dress codes. Get ready for a wild night!</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Are the beachside clubs in Magaluf open all year round or only during the summer season?</h3>



<p>During the low season, the beachside clubs in Magaluf may not be open, but don&#039;t worry! Mallorca offers alternative nightlife options to keep you entertained. Explore the vibrant city and discover hidden gems.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Can you recommend any of the little-known places in Alcudia that have a unique atmosphere or special events?</h3>



<p>Sure, there are hidden gems in Alcudia with a unique atmosphere. You should visit local bars and restaurants that host special events. They offer a great experience for those looking for freedom and a good time.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Is Santa Ponsa known for its live music scene and if so, what clubs or venues would you recommend for music enthusiasts?</h3>



<p>If you like live music, Santa Ponsa is the ideal place! With its lively nightlife and vibrant music scene, you&#039;ll find the best live music clubs here. Get ready to dance the night away!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h2>



<p>As night falls over Mallorca&#039;s stunning beaches, the vibrant club scene comes to life. From the hottest nightclubs in Palma to the beach clubs in Magaluf, there is no shortage of excitement and energy.</p>



<p>But the real hidden gems are found in Alcudia, where the party scene is full of surprises. And we can&#039;t forget Santa Ponsa, Cala D&#039;or and Playa De Palma, each offering their own unique and modern clubs.</p>



<p>So get ready to dance the night away under the starry Mediterranean sky, because Mallorca&#039;s nightlife is an experience you won&#039;t want to miss.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/nightclubs-open-late-near-the-beaches-of-mallorca-spain/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>4 Sunsets in Mallorca for Dreamers</title>
		<link>/en/sunsets-in-mallorca/</link>
					<comments>/en/sunsets-in-mallorca/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 10:48:32 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Mallorca, Spain]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=91</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dicen que lo bueno si es breve, dos veces bueno. Por este motivo comenzamos a despedir al verano con esos momentos fugaces que nos dejan imágenes para el recuerdo. Os traemos nuestras&#160;4 puestas de sol en Mallorca para soñadores&#160;donde podéis decir adiós a un nuevo día con vistas al mar. Estas son nuestras cuatro puestas...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>They say that if a good thing is brief, it is twice as good. For this reason we begin to say goodbye to summer with those fleeting moments that leave us images to remember. We bring you our&nbsp;<strong>4 sunsets in Mallorca for dreamers</strong>&nbsp;where you can say goodbye to a new day with views of the sea. These are our four favorite sunsets.</p>



<p>Who signs up for a&nbsp;<strong>trip to Mallorca</strong>?</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">1. Ca&#8217;n Pastilla</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img  fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="684"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/can-Pastilla-beach-sunset-1024x684.jpg"  alt="" class="wp-image-2728" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/can-Pastilla-beach-sunset-1024x684.jpg 1024w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/can-Pastilla-beach-sunset-300x200.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/can-Pastilla-beach-sunset-768x513.jpg 768w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/can-Pastilla-beach-sunset-1536x1026.jpg 1536w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/can-Pastilla-beach-sunset-18x12.jpg 18w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/can-Pastilla-beach-sunset.jpg 1617w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Ca’n Pastilla Beach Sunset</figcaption></figure>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><strong>FunPlan Recommendation</strong>: Watch the sunset on the Puro Beach terrace, cocktail in hand, until dinner.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Crossing the Mediterranean watching the sun hide behind the horizon. A sunset in Can Pastilla deserves a memory for a lifetime. You will feel that time stops and there is nothing more beautiful to contemplate. A perfect place to reflect on the rocks without looking at the clock to the rhythm of the chill out.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">2. Ses Covetes</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img  decoding="async" width="1024" height="496"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Ses-Covetes-sunset-1024x496.jpg"  alt="" class="wp-image-2730" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Ses-Covetes-sunset-1024x496.jpg 1024w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Ses-Covetes-sunset-300x145.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Ses-Covetes-sunset-768x372.jpg 768w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Ses-Covetes-sunset-18x9.jpg 18w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Ses-Covetes-sunset.jpg 1271w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Ses Covetes Sunset by Nav Unger</figcaption></figure>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><strong>FunPlan Recommendation:</strong>&nbsp;If you go between Wednesday and Sunday you can watch the sunset while enjoying an outdoor concert.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Nature in its purest form, a boat leaves and you are alone with the lights in the background. This is a sunset in Ses Covetes, one of the most classic on the Balearic island. If you want to live first-hand the experience of enjoying like a Mallorcan, this is your sunset.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">3. Sa Foradada Viewpoint</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img  decoding="async" width="1024" height="497"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Mirador-de-Sa-Foradada-Sunset-1024x497.jpg"  alt="" class="wp-image-2732" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Mirador-de-Sa-Foradada-Sunset-1024x497.jpg 1024w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Mirador-de-Sa-Foradada-Sunset-300x146.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Mirador-de-Sa-Foradada-Sunset-768x373.jpg 768w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Mirador-de-Sa-Foradada-Sunset-18x9.jpg 18w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Mirador-de-Sa-Foradada-Sunset.jpg 1263w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Mirador de Sa Foradada Sunset by Mallorca Heatwave</figcaption></figure>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><strong>FunPlan Recommendation</strong>: you will find Sa Foradada on the way to Deià, it is worth arriving mid-afternoon and waiting for the sun to set.</p>
</blockquote>



<p id="yui_3_16_0_1_1439976565304_20532">Views that deserve a postcard. If you pass through Sa Foradada you will only be able to stop and contemplate the world from above. Incredible cliffs invite you to dream and immerse yourself in a world apart, a desert island, a small paradise part of Mallorcan nature.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">4. Cap de Formentor</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img  loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="474"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Cap-de-Formentor-Sunset-1024x474.jpg"  alt="" class="wp-image-2734" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Cap-de-Formentor-Sunset-1024x474.jpg 1024w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Cap-de-Formentor-Sunset-300x139.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Cap-de-Formentor-Sunset-768x355.jpg 768w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Cap-de-Formentor-Sunset-18x8.jpg 18w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Cap-de-Formentor-Sunset.jpg 1133w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Cap de Formentor Sunset by veltronix.com</figcaption></figure>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><strong>FunPlan Recommendation</strong>: Watch the sunset from the top of the Formentor Lighthouse, you can say good night to the sun as if you were next to it.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Freedom, pure and clean freedom. As the sky turns pinkish you will feel the morning breeze saying goodbye to a new day. Only fleeting traces of light and the shadow of the cliffs will remain. A unique place to dream.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/sunsets-in-mallorca/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>