<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>The Fun Plan</title>
	<atom:link href="/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/en</link>
	<description>Crafting Moments, Creating Memories: Your Guide to Flawless Events.</description>
	<lastbuilddate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 10:40:20 +0000</lastbuilddate>
	<language>in-GB</language>
	<sy:updateperiod>
	hourly	</sy:updateperiod>
	<sy:updatefrequency>
	1	</sy:updatefrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/09/favi.png</url>
	<title>The Fun Plan</title>
	<link>/en</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>all</title>
		<link>/en/all/</link>
					<comments>/en/all/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 02:36:47 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Todos Los Destinos]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=2725</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/all/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Adventurous Kyrgyzstan: A Blend of Nature, History and Culture</title>
		<link>/en/adventurous-kyrgyzstan-a-blend-of-nature-history-and-culture/</link>
					<comments>/en/adventurous-kyrgyzstan-a-blend-of-nature-history-and-culture/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 08:07:01 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Kyrgyzstan]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=2682</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Situado en el corazón de Asia Central, donde montañas escarpadas se dispersan entre llanuras pintorescas, Kirguistán despliega un cautivador tapiz de paisajes extensos, tradiciones ancestrales y una rica cultura. El país, predominantemente una perla inexplorada en la escena turística mundial, celebra todos los elementos de un paraíso ideal para viajeros. La posición estratégica en la...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Set in the heart of Central Asia, where rugged mountains scatter amidst picturesque plains, Kyrgystan unfurls a captivating tapestry of sprawling landscapes, age-old traditions, and rich culture. The country, predominantly an unexplored pearl in the global tourism scene, celebrates all the elements of an ideal traveler's paradise. The strategic position at the crossroads of ancient trade routes, diverse ethnic communities, and distinctive cuisine set the country apart, bestowing upon it a unique charm and vivid identity.</p>



<p>An overview of Kyrgystan reveals a spectacular fusion of nature and nurture. Unraveling from its core, the capital city Bishkek into the remote outskirts, the country is adorned with the sempiternal beauty of snow-clad mountains, verdant meadows, serene Alpine lakes, and resourceful hot springs. This enchanting symphony of nature is reflected in its people who show a deep reverence for their natural abundance and environment. The Kyrgyz people, known for their warmth and hospitality, extend an inviting aura that encapsulates Kyrgyzstan's essence, making every traveller's experience remarkably homely and personal.</p>



<a href="https://go.idaoffers.com/aff_c?offer_id=13&#038;aff_id=61997&#038;url=https%3A%2F%2Finternationaldriversassociation.com%2Fcheckouts%2F%3Ftransaction_id%3D{transaction_id}%26affiliate_id%3D{affiliate_id}%26offer_id%3D{offer_id}" target="_blank" id="ida-banner" rel="noopener">
      <img decoding="async" 
        width="728px" 
        height="90px" 
        src="https://internationaldriversassociation.com/partners-hub/banner-sets/set-01/banner-8.png" 
        alt="International Drivers Association Banner" 
      />
    </a>



<p></p>



<p>Kyrgystan's geography illustrates a vibrant mosaic of glacial valleys, high-altitude lakes, and majestic peaks. The country's unmatched geographic diversity springs from the Tian Shan range vaulting across its expanse and the richness of its flora and fauna. The jewel of Kyrgystan, Lake Issyk-Kul, possesses curative powers and is a treasured spectacle of natural beauty. Protected reserves like the Ala-Archa National Park showcase the country's commitment to preserving its ecological heritage.</p>



<p>The traditions and history of Kyrgystan resonate in every corner of this scenic country. The remnants of Silk Road caravanserais testify to its historical significance. A multitude of influences shaping its historical trajectory, from Mongol invasions to the Soviet reign, fuels its culturally diverse fabric. This diversity reflects markedly in the country's architecture, art, and even everyday life anecdotes capturing the complex interplay of yesteryears with the rhythm of the present.</p>



<p>The untapped tourism potential of Kyrgystan is undeniable. With such a rich heritage, natural splendor, and ever-friendly locals, it is a destination begging for deeper exploration. Yet, despite these irresistible draws, this stunning canvass of a country remains relatively unknown to most international travellers. This obscurity often results from a lack of efficient travel planning resources and guides that can offer a comprehensive understanding of this elusive gem.</p>



<iframe width='100%' height='280px' src='https://internationaldriversassociation.com/partners-hub/widgets/style1?style=do_i_need_an_idp&#038;heading=Do+I+need+an+IDP%3F&#038;subtext=Complete+the+form+to+find+out+if+you+need+an+IDP+to+drive+overseas.&#038;primary_color=%23FEFEFF&#038;secondary_color=%23F3F4F6&#038;text_color=%23111827&#038;button_color=%232047F4&#038;affiliate_name=direct&#038;affiliate_id=&#038;offer_id=13'></iframe>



<p>Unlocking Kyrgystan's tourism potential, this guide aims to shed light on the country's various aspects, from its historic significance and architectural grandeur to popular holiday resorts and local cuisine, to help you navigate and witness the untold beauty and experiences Kyrgystan offers. For those who aspire to wander off the beaten path, uncover the local life's rhythm, and immerse in nature's unadulterated beauty and tranquillity, Kyrgystan calls for your exploration. This journey promises to be a confluence of enlightening insights and awe-inspiring revelations that will forever have you captivated by the Land of the Kyrgus.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Historic Significance of Kyrgystan</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img  fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1024" height="640"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Camels-and-people-walking-on-the-silk-road-1024x640.jpg"  alt="Camels and people walking on the silk road and sand dune of desert" class="wp-image-2703" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Camels-and-people-walking-on-the-silk-road-1024x640.jpg 1024w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Camels-and-people-walking-on-the-silk-road-300x187.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Camels-and-people-walking-on-the-silk-road-768x480.jpg 768w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Camels-and-people-walking-on-the-silk-road-1536x959.jpg 1536w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Camels-and-people-walking-on-the-silk-road-18x12.jpg 18w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Camels-and-people-walking-on-the-silk-road.jpg 1729w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Camels and people walking on the silk road and sand dune of desert</figcaption></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">The History of the Kyrgus People</h3>



<p>From time immemorial, the Kyrgus people, original inhabitants of Kyrgystan, have led a nomadic lifestyle, moving from one pasture to another, depending on the season. This lifestyle is deeply rooted in their culture, customs, and practices, which extend to their arts, music, and even attire.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Kyrgystan's Position on the Silk Road</h3>



<p>The worldwide renown historical crossroad, the Silk Road, significantly lends to the multi-layered past of Kyrgystan. Once a bustling trade route connecting China with the Middle East and Europe, the Silk Road augmented the cultural and economic exchange between civilizations over centuries.</p>



<p>In Kyrgystan, cities like Osh and Jalal-Abad flourished as important commercial hubs. They offered traders a place to rest, replenish their supplies, and also engage in local commerce, enabling the socio-economic growth of these cities. Remnants of these historic urban centers still amaze visitors with their rich history and well-preserved monuments.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Understanding the Invasions from Different Empires</h3>



<p>Over centuries, Kyrgystan has weathered numerous invasions and occupations leading to a confluence of diverse cultures. The Mongolian invasion during the 13th century had a significant impact on the region. Genghis Khan's empire left a lasting imprint, shaping the cultural and ethnic fabric of Kyrgystan.</p>



<p>The subsequent influence of the Qing Dynasty and the Russian Empire further added to the complex historical narrative of the country. Soviet rule, in particular, led to a colossal socio-economic transformation, bringing rapid industrialization and a shift from nomadic to settled life.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Kyrgystan's Journey to Independence</h3>



<p>An era which marked the changing trajectory of Kyrgystan’s socio-political landscape was its journey towards independence. Kyrgystan gained independence from the Soviet Union in 1991, marking the advent of a new chapter in its history. Today, Kyrgystan retains its unique culture while embracing democratic values and principles.</p>



<p>The essences of history, coupled with the indomitable spirit of the Kyrgus people and the distinctive blend of cultures, significantly contribute to Kyrgystan's charming allure. It's a living testament to a past that survived and thrived amid the ebb and flow of time, which continues to captivate every traveler. Through every rugged terrain and within each bustling bazaar, the echoes of an age-old history and the resilience of its people continue to enthral visitors worldwide.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Capital City of Bishkek</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img  decoding="async" width="1024" height="576"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Aerial-view-of-Bishkek-city-Kyrgyzstan-1024x576.jpg"  alt="Aerial view of Bishkek city Kyrgyzstan" class="wp-image-2692" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Aerial-view-of-Bishkek-city-Kyrgyzstan-1024x576.jpg 1024w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Aerial-view-of-Bishkek-city-Kyrgyzstan-300x169.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Aerial-view-of-Bishkek-city-Kyrgyzstan-768x432.jpg 768w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Aerial-view-of-Bishkek-city-Kyrgyzstan-1536x864.jpg 1536w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Aerial-view-of-Bishkek-city-Kyrgyzstan-18x10.jpg 18w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Aerial-view-of-Bishkek-city-Kyrgyzstan.jpg 1920w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Aerial view of Bishkek city Kyrgyzstan</figcaption></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">A Tour of the Modern Metropolis</h3>



<p>Bishkek, the bustling capital of Kyrgystan, is a metropolis that captures the country's essence. Its vibrant city streets, modern infrastructures, fascinating museums, and leafy parks make it distinctive. The city architecture blends Soviet-era block buildings with elements of the Kyrgus' traditional nomadic culture, making Bishkek a city like no other.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">How Bishkek Has Changed Over the Years</h3>



<p>Over the years, Bishkek has seen significant transformation. From a small caravan rest stop in the 19th century to becoming the political, economic, and cultural center of Kyrgystan, the city's development has been remarkable. Today, it stands as an exemplar of Kyrgystan's progress, embracing the future while preserving its historic roots.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Highlighting Interesting Places around the City</h3>



<p>Bishkek brims with places that are a must-visit. Ala-Too Square, the heart of the city, hosts various public events and celebrations. The majestic State History Museum overlooks the square, housing a wide range of exhibits from Kyrgystan's history. The Osh Bazaar is a labyrinth of stalls selling local products, from fresh produce to traditional Kyrgus hats.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">The Role of Religion in the City</h3>



<p>Although Kyrgystan is a secular country, Islam, practised by most Kyrgus people, plays an essential role in people's lives. In Bishkek, this religious influence is evident in the city's myriad of mosques, the most striking of which is the Great Central Mosque, a testament to stunning Islamic architecture. However, Bishkek's religious landscape is diverse, showcasing not just mosques but also Russian Orthodox churches and other places of worship, symbolizing the city's religious tolerance and diversity.</p>



<a href="https://go.idaoffers.com/aff_c?offer_id=13&#038;aff_id=62286&#038;url=https%3A%2F%2Finternationaldriversassociation.com%2Fcheckouts%2F%3Ftransaction_id%3D{transaction_id}%26affiliate_id%3D{affiliate_id}%26offer_id%3D{offer_id}" target="_blank" id="ida-banner" rel="noopener">
      <img decoding="async" 
        width="728px" 
        height="90px" 
        src="https://internationaldriversassociation.com/partners-hub/banner-sets/set-01/banner-8.png" 
        alt="International Drivers Association Banner" 
      />
    </a>



<p></p>



<p>Bishkek, in its own right, is a microcosm of Kyrgystan. It's where tradition meets modernity, creating a harmonious blend that comes together to show off the unique charm of Kyrgystan. Whether you're wandering through the thriving bazaars or appreciating the city's diverse architecture, Bishkek provides an alluring first taste of the wonders that the rest of the country has in store.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Exploring Kyrgystan's Lush Green Spaces</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img  decoding="async" width="1024" height="684"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Park-Bishkek-Kyrgyzstan-1024x684.jpg"  alt="Park, Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan" class="wp-image-2695" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Park-Bishkek-Kyrgyzstan-1024x684.jpg 1024w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Park-Bishkek-Kyrgyzstan-300x200.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Park-Bishkek-Kyrgyzstan-768x513.jpg 768w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Park-Bishkek-Kyrgyzstan-1536x1026.jpg 1536w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Park-Bishkek-Kyrgyzstan-18x12.jpg 18w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Park-Bishkek-Kyrgyzstan.jpg 1617w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Park, Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan</figcaption></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">A Walk Through the Parks of Bishkek</h3>



<p>Kyrgystan's capital, Bishkek, cradles a multitude of lush green spaces, offering visitors a refreshing retreat amidst the city's urban growth. Panfilov Park, named after Ivan Panfilov, a prominent World War II hero, is known for its shady walkways, peaceful sitting areas and an array of ornamental sculptures. The famous Victory Monument is also situated within this park, serving as a symbol of the nation's strength.</p>



<p>Another must-visit green space is the Oak Park, a beloved place for locals to escape the city's hustle and bustle and breathe in the fresh air. This park is home to an open-air sculpture museum, featuring beautiful works of art, providing a unique cultural perspective amidst a natural backdrop.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Comparing Soviet Architecture and the City's Modernity</h3>



<p>In Bishkek, buildings tell their own stories, contrasting the city's Soviet past with its modern progression. Soviet-era edifices with their sturdy constructs and minimalist designs stand alongside modern glass towers, epitomizing the city's evolution.</p>



<p>/</p>



<p>Monuments such as the State History Museum and Philharmonic Hall bear the Soviet architectural influence, showcasing grandeur and simplicity simultaneously. In contrast, recent developments feature sleek office buildings, shopping centers, and high-rise apartments portraying the city's commitment to modernization.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Kyrgystan's Architecture and Seismic Considerations</h3>



<p>Kyrgystan lies in a seismically active zone, posing challenges for architectural designs. Many of the country's structures, particularly those built during the Soviet era, were constructed with these considerations in mind to withstand potential earthquakes.</p>



<p>Even today, modern architectural designs incorporate seismic-resilient features, ensuring safety without compromising aesthetic appeal. This unique aspect, though often overlooked, forms a significant part of Kyrgystan's architectural narrative.</p>



<p>The exploration goes beyond the urban spaces of Bishkek as Kyrgystan is a land of spectacular natural beauty. Kyrgystan's lush green spaces serve not only as recreational spots but also as ecological lungs of the city. Whether it's the serene calm of the parks or the visual aesthetic of varied architectural styles, the country's green spaces offer a unique blend of tranquillity and vibrancy that is captivating.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Local Cuisine</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img  loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/tandoor-bread-Kyrgyzstan-1024x683.jpg"  alt="Tandoor naan or tandoor bread sold at the market in Kyrgyzstan." class="wp-image-2698" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/tandoor-bread-Kyrgyzstan-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/tandoor-bread-Kyrgyzstan-300x200.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/tandoor-bread-Kyrgyzstan-768x512.jpg 768w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/tandoor-bread-Kyrgyzstan-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/tandoor-bread-Kyrgyzstan-18x12.jpg 18w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/tandoor-bread-Kyrgyzstan.jpg 1619w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Tandoor naan or tandoor bread sold at the market in Kyrgyzstan.</figcaption></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">The Importance of Meat in Kyrgystan's Cuisine</h3>



<p>In the culinary landscape of Kyrgystan, meat is more than just a component; it channels a significant part of the national gastronomy. Lamb, beef, and horse meat play a starring role in many local dishes. Beshbarmak, regarded as the national dish, is a flavorful blend of boiled meat served over pasta. Another notable dish is Shashlik, skewered and grilled cubes of meat, enjoyed immensely during gatherings and celebrations.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Highlighting Dishes of Note and Where to Try Them</h3>



<p>Alongside the meat-heavy dishes, Kyrgystan's cuisine also offers diversity. Paloo, the Kyrgus rendition of pilaf, is a delectable dish made with rice, cooked with an assortment of vegetables, and often served with chunks of meat. Another crowd-pleaser is manty, delicious steamed dumplings filled with meat or vegetables.</p>



<p>You can find authentic local dishes at spots like Navat, Arzu, and Dastorkon, some of the most popular establishments in Bishkek. For street food immersion, the lively Osh Bazaar offers an array of local food stalls to tuck into Kyrgystan's culinary delights.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">A Look at Modern Shopping and Traditional Bazaars</h3>



<p>Kyrgystan's shopping scene is a captivating mix where the traditional intersects with the modern. On the one hand, Bishkek houses numerous modern supermarkets and shopping malls. On the other, the city also hosts vibrant bazaars, including the bustling Osh Bazaar.</p>



<p>These traditional markets are hotspots for local produce, spices, fresh dairy products, and a plethora of other items. The exchange between buyers and sellers, coupled with the vivid sights, scents, and sounds, make these bazaars a captivating cultural experience and an integral part of local life.</p>



<p>From succulent meat dishes to vibrant markets, Kyrgystan's enriching culinary journey is sure to leave your palate mesmerized with its distinct flavors and your heart filled with treasured experiences. A trip to this mesmerizing country would be incomplete without delving into its food culture and navigating the bustling bazaars that bring cities like Bishkek to life.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Delving into the Ancient Sites</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img  loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="686"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Ancient-site-of-Burana-near-Bishkek-1024x686.jpg"  alt="Ancient site of Burana near Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan." class="wp-image-2688" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Ancient-site-of-Burana-near-Bishkek-1024x686.jpg 1024w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Ancient-site-of-Burana-near-Bishkek-300x201.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Ancient-site-of-Burana-near-Bishkek-768x514.jpg 768w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Ancient-site-of-Burana-near-Bishkek-1536x1029.jpg 1536w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Ancient-site-of-Burana-near-Bishkek-2048x1372.jpg 2048w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Ancient-site-of-Burana-near-Bishkek-18x12.jpg 18w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Ancient site of Burana near Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan.</figcaption></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">A Visit to Burana Tower and the Ancient City of Balasagun</h3>



<p>The historical Burana Tower, nestled in the ruins of the ancient city of Balasagun, is a remnant of Kyrgystan's rich history. Once standing at an impressive height of 45 meters, the Burana Tower is a minaret from the 11th century, now significantly reduced due to natural calamities. Despite the loss, the towering monument still retains a majestic allure, offering a panoramic view of the surrounding Chuy Valley from its peak.</p>



<p>Adjacent to the tower, you can find a field of balbals – ancient grave markers adorned with fascinating carvings that provide crucial insights into Turkic rituals and beliefs.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Exploring the Ala Archa National Park</h3>



<p>Moving away from the historical relics, the Ala Archa National Park offers a change in scene with its breathtaking natural beauty. The park, a short drive away from Bishkek, spans over 200 square kilometers and is home to over 20 small and large glacial lakes, along with a myriad of plant and animal species.</p>



<p>The park holds a great appeal for nature lovers and adventurers alike. Whether you are up for a leisurely stroll to admire the pristine landscapes or inclined towards vigorous hiking up to the towering peaks, the Ala Archa National Park has something for everyone.</p>



<p>From historical structures that echo the past to natural landscapes that highlight the country's geographical diversity, Kyrgystan's ancient sites and natural wonders provide a fulfilling journey to any travelers. A visit to these places not only offers a visual treat but also an understanding of the country’s rich cultural history and ecological wealth.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A Culinary Experience</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img  loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="685"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Osh-Bazaar-in-Bishkek-Kyrgyzstan-1024x685.jpg"  alt="Kurut dried cheese balls in Osh Bazaar Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan" class="wp-image-2706" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Osh-Bazaar-in-Bishkek-Kyrgyzstan-1024x685.jpg 1024w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Osh-Bazaar-in-Bishkek-Kyrgyzstan-300x201.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Osh-Bazaar-in-Bishkek-Kyrgyzstan-768x514.jpg 768w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Osh-Bazaar-in-Bishkek-Kyrgyzstan-1536x1028.jpg 1536w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Osh-Bazaar-in-Bishkek-Kyrgyzstan-18x12.jpg 18w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Osh-Bazaar-in-Bishkek-Kyrgyzstan.jpg 1614w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Kurut dried cheese balls in Osh Bazaar Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan</figcaption></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Visiting a Traditional Kyrgystan Restaurant</h3>



<p>Visitar un restaurante tradicional de Kirguistán puede ser una experiencia sin igual. Involucrando tus sentidos con una miríada de sabores, olores y sonidos, estos restaurantes sirven como una ventana para entender la rica herencia culinaria de Kirguistán. &#8220;Faiza&#8221;, un restaurante renombrado ubicado en Bishkek, ofrece una experiencia auténtica que muestra la cocina tradicional del país. Los menús aquí están cargados de estofados carnudos, caldos robustos y pasteles tentadores — todos emblemáticos del panorama gastronómico de Kirguistán.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">The Role of Cheese in the Local Cuisine</h3>



<p>The culinary tapestry of Kyrgystan isn't solely about meat dishes. Cheese holds a coveted place too. Kurut, a variety of dried cheese balls, is a popular snack often accompanied with tea or eaten on its own. Similarly, Beshbarmak, the national dish, occasionally features thin slices of local cheese, giving it a distinctive twist.</p>



<p>For a more comprehensive cheese trial, make sure to take a trip to any of the vibrant local markets. Here, you will find an array of handmade cheese varieties ranging from creamy and smooth to sharp and tangy. Exploring these stalls not only offers a peek into the diversity of Kyrgystan's cheese making traditions but also provides a chance to savor them fresh.</p>



<p>Kyrgystan's culinary heritage is diverse and distinct, punctuated with robust flavors and age-old cooking techniques. By visiting a traditional restaurant and exploring the local markets, you can witness and participate in this vibrant gastronomical narrative, one delicious taste at a time.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Exploring Lake Issyk-Kul</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img  loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="681"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Issyk-Kul-lake-and-beach-in-Kyrgyzstan-1024x681.jpg"  alt="Scenic landscape of Issyk-Kul lake and beach in Kyrgyzstan" class="wp-image-2709" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Issyk-Kul-lake-and-beach-in-Kyrgyzstan-1024x681.jpg 1024w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Issyk-Kul-lake-and-beach-in-Kyrgyzstan-300x200.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Issyk-Kul-lake-and-beach-in-Kyrgyzstan-768x511.jpg 768w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Issyk-Kul-lake-and-beach-in-Kyrgyzstan-1536x1022.jpg 1536w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Issyk-Kul-lake-and-beach-in-Kyrgyzstan-18x12.jpg 18w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Issyk-Kul-lake-and-beach-in-Kyrgyzstan.jpg 1623w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Scenic landscape of Issyk-Kul lake and beach in Kyrgyzstan</figcaption></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Introduction to Lake Issyk-Kul</h3>



<p>El Lago Issyk-Kul, apodado la &#8220;Perla de Asia Central&#8221;, brilla como una de las principales atracciones de Kirguistán. Este lago salado endorreico, rodeado por las montañas nevadas de Tian Shan, es el segundo lago de gran altitud más grande del mundo. A pesar de su nombre, que se traduce como &#8220;lago caliente&#8221;, sus aguas azules y cristalinas pueden ser bastante frías, manteniendo temperaturas bajas incluso en el apogeo del verano.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Breakdown of Lake Issyk-Kul’s Main Attractions and Rich Offerings</h3>



<p>Perched over a thousand meters above sea level, Lake Issyk-Kul is more than just a pretty sight. It serves as a marquee for an assortment of exciting activities and attractions. The lake's northern shore, teeming with tourist resorts and sandy beaches, is a hotspot for relaxation and water sports. Jet-skiing, yachting, and paddling offer adrenaline-infused ways to explore the lake's spanning waters.</p>



<p>The southern shore offers a more tranquil and untouched environment. Here, you can embark on hikes leading to rugged gorges, waterfalls, and the shimmering Barskoon Glacier. Besides, the sacred springs at Jeti-Oguz, revered for their healing properties, provide an intriguing detour.</p>



<p>Around the lake, several cultural and historical sites like the petroglyphs at Cholpon-Ata and the minaret at Burana Tower add layers of depth to the scenic beauty.</p>



<p>Encapsulating a diverse range of attractions — from exciting water sports and scenic hiking trails to important historical landmarks — a trip to Lake Issyk-Kul unfurls a variety of memorable experiences. It's a place that combines the contemplative lure of untouched nature with the thrill of adventure, crafting a compelling narrative of Kyrgyzstan's charms.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">A Look at the Resort Town of Cholpon ATA</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img  loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="770"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Cholpon-Ata-Kyrgyzstan-1024x770.jpg"  alt="Beautiful shot of mountains near a rural field in Cholpon Ata, Kyrgyzstan" class="wp-image-2711" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Cholpon-Ata-Kyrgyzstan-1024x770.jpg 1024w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Cholpon-Ata-Kyrgyzstan-300x225.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Cholpon-Ata-Kyrgyzstan-768x577.jpg 768w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Cholpon-Ata-Kyrgyzstan-16x12.jpg 16w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Cholpon-Ata-Kyrgyzstan.jpg 1437w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Beautiful shot of mountains near a rural field in Cholpon Ata, Kyrgyzstan</figcaption></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">History of Cholpon ATA as a Vacation Spot</h3>



<p>A tranquil and picturesque destination in the lap of Kyrgyzstan's rugged natural beauty, Cholpon ATA hardly needs an introduction. This bubbling resort town, nestled near the northern edges of the majestic Lake Issyk-Kul, has a rich history that stretches back centuries. Formerly revered as a sacred retreat for indigenous tribes seeking solace in its warm, therapeutic waters, Cholpon ATA has evolved over centuries into a thriving tourist hotspot.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Understanding the Boom in Bed and Breakfast Rentals</h3>



<p>Cholpon ATA's journey to becoming a vacation spot is a testament to its timeless allure. With the rise of sustainable and experiential travel trends, Cholpon ATA has seen a striking boom in bed and breakfast rentals. These locally-run accommodations offer tourists a chance to immerse themselves in authentic Kyrgyz culture, savor traditional cuisine, and form meaningful connections with the locals.</p>



<p>Adorned with ethno-style furnishings and offering unrivaled views of Lake Issyk-Kul's azure expanse, these rentals are gaining popularity among travelers seeking a unique, personalized experience. The bed and breakfast culture not only uplifts local entrepreneurship but also contributes significantly to preserving Cholpon ATA's cultural heritage.</p>



<p>Steeped in history and endowed with an inviting local culture, Cholpon ATA deftly combines leisure and learning. Whether you're relishing the cosy ambiance of a traditional bed and breakfast or soaking up the therapeutic serenity of its natural springs, every moment in Cholpon ATA is bound to be a remarkable experience.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Exploring the Eastern Tip of the Lake</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img  loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="666"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/city-of-Karakol-Kyrgyzstan-1024x666.jpg"  alt="The view from a hill outside the city of Karakol, Kyrgyzstan" class="wp-image-2714" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/city-of-Karakol-Kyrgyzstan-1024x666.jpg 1024w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/city-of-Karakol-Kyrgyzstan-300x195.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/city-of-Karakol-Kyrgyzstan-768x499.jpg 768w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/city-of-Karakol-Kyrgyzstan-1536x999.jpg 1536w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/city-of-Karakol-Kyrgyzstan-18x12.jpg 18w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/city-of-Karakol-Kyrgyzstan.jpg 1661w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">The view from a hill outside the city of Karakol, Kyrgyzstan</figcaption></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Introduction to Karakol City</h3>



<p>Karakol, set against the backdrop of the towering Tian Shan mountain range, graces the eastern tip of Lake Issyk-Kul. This vibrant city, colored by the multi-ethnic tapestry of Turkic, Mongolic, and Slavic influences, has an intriguing history dating back to the end of the 19th century. Over the years, Karakol has emerged as an important base for trekking and mountaineering expeditions in Kyrgyzstan, besides being known for its unique cultural melange.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">The Influence of the Dungan Community</h3>



<p>Underpinning Karakol's multicultural charm is the significant presence of the Dungan community. The Dungans, Chinese Muslim immigrants, have been residing in Karakol since the 1880s. Their migration and subsequent settlement in the city have left indelible marks on its cultural, architectural, and culinary landscape. Their rich traditions have weaved themselves into Karakol's social fabric, adding to its allure.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Highlighting the Dungan Mosque and its Unique Construction</h3>



<p>A testament to the Dungan influence is the visually stunning Dungan Mosque. Unlike typical Islamic places of worship, this mosque, built in 1910, sports an architectural style that fuses Chinese and Buddhist elements. Interestingly, the entire wooden structure, vibrantly painted and ornately carved, stands without a single nail being used. The mosque is a living chronicle of the city's historical past and a must-visit landmark for any traveler.</p>



<p>To explore Karakol is to delve into an intriguing blend of history, culture, and natural beauty. Whether immersing in its multicultural ambiance, understanding the influence of the Dungan community, or marveling at the craftsmanship of the unique Dungan Mosque, every moment in Karakol enriches your Kyrgyzstan experience manifold.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Seven Bulls Rock and Other Locations</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img  loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="683"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Rock-formation-Seven-bulls-Kyrgyzstan-1024x683.jpg"  alt="Rock formation Seven bulls and a broken heart in Kyrgyzstan" class="wp-image-2716" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Rock-formation-Seven-bulls-Kyrgyzstan-1024x683.jpg 1024w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Rock-formation-Seven-bulls-Kyrgyzstan-300x200.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Rock-formation-Seven-bulls-Kyrgyzstan-768x512.jpg 768w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Rock-formation-Seven-bulls-Kyrgyzstan-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Rock-formation-Seven-bulls-Kyrgyzstan-18x12.jpg 18w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Rock-formation-Seven-bulls-Kyrgyzstan.jpg 1619w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Rock formation Seven bulls and a broken heart in Kyrgyzstan</figcaption></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Introduction to the Seven Bulls Rock</h3>



<p>Perched in the beautiful Jeti-Ögüz district, the striking Seven Bulls Rock is an iconic natural landmark in Kyrgyzstan. Also known as Jeti-Ögüz Rocks, this unexpectedly artistic manifestation of geological processes captivates with its grandeur and colors. The seven massive, red-colored sandstone formations reminiscent of bulls standing side by side lend the site its popular name.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Hiking Potentials in These Areas</h3>



<p>Surrounding the Seven Bulls Rock are rustic landscapes that are a haven for adventurers and nature enthusiasts. The area offers a variety of hiking routes, ranging from casual strolls to challenging ascents. The walk to the Broken Heart Rock, located nearby, is an easy and scenic trail that offers panoramic views of the Seven Bulls Rock and the encompassing valley.</p>



<p>For a more challenging exploit, intrepid souls can embark on a multiple-day trek into the nearby Terskey Ala-Too Range. Here, the blend of snow-capped peaks, sparkling rivers, and verdant meadows makes for an exhilarating experience.</p>



<p>A visit to the Seven Bulls Rock quickly morphs from a sightseeing trip into an adventure overflowing with possibilities. With its distinctive natural structures and breathtaking hiking trails, this Kyrgyz treasure gives you a world of untamed beauty to explore in a day or stay immersed for weeks.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Rise of the Tourism Infrastructure</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img  loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="684"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Yurt-nomadic-houses-camp-1024x684.jpg"  alt="Kyrgyz yurt in the middle of the mountains" class="wp-image-2719" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Yurt-nomadic-houses-camp-1024x684.jpg 1024w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Yurt-nomadic-houses-camp-300x200.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Yurt-nomadic-houses-camp-768x513.jpg 768w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Yurt-nomadic-houses-camp-1536x1026.jpg 1536w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Yurt-nomadic-houses-camp-18x12.jpg 18w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Yurt-nomadic-houses-camp.jpg 1617w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Kyrgyz yurt in the middle of the mountains</figcaption></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">An Examination of the Growing Infrastructure</h3>



<p>Kyrgyzstan, with its immense natural beauty and rich cultural heritage, holds a promise for tourism. While still undeveloped in some parts, this landlocked country in Central Asia is experiencing an upswing in the growth of its tourism infrastructure. This improved influx capacity is making it easier for travelers worldwide to enjoy its untamed landscapes, historic sites, and unique experiences.</p>



<p>Key enhancements are being observed in the accommodation sector, with an increasing number of hotels, guesthouses, and camping sites dotted around popular tourist points. Transportation links have also seen progression, including enhanced road infrastructures and better connectivity due to extended domestic and international flight routes. Furthermore, technological advances, like mobile connections and internet hotspots, cater to the modern traveler.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Personal Encounter with Local Entrepreneurs</h3>



<p>The development is not merely limited to architectural or technological facets – Kyrgyzstan is experiencing a cultural type of development via local engagement. Entrepreneurs, with their relentless spirit and innovative thinking, are increasingly contributing to Kyrgyzstan's tourism landscape.</p>



<p>These individuals are creating authentic and sustainable travel experiences. They provide homestays that offer a peek into Kyrgyz life or facilitate encounters with nomadic communities residing in the highlands. Some facilitate treks to unexplored territories, while others organize culinary tours centered around the traditional Kyrgyz cuisine.</p>



<p>The growth of the tourism infrastructure is, thus, breathing new life into Kyrgyzstan. Through constant improvements and local entrepreneurship, the country is gradually turning more accessible to global travelers, while also preserving its unique identity and contributing to local economies.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The Southern Shore of the Lake</h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img  loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="1024" height="685"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Skazka-Canyon-Kyrgyzstan-1024x685.jpg"  alt="Fairytale canyon or Skazka Canyon near Issyk-Kul lake, Kyrgyzstan." class="wp-image-2722" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Skazka-Canyon-Kyrgyzstan-1024x685.jpg 1024w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Skazka-Canyon-Kyrgyzstan-300x201.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Skazka-Canyon-Kyrgyzstan-768x514.jpg 768w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Skazka-Canyon-Kyrgyzstan-1536x1027.jpg 1536w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Skazka-Canyon-Kyrgyzstan-18x12.jpg 18w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/11/Skazka-Canyon-Kyrgyzstan.jpg 1615w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Fairytale canyon or Skazka Canyon near Issyk-Kul lake, Kyrgyzstan.</figcaption></figure>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Immersing in Different Kyrgyzstan Folklore</h3>



<p>Kyrgyzstan’s southern shore of Lake Issyk-Kul is a treasure trove of story and folklore. Origin tales, fables of local personalities, and mythological accounts shape the identity of these regions. Glass-clear water of the lake coupled with the stunning backdrop of snow-capped peaks have lent themselves to numerous lores passed down through generations.</p>



<p>Among the many narratives, the story of the underwater city remains a popular tale. According to local folklore, an ancient metropolis once stood in the place of the lake. However, due to an act of divine wrath or natural calamity, the city submerged and remains underwater till today. These tales of unwary travelers being mesmerized by beautiful city lights underwater lend an edge of mystery to this otherwise serene locale.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Highlighting Unique Geological Formation - Fairy Tale Canyon</h3>



<p>The southern shore of Lake Issyk-Kul is also home to the Fairy Tale Canyon, known locally as Skazka. A unique geological formation, it presents a vibrant palette of colors and shapes, sculpted by time and elemental forces.</p>



<p>Wandering through the craggy trails of the canyon feels like journeying through the pages of a fantastical storybook. Here, wind-swept rocks form an array of striking images - from mysterious creatures to majestic castles - limited only by one's imagination.</p>



<p>The southern shore of Lake Issyk-Kul, with its distinct folklore and extraordinary natural formations, introduces a different rhythm of life and a unique perspective on the world. Whether it’s unraveling local legends or marveling at the Fairy Tale Canyon's beauty, every experience contributes to the multifaceted narrative of Kyrgyzstan.</p>



<a href="https://go.idaoffers.com/aff_c?offer_id=13&#038;aff_id=14029&#038;url=https%3A%2F%2Finternationaldriversassociation.com%2Fcheckouts%2F%3Ftransaction_id%3D{transaction_id}%26affiliate_id%3D{affiliate_id}%26offer_id%3D{offer_id}" target="_blank" id="ida-banner" rel="noopener">
      <img decoding="async" 
        width="728px" 
        height="90px" 
        src="https://internationaldriversassociation.com/partners-hub/banner-sets/set-01/banner-8.png" 
        alt="International Drivers Association Banner" 
      />
    </a>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/adventurous-kyrgyzstan-a-blend-of-nature-history-and-culture/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Annual San Fermin Festival in Pamplona</title>
		<link>/en/annual-san-fermin-festival-in-pamplona/</link>
					<comments>/en/annual-san-fermin-festival-in-pamplona/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 11:29:53 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=2635</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Este sábado día 6 dan comienzo los Sanfermines 2023, con&#160;el chupinazo&#160;que tendrá lugar a las 12,00h en la Plaza Consistorial de Pamplona. La fiesta debe su nombre Fermín de Amiens, nacido en Pompaelo (la actual&#160;Pamplona) que fue misionero cristiano, primer obispo&#160;de Amiens(cuya iglesia mandó construir) y fue decapitado a los 31 años de edad. Una...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This Saturday the 6th, the Sanfermines 2023 begins, with&nbsp;<strong>the &quot;chupinazo</strong>&nbsp;which will take place at 12:00 p.m. in the Plaza Consistorial of Pamplona.</p>



<p>The festival is named after Fermín de Amiens, born in Pompaelo (present-day Pamplona) who was a Christian missionary, first bishop of Amiens (whose church he ordered to be built) and was beheaded at the age of 31. A mistaken belief is to think that San Fermín is the patron saint of Pamplona exclusively, when he is the patron saint of all of Navarra.</p>



<p>The celebrations begin with the launching of the chupinazo and end at midnight on July 14 with the&nbsp;<strong>farewell song “Poor me”.</strong></p>



<p>The most famous activities of San Fermines are&nbsp;<strong>the confinements,</strong>&nbsp;which consist of an 849m route in front of the bulls that ends in the bullring. They take place every day between July 7 and 14 at 8:00 a.m., with an average duration of two to three minutes.</p>



<p>The Sanfermines have an origin that dates back to the Middle Ages, although their worldwide fame is a recent phenomenon, also linked to the dissemination that Ernest Hemingway gave them through his book “Fiesta”.</p>



<p>Three independent celebrations take place during these days in which the population of Pamplona goes from 190,000 inhabitants to more than 1,000,000 people:</p>



<p>* Religious acts in honor of San Fermín</p>



<p>* Trade fairs</p>



<p>* Bullfights</p>



<p>This year, the SanFermines will have 437 events that you can see in detail in this&nbsp;<a href="https://sanferminespamplona.es/" target="_blank" data-type="link" data-id="https://sanferminespamplona.es/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Web page</a>.</p>



<p>Do you dare to go to&nbsp;<a href="/en/journey/" target="_blank" data-type="page" data-id="815" rel="noreferrer noopener">the confinements</a>&nbsp;of San Fermin? If the answer is yes, here are some&nbsp;<a href="https://www.sanfermin.com/es/" target="_blank" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.sanfermin.com/es/" rel="noreferrer noopener">tips</a>&nbsp; to be able to enjoy the party without suffering any altercations 😉</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/annual-san-fermin-festival-in-pamplona/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rome: A Trip To The Eternal City In 3 Days</title>
		<link>/en/rome-a-trip-to-the-eternal-city-in-3-days/</link>
					<comments>/en/rome-a-trip-to-the-eternal-city-in-3-days/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 10:58:22 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Rome]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=2619</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Había leído tanto y visto tantas fotografías de Roma, que pensaba que cuando por fin estuviera en la capital de Italia no me sorprendería nada de la ciudad. Y tras estar tres días allí, puedo decir que he vuelto más enamorada todavía si cabe que antes de viajar. Pasear por calles donde dos mil años...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I had read so much and seen so many photographs of Rome, that I thought that when I was finally in the capital of Italy nothing about the city would surprise me. And after spending three days there, I can say that I have returned even more in love, if possible, than before traveling. </p>



<p>Walking through streets where Julius Caesar walked two thousand years ago, seeing monuments as ancient as the Pantheon or the Colosseum or others as beautiful and majestic as the Trevi Fountain, and being able to visit one of the smallest states in the world on foot is only possible in a corner of the planet: Rome. I invite you to find out what my trip to the Eternal City has been like in 3 days.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">THE VATICAN</h2>



<p>When I thought about which area of the city to stay in, I chose to rent an apartment in Rome near the Vatican since it is close to two metro stops (Cipro and Ottaviano), you can walk to the city center (about 25 minutes at a brisk pace) and found the prices to be much cheaper. </p>



<p>This gave me the opportunity to get to know the Vatican in depth, a state that had always caught my attention due to its peculiar geographical and administrative location. Only very high stone walls delimit the border between the streets of Rome and the interior of the famous &#039;<strong>smallest country in the world</strong>&#039;. Precisely on my first day in the city I decided to get to know the Vatican in depth.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img  loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="640" height="463"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/St.-Peters-Basilica-rome-italy.jpg"  alt="The Vatican" class="wp-image-2630" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/St.-Peters-Basilica-rome-italy.jpg 640w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/St.-Peters-Basilica-rome-italy-300x217.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/St.-Peters-Basilica-rome-italy-18x12.jpg 18w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">The Vatican</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>We start by placing ourselves in the row of the&nbsp;<strong>Vatican Museums</strong>, where it seems like the world is going to end due to the large number of people there; not only tourists, but guides who offer their &#039;desperate&#039; services to visitors who are within 20 meters of the entrance to the museums. </p>



<p>What do you get if you choose to enter with a guide? Direct access without waiting inside, but the price per person is much higher than standing in the &#039;rigorous line&#039; and waiting your turn. If you have an international student card (the typical youth card that we use in Spain does not work) you can enter by paying 8 euros, otherwise you will have to purchase your ticket for 16 euros per person.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><strong>The interior of the Vatican Museums is made up of numerous exhibitions, each one with a different theme such as paintings, tapestries, sculptures, numismatics...</strong></p>
</blockquote>



<p>A piece of advice: if you want to escape the large crowds, start with the museums on the right, they are always much less crowded than those next to the&nbsp;<strong>Sistine Chapel</strong>. And it is precisely this last one that is the most coveted room by tourists who visit the Vatican Museums. </p>



<p>Of course, to access it you must cover your shoulders and knees, remain silent and not take photographs (even without a flash). From there there is a door, quite hidden, that directly connects the Chapel with the interior of the&nbsp;<strong>basilica of Saint Peter</strong>.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img  loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="640" height="383"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Philosophy-School-Of-Athens-rome-italy.jpg"  alt="Sistine Chapel" class="wp-image-2629" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Philosophy-School-Of-Athens-rome-italy.jpg 640w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Philosophy-School-Of-Athens-rome-italy-300x180.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Philosophy-School-Of-Athens-rome-italy-18x12.jpg 18w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Sistine Chapel</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>San Pedro is the largest church in the world and without a doubt surprises everyone who visits it. Even if you do not access its interior from the Vatican Museums, entry has no cost. </p>



<p>However, going up to the dome costs about 9 euros per person and from the top you can have stunning views of the enormous&nbsp;<strong>St. Peter&#039;s Square</strong>, one of the largest on the planet. To go up to the dome you cannot avoid climbing stairs, so although there is a part that you can avoid taking the elevator, then you have to ascend a spiral staircase to the top of the basilica.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">HEART OF THE CAPITAL</h2>



<p>The second day of my stay was based on getting to know the main monuments of Rome in depth, which, as happens if&nbsp;<a href="/en/paris-in-two-days/" target="_blank" data-type="link" data-id="/paris-en-dos-dias/" rel="noreferrer noopener">you travel to paris</a>, most points of interest are in the center and you can explore them perfectly on foot. </p>



<p>The first stop was very close to the Vatican, on the banks of the Tiber River, where the spectacular&nbsp;<strong>Castle of Sant Angelo</strong>&nbsp;which I did not enter due to lack of time and a somewhat limited budget (and the entrance cost 9 euros per person). From there we reach the&nbsp;<strong>Navona Square</strong>, where despite being one of the largest in Rome, it was completely overwhelmed by tourists spread across its three main points: the<strong>&nbsp;Fountains of Neptune, Moro and the Three Rivers</strong>.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img  loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="640" height="480"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Campo-de-Fiori-Rome-Italy.jpg"  alt="Campo dei Fiori" class="wp-image-2628" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Campo-de-Fiori-Rome-Italy.jpg 640w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Campo-de-Fiori-Rome-Italy-300x225.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Campo-de-Fiori-Rome-Italy-16x12.jpg 16w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Campo dei Fiori</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>The next stop was at the&nbsp;<strong>Campo dei Fiori</strong>&nbsp;where in a small space they had set up a large street market where they sold, at quite high prices, pasta, fruit, vegetables, liquors and flowers. </p>



<p>We head to one of the most beautiful monuments that is sometimes not given as much importance as the famous Colosseum:&nbsp;<strong>Agrippa&#039;s Pantheon</strong>. It is one of the oldest heritage sites in Italy and access to the interior is completely free. In addition, there are numerous ice cream parlors nearby to taste this delicious Italian product. </p>



<p>A 5-minute walk from there, I reached the&nbsp;<strong>Trevi Fountain</strong>&nbsp;where to my surprise it was fenced off due to construction (something common in Rome...). To continue the tour through the city center, I passed through the&nbsp;<strong>Colonna Square</strong>, I climbed the long staircase&nbsp;<strong>Spain Square</strong>&nbsp;and I came to&nbsp;<strong>Villa Borguese</strong>&nbsp;crossing the&nbsp;<strong>Popolo Square</strong>. An intense day, but where I was able to see the main monuments of Rome.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img  loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="640" height="385"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/latin-writings-in-front-of-Pantheon-in-Rome-Italy.jpg"  alt="Pantheon of Agrippa" class="wp-image-2627" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/latin-writings-in-front-of-Pantheon-in-Rome-Italy.jpg 640w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/latin-writings-in-front-of-Pantheon-in-Rome-Italy-300x180.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/latin-writings-in-front-of-Pantheon-in-Rome-Italy-18x12.jpg 18w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Pantheon of Agrippa</figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">COLISEUM AND THE HILLS OF ROME</h2>



<p>At 12 noon on my third day in Rome I was in the&nbsp;<strong>Gianicolo hill</strong>, where in addition to having beautiful views of the city, one of the shows takes place: the firing of a cannon. </p>



<p>So like every day, a van arrived with several soldiers and under the statue of Garibaldi they opened a door and took out a cannon; They loaded it and after counting down they &#039;deafened&#039; the few attendees who were present. After this curious act that has been taking place for more than a hundred years, we walked to the &#039;neighboring&#039; neighborhood of&nbsp;<strong>Trastevere</strong>.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><strong>Trastevere: Its picturesque and narrow cobbled streets are full of restaurants where it is inevitable not to want to try their pizzas and pastas...</strong></p>
</blockquote>



<p>But the last stop of our trip was the Colosseum, so we headed there but not before going to see the famous&nbsp;<strong>Mouth of Truth</strong>.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignleft size-full"><img  loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="480" height="640"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Mouth-of-Truth-Colosseum.jpg"  alt="Mouth of Truth in Rome" class="wp-image-2625" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Mouth-of-Truth-Colosseum.jpg 480w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Mouth-of-Truth-Colosseum-225x300.jpg 225w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Mouth-of-Truth-Colosseum-9x12.jpg 9w" sizes="(max-width: 480px) 100vw, 480px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Mouth of Truth in Rome</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Nearby is one of the most impressive monuments in Rome: the&nbsp;<strong>Monument to Victor Emmanuel II</strong>; Access to its interior is free of charge, there are free toilets and Wi-Fi connection. From there we went directly to the entrance of the Roman Forum to buy the ticket that gave us access to the&nbsp;<strong>Forum, the Palatine and the Colosseum</strong>. Why buy it at the Forum and not at the Colosseum? Because the lines are about 20 times shorter in the Forum, the price is the same and the only thing that changes is that the first thing you see is the Palatine and the Roman Forum…</p>



<p>The three places are true gems of history and the only drawback is that the mass tourism and the heat made me desperate at times. However, the reward was worth it since being able to explore on foot three corners that are more than two thousand years old is a true marvel. The price? For those under 25 years of age it is 7.50 euros and for the rest it is 12 euros; something much more than considerable considering the cultural value of all of them.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/rome-a-trip-to-the-eternal-city-in-3-days/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Requirements for traveling with minors</title>
		<link>/en/requirements-for-traveling-with-minors/</link>
					<comments>/en/requirements-for-traveling-with-minors/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 10:37:58 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=2613</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Estamos acostumbrados a viajar solos, con grupos de amigos, pero ¿y con niños? En The Fun Plan sabemos lo estresante que puede llegar a ser planificar un viaje con menores de edad y por ello te queremos echar un cable. Si estás organizando un&#160;viaje escolar con tus alumnos&#160;o por el contrario es un viaje familiar...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are used to traveling alone, with groups of friends, but what about with children? At The Fun Plan we know how stressful it can be to plan a trip with minors and that&#039;s why we want to help you out.</p>



<p>If you are organizing a&nbsp;<a href="/en/journey/" target="_blank" data-type="page" data-id="815" rel="noreferrer noopener">school trip with your students</a>&nbsp;or on the contrary, it is a family trip, it is normal for certain doubts to arise, such as: What documentation does the minor need? What things can&#039;t I forget? Below we provide you with all the information about the&nbsp;<strong>requirements for traveling with minors</strong>&nbsp;in Spain or abroad, and the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.aena.es/es/pasajeros/documentacion-visados/documentacion-para-viajar.html" target="_blank" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.aena.es/es/pasajeros/documentacion-visados/documentacion-para-viajar.html" rel="noreferrer noopener">travel documentation</a>&nbsp;essential that you should not forget.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Travel within Spain and the EU</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>Although the DNI is not mandatory until they are 14 years of age, minors can obtain the National Identity Document from the moment they are born, as long as one of the parents accompanies them to the corresponding office to pay the fees.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Minors under 14 years of age may fly only within national territory without ID as long as they are accompanied by their parents and they carry the Family Book with them. If flying outside of Spain, minors will need a DNI for the countries of the European Union and a Passport for the rest of the countries that do not belong to the EU.</p>



<p>Minors under 14 years of age may not travel alone in any case, however, those between 14 and 16 years of age may travel alone by hiring assistance at the airport. This assistance means that the minor will be accompanied at all times.&nbsp;<strong>From the age of 16, minors may travel alone</strong>, as long as they have authorization from their parents to travel, which must be formalized in writing at any Civil Guard post.</p>



<p>It is recommended to travel within the EU&nbsp;<a href="https://sede.seg-social.gob.es/wps/portal/sede/sede/Ciudadanos" target="_blank" data-type="link" data-id="https://sede.seg-social.gob.es/wps/portal/sede/sede/Ciudadanos" rel="noreferrer noopener">European sanitary card</a>. This document certifies the right of its holder to receive health benefits in the Member States of the European Union, in the rest of the countries of the European Economic Area and in Switzerland. It is valid for one year, and can be processed online or at a Social Security office.</p>



<p>If you need to travel with medications, there is nothing to worry about! Liquid medications are exempt from liquid transportation restrictions. The regulations allow you to travel from any airport in the European Union with medications. It is recommended to always carry them in your hand luggage and accompanied by your prescription or the corresponding medical prescription.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Traveling abroad outside the EU</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>Travel by and with minors is subject to specific restrictions. The border police, both inside and outside the Schengen area, have the specific mandate to pay special attention to minors, whether they are traveling accompanied or not, they will need the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.exteriores.gob.es/es/Paginas/index.aspx" target="_blank" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.exteriores.gob.es/es/Paginas/index.aspx" rel="noreferrer noopener">authorization for minors to travel abroad</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Those minors traveling outside EU countries will need to present their Passport to border agents. For&nbsp;<a href="https://www.policia.es/_es/index.php" target="_blank" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.policia.es/_es/index.php" rel="noreferrer noopener">apply for the passport</a>&nbsp;The same procedure is required as for the DNI, with the difference that the minor&nbsp;<strong>must be accompanied by both parents or, failing that, by their legal guardians</strong>.</p>



<p>If there is only one parent or guardian, this must be justified through sentences, birth certificates, death certificates or any other document in which it is stated and can be demonstrated that only one exists.</p>



<p>Furthermore, when we plan to travel to other countries, we must know if the destination country requires any type of&nbsp;<strong>Visa or Health Certificate</strong>. If this is the case, you must consult the embassy of the destination country about the requirements to request it. Each country imposes its conditions and price of issuance fees, as well as some allow the obtaining of group or family visas.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong><em>Minors traveling alone</em></strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Those minors traveling alone must justify to border agents that they do not leave the national territory against the will of their parents or legal guardians.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong><em>Minors traveling accompanied</em></strong></li>
</ul>



<p>In the event that minors travel accompanied, the requirements and necessary documentation to present at the customs of the destination country will depend on:</p>



<p><em>–&nbsp;<strong>If you travel accompanied by 1 of your parents</strong>:&nbsp;</em>They must request the express authorization of the other absent parent or legal guardian. If there is no other, it will be useful to have documents such as judgments, birth certificates or death certificates to prove that only one exists.</p>



<p>–<em><strong>If the minor&#039;s parents are divorced&nbsp;</strong></em></p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li>The divorce decree must be reviewed and ensure that it allows traveling abroad with the minor.</li>



<li>Present authorization from the other parent or legal guardian giving their consent.</li>



<li>If one of the parties objects to the minor traveling outside the country, a lawyer will have to be consulted, thus requesting judicial authorization. It is advisable to add the minor&#039;s round-trip plane tickets to this application.</li>
</ol>



<p><em>–&nbsp;<strong>If you travel accompanied by adults who are not your parents</strong>:&nbsp;</em>They will need to justify to border agents that custody of the minor has not been unlawfully deprived. To do this, an authorization must be formalized in writing, which must be requested at a Civil Guard office.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/requirements-for-traveling-with-minors/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Beaches and coves to get lost in Mallorca</title>
		<link>/en/beaches-coves-get-lost-in-mallorca/</link>
					<comments>/en/beaches-coves-get-lost-in-mallorca/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 10:24:35 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Mallorca, Spain]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=2606</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mallorca es uno de los destinos predilectos de aquellos viajeros que desean huir del bullicio, el gentío y las playas abarrotadas de familias. Si viajáis a Mallorca, tendréis la suerte de encontrar aquellos paraísos escondidos para disfrutar de unas vacaciones de relax y ensueño en las Baleares. Os chivamos nuestras 6 playas y 6 calas...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Mallorca is one of the favorite destinations for travelers who want to escape the hustle and bustle, the crowds and the beaches crowded with families. If you travel to Mallorca, you will be lucky enough to find those hidden paradises to enjoy a relaxing and dreamlike vacation in the Balearic Islands. We tell you about our 6 beaches and 6 coves where you will live a summer dream.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">6 beaches to get lost in Mallorca</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">PALM BEACH</h3>



<p>It is the largest beach in the capital. With fine sand and crystal clear water, you will have to make room among the hammocks to find a place and relax. An ideal place to have an aperitif while enjoying the eastern sun. It is also perfect to take advantage and try some water sports.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">SA CALOBRA</h3>



<p>The view from this beach is unbeatable: the Sierra de Tramuntana accompanies the landscape. You will reach it through a tunnel next to the cliffs. You will be impressed with the view after the mouth of the Torrent de Pareis.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">FORMENTOR BEACH</h3>



<p>If you want to enjoy the beach and coves in equal measure, then go to the port of Pollença where you will come across Formentor beach. Transparent waters bathe the sand. If you prefer to escape the hustle and bustle of the crowd, you can walk to Cala del Pi de la Posada or Cala Formentor.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">CAN PERE ANTONI BEACH</h3>



<p>It is located just two kilometers from the capital, La Palma, in a spectacular setting as a backdrop: the palm trees of Pº Marítimo, the silhouette of the Gothic Cathedral of Palma and the Episcopal Palace. You will enjoy an environment that seems straight out of a dream.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">ES TRENC BEACH</h3>



<p>If you like walking, go to Es Trenc Beach. Three and a half kilometers of white sand bathe its waters with a dreamlike landscape. If the weather is good you can see the island of Cabrera and wallow among the dunes at the same time. Send us your selfie to #FunPlanMallorca!</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">CALÓ DES MORO</h3>



<p>Only if you are to the south will you enjoy this beach, present in Santanyí. We recommend getting up early to avoid the crowds since it is one of the busiest beaches during the summer. Be sure to visit Es Pontàs, a rock eroded by the waves that looks like a bridge in the water.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">6 coves to get lost in Mallorca</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">CALA BANYALBUFAR</h3>



<p>A freshwater waterfall tops this dreamlike landscape. To get to it you must travel 17 kilometers from Valldemossa. A hidden place with a special charm, perfect for a summer getaway.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">CALA DEIÀ</h3>



<p>If you like trends and want to know where famous people spend their summers, this is your place. Not only will you enjoy the heat, the sun and the sea, but you may even share a dip with some celebrity. Eye! The white sand disappears giving way to gravel. We recommend you walk through it and soak up its fishing tradition.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">CALA MESQUIDA</h3>



<p>We only give you one piece of information: in 1991 Cala Mesquida was declared a Corner of Special Tourist Interest by the Balearic Parliament. To get to it you must travel 7 kilometers from Capdepera. It&#039;s worth a visit, right?</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">CALA MENDIA</h3>



<p>If you are one of those who like natural environments and the mountains, go to Manacor where you will find Cala Mendia. You will be surprised by its surroundings since it is more like a natural pool bathed in white and blue tones. *Funplaner recommendation: from Cala Mendia you can visit Cala Anguila by swimming.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">CALA COMTESSA</h3>



<p>Another point on the island very frequented by Celebrities. A hidden corner in a landscape of pine trees and rocks that surround this white sand paradise. Place frequented by the island&#039;s VIPs. *Funplaner recommendation: if you want to rub shoulders with high standing, come to Puerto Portals.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">CALA ESTÀNCIA</h3>



<p>Cala Estancia is part of a unique setting. A natural pool 3 meters deep and fine white sand. You can escape if you are passing through for the summer in the tourist area of Can Pastilla.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/beaches-coves-get-lost-in-mallorca/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Original Summer Plans In Valencia</title>
		<link>/en/original-summer-plans-in-valencia/</link>
					<comments>/en/original-summer-plans-in-valencia/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 10:00:30 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Valencia, Spain]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=2600</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Todos hemos oído en alguna ocasión que Nueva York nunca duerme, pero la verdad es que cuando empieza el buen tiempo comienzan a surigir nuevos y originales&#160;planes de verano en Valencia. &#160;Y es que desde primera hora del día hasta la última de la noche,&#160;Valencia ofrece multitud de actividades&#160;y eventos para que el verano sea...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We have all heard at some point that New York never sleeps, but the truth is that when the good weather begins, new and original ones begin to emerge.&nbsp;<strong>summer plans in Valencia</strong>. And from the first hour of the day until the last hour of the night,&nbsp;<a href="/en/journey/" target="_blank" data-type="page" data-id="815" rel="noreferrer noopener">Valencia offers a multitude of activities</a>&nbsp;and events to make the summer unforgettable.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">The Nights of the Oceanográfic</h3>



<p>The show lasts 40 minutes, and the museum will be open until 00:00.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">A lake of concerts</h3>



<p>What better way to start your Friday night than with a music concert?</p>



<p>From May to October, the south lake of the Science Museum brings together unforgettable performances called a concert lake where the protagonists are the&nbsp;<strong>Berklee campus students</strong>.</p>



<p>If you want to get away from reggaeton for an hour, in these open-air concerts you can listen to jazz, rock and roll, funk, folk or Mediterranean music.</p>



<p>A great plan to leave the stress of the week behind and start the weekend in the best way.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Sports in Malvarrosa</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>Relax looking at the sea or explore it by snorkeling. The&nbsp;<a href="/en/best-beaches-in-valencia/" target="_blank" data-type="link" data-id="/mejores-playas-de-valencia/" rel="noreferrer noopener">beaches and coves of Valencia</a>&nbsp;They offer a lot of fun plans to do throughout the day.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The city of Valencia is willing to break the beach and beach bar routine in the&nbsp;<strong>Malvarrosa beach</strong>&nbsp;with its new “Physical Activity and Health” program so if you have never been encouraged to practice sports such as yoga, tai chi, Latin fitness or cross training among others, this is the time!</p>



<p>Also... as soon as we feel hot, take a dip in the water!</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/original-summer-plans-in-valencia/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Paris in Two Days</title>
		<link>/en/paris-in-two-days/</link>
					<comments>/en/paris-in-two-days/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 09:03:19 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[París, France]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=2588</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Se acercan las vacaciones de Semana Santa, algunos disfrutarán de unos días libres en la primera semana de mayo y los meses de verano están a ‘la vuelta de la esquina’. Si tienes pensado hacer una escapada y no sabes a dónde ir, te recomendamos una apuesta segura: París. La capital de Francia, además de ser una...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Easter holidays are approaching, some will enjoy a few days off in the first week of May and the summer months are &#039;just around the corner&#039;. If you are planning a getaway and don&#039;t know where to go, we recommend a safe bet: Paris. The capital of France, in addition to being <strong>one of the most touristic cities in the world</strong>, it is perfect to visit in a couple of days. If you want to surprise your partner in the &#039;city of love&#039; or enjoy with your family in a town whose leisure options are endless, we explain what to do in your <a href="/en/journey/" data-type="page" data-id="815">trip to paris</a> in two days.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">ARRIVAL TO THE CAPITAL</h2>



<p>Thanks to low-cost flights, it is increasingly&nbsp;<strong>easy and economical to travel to the French capital</strong>; and whatever airport you land at, you can access the heart of Paris by transport. We recommend that you book your accommodation in the most central neighborhoods or close to the main metro stops, since these days we will be moving around the city by this means of transport. Once you leave your suitcases in your room, head to the Trocadero stop. As soon as you exit the metro you will have a beautiful image of the quintessential symbol of Paris:&nbsp;<strong>the Eiffel Tower</strong>.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img  loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="550" height="828"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Torre-Eiffel.jpg"  alt="Eiffel Tower Paris" class="wp-image-2590" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Torre-Eiffel.jpg 550w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Torre-Eiffel-199x300.jpg 199w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Torre-Eiffel-8x12.jpg 8w" sizes="(max-width: 550px) 100vw, 550px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Eiffel Tower, Paris</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>After taking the first photographs of your trip, go to the foot of the base to&nbsp;<strong>climb to this famous viewpoint</strong>. If you want to ascend on foot you will have to go to the ticket office on the right, while if you want to take the elevator go to the one on the left. You have three different heights, but we definitely recommend that you go to the highest. The entrance price ranges from 5 to 14 euros and the tower remains open until midnight, so you can enjoy the wonderful views of Paris for as long as you want.</p>



<p>From there, we will walk to another of the city&#039;s symbols, the<strong>&nbsp;Arch of Triumph</strong>; and if it is before 11 p.m. and we want to go up, we can do so by paying an entrance fee of 9.50 euros. From above you have impressive views of one of the main arteries of the capital, the Champs Elysées. Before going to our accommodation to rest, we will walk along the famous avenue looking at the elegant windows of the most glamorous stores in the city.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">FIRST DAY</h2>



<p>We will start at the third symbol of the city, the&nbsp;<strong>Notre Dame Cathedral</strong>, and we will be on the left side of the religious temple around 9:30 am. And starting at 10 a.m. you can climb to the top of the towers from where you will have magnificent views of the center of Paris and you can photograph the friendly gargoyles that accompany the entire route. Once down, don&#039;t forget to enter the interior of Notre Dame since access is free, unlike the climb to the towers which costs 8.50 euros.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img  loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="550" height="573"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Notre-Dame.jpg"  alt="Cathedrale Notre-Dame - Paris" class="wp-image-2591" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Notre-Dame.jpg 550w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Notre-Dame-288x300.jpg 288w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Notre-Dame-12x12.jpg 12w" sizes="(max-width: 550px) 100vw, 550px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Cathedrale Notre-Dame – Paris</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>From there we will go to the most visited museum in the world, the&nbsp;<strong>Louvre</strong>, although first we will pass through two of the beautiful bridges that cross the waters of the Seine River: the&nbsp;<strong>New Bridge and the Bridge of Arts</strong>. The latter is &#039;invaded&#039; by millions of padlocks placed by couples in love who want to seal their love with this romantic gesture. After photographing the exterior of the Louvre, we will walk through the<strong>&nbsp;Tuileries Gardens</strong>&nbsp;and we will end up in the center&nbsp;<strong>Concorde Square</strong>. Very close to her is the&nbsp;<strong>Madeleine church</strong>, one of the few free monuments in Paris; and from there we will walk towards the north of the city to see the&nbsp;<strong>Garnier opera</strong>&nbsp;whose entrance costs 9 euros per person.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img  loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="550" height="370"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/opera-garnier.jpg"  alt="Opera Garnier Paris" class="wp-image-2592" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/opera-garnier.jpg 550w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/opera-garnier-300x202.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/opera-garnier-18x12.jpg 18w" sizes="(max-width: 550px) 100vw, 550px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Opera Garnier Paris</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Our next stop is&nbsp;<strong>Basilica of the Sacred Heart</strong>n, and to do this, we will go through the famous&nbsp;<strong>Galeries Lafayette</strong>, the legendary cabaret&nbsp;<strong>Moulin Rouge</strong>&nbsp;and we will climb the endless stairs of the&nbsp;<strong>Montmartre neighborhood</strong>. Admission to the interior of the Sacred Heart is free, and from the outside, you have impressive views of the immense Paris. If we still have the strength, we take a subway to the&nbsp;<strong>Pantheon</strong>&nbsp;since it remains open until 6 p.m. and the entrance price is 7.50 euros.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img  loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="550" height="413"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/galerias-lafayette.jpg"  alt="Galeries Lafayette - Paris" class="wp-image-2593" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/galerias-lafayette.jpg 550w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/galerias-lafayette-300x225.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/galerias-lafayette-16x12.jpg 16w" sizes="(max-width: 550px) 100vw, 550px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Galeries Lafayette – Paris</figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">SECOND DAY</h2>



<p>Depending on the time our flight leaves, we can do more or less things in the last hours of our trip. We recommend that you do not leave the capital without making a&nbsp;<strong>Batobus ride along the Seine</strong>; They are boats that travel from the water to the main monuments of the city. And three monuments that we can find precisely on the banks of the river are the&nbsp;<strong>&#039;Small&#039; and &#039;Big&#039; Palace</strong>&nbsp;and the&nbsp;<strong>Invalides monument</strong>; The entrance price for the latter is 9 euros while access to the palaces is free. If we want to see something else, there are numerous museums that are worth visiting, although after the Louvre we highlight the&nbsp;<strong>Orsay&#039;s Museum</strong>&nbsp;as the most appropriate option.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img  loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="550" height="276"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Museo-Orsay.jpg"  alt="Orsay Museum - Paris" class="wp-image-2595" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Museo-Orsay.jpg 550w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Museo-Orsay-300x151.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Museo-Orsay-18x9.jpg 18w" sizes="(max-width: 550px) 100vw, 550px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Orsay Museum - Paris</figcaption></figure></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/paris-in-two-days/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Full Moon Alert for Travelers in Spain: October 2023's Luminous Spectacle</title>
		<link>/en/full-moon-october-spain/</link>
					<comments>/en/full-moon-october-spain/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 03:23:25 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Noticias y Eventos]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[luna llena octubre 2023]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=2533</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[¡Atención, viajeros y visitantes en España! El mes de octubre trae consigo un regalo celestial que no querrán perderse. La Luna del Cazador está lista para iluminar los cielos españoles, ofreciendo una vista impresionante que complementa perfectamente la belleza de España. Históricamente conocida como la Luna del Cazador, este evento lunar tiene raíces en las...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Attention travelers and visitors in Spain! The month of October brings with it a heavenly gift that you won&#039;t want to miss. The Hunter&#039;s Moon is ready to light up the Spanish skies, offering a stunning view that perfectly complements the <a href="/en/destinos/spain/" data-type="link" data-id="/destinos/spain/">beauty of Spain</a>.</p>



<p>Historically known as the Hunter&#039;s Moon, this lunar event has roots in the traditions of the native tribes of North America. They used this time, with the only position of the moon low on the horizon, to hunt at night, preparing for the colder months to come.</p>



<p>Mark your calendars! The full Hunter&#039;s Moon is scheduled to grace the skies on the last weekend of October 2023. The most radiant moment is expected to be on Saturday, October 28 at 10:24 pm Spanish local time. Although it will be almost full the day before, the glow of the moon on the 28th is something every traveler should experience.</p>



<p>Fun fact for those exploring Spain during Halloween: The Hunter&#039;s Moon will shine brightly just days before Halloween. Since October 31 is a national holiday here, many Spanish towns take advantage of the moon&#039;s glow to enhance their spooky celebrations. So, if you&#039;re a fan of legends, watch out for those werewolves who might be basking in the lunar glow!</p>



<p>This moon often appears larger with a hint of orange, evoking a focus that guided hunters in the past. With the Harvest Moon of the previous month already past, the open fields become a park for wildlife, illuminated by this moon.</p>



<p>Aunque &#8220;Luna del Cazador&#8221; es su nombre más común, diversas culturas tienen sus propios títulos para este evento lunar. Algunas tribus lo nombraron basándose en su color, mientras que otras se inspiraron en la naturaleza. Nombres como Luna del Arroz Seco, Luna de las Hojas Caídas, Luna Congelada y Luna de Hielo insinúan el cambio de estaciones. Para los entusiastas de las aves, el nombre de la tribu Cree, Luna Migratoria, podría resonar, ya que coincide con la temporada de migración de las aves.</p>



<p>So whether you&#039;re in Spain for leisure or adventure, be sure to look up and enjoy this natural wonder! Have a safe trip and clear skies!</p>



<p>Lea más al respecto aquí: <a href="https://www.heraldo.es/noticias/sociedad/2023/10/23/cuando-es-luna-llena-octubre-2023-1686175.html" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.heraldo.es/noticias/sociedad/2023/10/23/cuando-es-luna-llena-octubre-2023-1686175.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">www.heraldo.es</a></p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/full-moon-october-spain/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Connecting with Glasgow City Council: 3 Easy Steps</title>
		<link>/en/glasgow-city-council-contact-information/</link>
					<comments>/en/glasgow-city-council-contact-information/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 15:20:37 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Glasgow]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Glasgow City Council]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=2025</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[¿Estás buscando conectar con el Ayuntamiento de la Ciudad de Glasgow? ¡Es más fácil de lo que crees! En solo tres simples pasos, puedes ponerte en contacto y hacer que tu voz sea escuchada. Encuentra su información de contacto, elige tu método de comunicación preferido e inicia el contacto. Este artículo te guiará a través...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Are you looking to connect with Glasgow City Council? It is easier than you think! In just three simple steps, you can get in touch and make your voice heard.</p>



<p>Find their contact information, choose your preferred communication method and initiate contact.</p>



<p>This article will guide you through the process, giving you the freedom to connect and make a difference.</p>



<p>So let&#039;s start connecting with Glasgow City Council today!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Key points</h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Find contact information through the official website or community resources.</li>



<li>Choose the preferred communication method based on your needs and preferences.</li>



<li>Initiate contact through phone calls, emails, or online contact forms.</li>



<li>Ensure effective communication by being clear, concise and providing necessary details.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Finding Contact Information</h2>



<p>To find Glasgow City Council contact information, follow these three easy steps.</p>



<p>Primero, accede a los servicios en línea para obtener sus datos de contacto. Visita el sitio web oficial del Ayuntamiento de Glasgow y dirígete a la sección de &#8220;Contacto&#8221;. Allí encontrarás una lista de varios departamentos y su información de contacto correspondiente, incluyendo números de teléfono y direcciones de correo electrónico.</p>



<p>Second, use community resources. Local libraries often have directories or information boards with contact details for government offices, including city hall. You can also check community centers or local government buildings for any available contact information.</p>



<p>Finally, if you can&#039;t find contact information through online services or community resources, consider contacting City Hall&#039;s customer service line for assistance.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Choose your preferred communication method</h2>



<p>Choose your preferred method of communication with Glasgow City Council taking into account your needs and preferences. Effective communication is crucial in any government organisation, and Glasgow City Council understands the importance of providing excellent customer service to its residents. By selecting the communication method that best suits you, you can ensure that your concerns are addressed quickly and efficiently.</p>



<p>There are several options available for contacting Glasgow City Council, including phone calls, emails and online forms. Each method has its own benefits. Phone calls allow for immediate conversation and clarification, while emails provide a written record of your correspondence. Online forms offer convenience and the ability to attach supporting documents.</p>



<p>Consider your specific needs and preferences when choosing your preferred communication method. Whether you value speed, convenience or a combination of both, Glasgow City Council is committed to providing you with the highest level of customer service.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Initiating contact with Glasgow City Council</h2>



<p>By initiating contact with Glasgow City Council, you can easily communicate via the communication method of your choice. Effective communication is key so that your concerns are addressed and your questions answered quickly. Here are three simple steps to start contacting Glasgow City Council:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li>Telephone: Call the council&#039;s helpline at [phone number] to speak directly to a representative who can help you with your queries or problems.</li>



<li>Email: Write a detailed email describing your concerns and send it to [email address]. Be sure to include your contact information to receive a quick response.</li>



<li>Online form: Visit the Glasgow City Council website and complete the online contact form. Provide all the necessary details and submit the form to receive a timely response.</li>
</ol>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Frequent questions</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Can I email Glasgow City Council about a noise complaint?</h3>



<p>Yes, you can email Glasgow City Council to report a noise complaint. They offer an email communication option to address these types of issues, ensuring compliance with noise pollution regulations.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">How long does it usually take Glasgow City Council to respond to a street cleaning request?</h3>



<p>Glasgow City Council normally responds to street cleaning requests within a reasonable timeframe. You can expect a quick response from them regarding your request.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What is the process for reporting a pothole to Glasgow City Council?</h3>



<p>To report a pothole to Glasgow City Council, follow a simple process. Reporting potholes benefits everyone by improving road safety and preventing further damage. Your input is valuable, so don&#039;t hesitate to report any potholes you encounter.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Can Glasgow City Council provide assistance in finding affordable housing?</h3>



<p>Yes, Glasgow City Council can help you find housing assistance programmes. They will provide you with information about the eligibility criteria for affordable housing, ensuring you can access the help you need.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">How can I request a copy of a birth certificate from Glasgow City Council?</h3>



<p>To request a copy of your birth certificate from Glasgow City Council, simply contact your local government office. They will guide you through the process and provide you with the necessary information and forms.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h2>



<p>In conclusion, connecting with Glasgow City Council is a simple process that can be achieved in just three easy steps.</p>



<p>By finding contact information, selecting your preferred method of communication, and initiating contact, you can effectively engage with City Hall.</p>



<p>Whether you have questions, concerns or suggestions, contacting Glasgow City Council is a great way to stay informed and get involved in the community.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/glasgow-city-council-contact-information/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>