<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>Brighton Beaches &#8211; The Fun Plan</title>
	<atom:link href="/en/tag/brighton-beaches/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/en</link>
	<description>Crafting Moments, Creating Memories: Your Guide to Flawless Events.</description>
	<lastbuilddate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 15:07:35 +0000</lastbuilddate>
	<language>in-GB</language>
	<sy:updateperiod>
	hourly	</sy:updateperiod>
	<sy:updatefrequency>
	1	</sy:updatefrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/09/favi.png</url>
	<title>Brighton Beaches &#8211; The Fun Plan</title>
	<link>/en</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Sun, sand and smiles: Discovering Brighton&#039;s best family beaches</title>
		<link>/en/family-friendly-sandy-beaches-in-brighton-and-hove/</link>
					<comments>/en/family-friendly-sandy-beaches-in-brighton-and-hove/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Sun, 22 Oct 2023 15:03:48 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Brighton and Hove]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brighton Beaches]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=2020</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Prepárate para disfrutar del sol, sentir la arena entre tus pies y experimentar sonrisas interminables en las mejores playas familiares de Brighton. En este artículo, revelaremos los tesoros ocultos que harán que tus días en la playa sean inolvidables. Desde la vibrante playa de Brighton hasta la tranquila playa de Saltdean, hay un lugar perfecto...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Get ready to soak up the sun, feel the sand between your feet and experience endless smiles on Brighton&#039;s best family beaches.</p>



<p>In this article, we will reveal the hidden treasures that will make your days at the beach unforgettable.</p>



<p>From vibrant Brighton Beach to tranquil Saltdean Beach, there&#039;s a perfect spot for every family.</p>



<p>So grab your sunscreen, pack the picnic, and get ready for a day of fun and relaxation by the sea.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Key Takeaways</h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Brighton Beach, Hove Lagoon, Rottingdean Beach and Saltdean Beach are the main family beaches in Brighton.</li>



<li>Peacehaven Beach, Shoreham Beach and Southwick Beach are ideal for those looking for a quiet and relaxing beach experience.</li>



<li>West Pier Beach and Portslade Beach offer historical significance and nearby attractions for visitors.</li>



<li>Family beaches in Brighton offer excellent services and facilities for families, including clean toilets, changing rooms, ample parking areas, food stalls, play areas and designated areas for beach sports.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Brighton Beach</h2>



<p>Brighton Beach offers a variety of family-friendly amenities and activities for a fun day by the sea. With its soft sand and gentle waves, it&#039;s the perfect place to build sandcastles and splash around.</p>



<p>The beach is equipped with well-maintained playgrounds, offering endless entertainment for children of all ages. Parents can relax on the beach while keeping an eye on their little ones, thanks to lifeguards on duty who ensure safety in the water at all times.</p>



<p>Brighton Beach prides itself on creating a safe environment for families to enjoy, with clear signs indicating designated swimming areas and safety guidelines.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Hove Lagoon</h2>



<p>You&#039;ll find another family-friendly beach option at Hove Lagoon, which offers a variety of activities and amenities for a day of fun in the sun.</p>



<p>Hove Lagoon is the perfect destination for water sports enthusiasts, with a variety of activities to choose from. Whether you&#039;re a beginner or a seasoned expert, there&#039;s something for everyone. Try your skill at paddleboarding, kayaking or windsurfing, and feel the thrill of gliding on the water.</p>



<p>If you prefer to stay on land, you can enjoy the sandy beach and sunbathe while the kids build sandcastles. Hove Lagoon also regularly hosts family events, such as beach volleyball tournaments and outdoor movie nights.</p>



<p>With its vibrant atmosphere and exciting activities, Hove Lagoon is the ultimate beach destination for families seeking adventure and freedom.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Rottingdean Beach</h2>



<p>Just a short drive east of Brighton, discover a host of attractions and a beach that offers a peaceful getaway: Rottingdean Beach.</p>



<p>This hidden gem is perfect for families looking for a day of fun and relaxation. With its golden sand and gentle waves, it offers a safe and welcoming environment for children to play and explore. Take part in a variety of kid-friendly activities, such as building sandcastles, flying kites, or enjoying a picnic on the shore.</p>



<p>But that&#039;s not all Rottingdean Beach has to offer. Keep your eyes open for the local wildlife that calls this beach home. From seagulls flying overhead to crabs scampering along the shore, there is always something fascinating to discover.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Saltdean Beach</h2>



<p>Continue your beach adventure east of Rottingdean Beach to discover another family-friendly destination: Saltdean Beach.</p>



<p>Located along Brighton&#039;s stunning coastline, Saltdean Beach offers a perfect retreat for a fun-filled day with your loved ones.</p>



<p>Stepping onto the soft golden sand, you will be greeted by a picturesque view of the dazzling blue sea stretching out before you.</p>



<p>Saltdean Beach has excellent play facilities, ensuring that children of all ages can enjoy endless hours of excitement and entertainment. Let the little ones climb, slide and swing as they please while you relax and enjoy the sun.</p>



<p>After working up an appetite, head to one of the beachfront cafes and treat yourself to a delicious meal or a refreshing drink while taking in the stunning ocean views.</p>



<p>At Saltdean Beach, freedom and fun are guaranteed for the whole family.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Ovingdean Beach</h2>



<p>Get ready to discover the family charm of Ovingdean Beach.</p>



<p>With its well-equipped playgrounds and spacious picnic spots, this beach is perfect for a day of fun and relaxation.</p>



<p>Plus, you&#039;ll find water safety measures to ensure a worry-free experience, making it an ideal choice for families.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Playgrounds and picnic spots</h3>



<p>When you visit Ovingdean Beach, you&#039;ll discover a variety of playgrounds and picnic areas that are perfect for family fun in the sun. Here, you can enjoy the freedom of letting your kids roam and play while you relax and soak up the coastal charm.</p>



<p>Ovingdean Beach offers a welcoming atmosphere with its well-maintained playground equipment and spacious picnic areas. You&#039;ll find everything you need to keep the little ones entertained, from slides and swings to climbing structures and sandboxes.</p>



<p>And when it&#039;s time to recharge, take advantage of the conveniently located picnic spots, where you can enjoy a delicious meal with stunning ocean views.</p>



<p>With its mix of fun-filled play areas and picturesque picnic spots, Ovingdean Beach is a haven for families looking for a day of outdoor fun.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Safety measures in the water</h3>



<p>At Ovingdean Beach, prioritize water safety measures to ensure a day of carefree family fun in the sun. Ovingdean Beach is known for its commitment to beach safety and has taken several measures to ensure the well-being of its visitors.</p>



<p>One of the most important aspects of water safety is the presence of trained lifeguards. Ovingdean Beach has a team of vigilant lifeguards who are always on duty, keeping a close eye on swimmers and providing help when necessary. Its presence provides a feeling of security and tranquility to families who enjoy the beach.</p>



<p>In addition to lifeguards, Ovingdean Beach also has clear signage indicating potential hazards and safety guidelines. These measures, combined with the vigilance of lifeguards, make Ovingdean Beach a perfect destination for families looking for a safe and enjoyable beach experience.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Accessibility for families</h3>



<p>You can easily access Ovingdean Beach with your family, thanks to its convenient location and family-friendly facilities. Located just a short drive from Brighton, this lovely beach offers everything you need for a fun-filled day with your loved ones.</p>



<p>Here are some reasons why Ovingdean Beach is the perfect choice for families:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Family-friendly accommodation options: Ovingdean Beach is surrounded by a variety of family-friendly accommodation, ranging from cozy cottages to spacious holiday apartments. You can easily find a place to stay that suits your family&#039;s needs and preferences.</li>



<li>Accessible transport options for families: Ovingdean Beach is well connected to the rest of Brighton, making it easy to access for families. Whether you choose to drive, take a bus, or even bike, there are many transportation options available to suit your family&#039;s comfort.</li>



<li>Family-friendly facilities: Ovingdean Beach offers a variety of amenities designed to make your family&#039;s visit enjoyable. From clean, well-maintained facilities to lifeguard services, you can relax knowing that your family&#039;s safety and comfort are taken care of.</li>
</ul>



<p>With its accessibility, family-friendly accommodation options and convenient transport, Ovingdean Beach is the ideal destination for families looking for an unforgettable beach holiday.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Peacehaven Beach</h2>



<p>One of the best family beaches in Brighton is Peacehaven Beach, known for its calm atmosphere and stunning views. Stepping onto the soft golden sand, you will immediately notice the tranquility that surrounds this hidden gem.</p>



<p>Peacehaven Beach is perfect for families looking for a quiet escape from the bustling city. Explore the fascinating rock pools with the little ones, discovering fascinating sea creatures and shells along the way.</p>



<p>The beach also offers picturesque coastal walks, where you can immerse yourself in the beauty of nature while feeling the refreshing sea breeze on your skin.</p>



<p>Whether building sandcastles, enjoying a picnic along the shore, or simply soaking up the sun, Peacehaven Beach provides the freedom and serenity you&#039;re looking for for a memorable family day.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Shoreham Beach</h2>



<p>Continuing our exploration of Brighton&#039;s best family beaches, we will now turn our attention to the captivating shores of Shoreham Beach. Here you will find a paradise that offers not only sun and sand, but also exciting surfing opportunities and exciting wildlife viewing adventures.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Surfing opportunities</strong>: If you&#039;re looking for an adrenaline rush, Shoreham Beach is the place to be. The rolling waves offer the perfect conditions for surfing enthusiasts to catch some serious waves and experience the freedom of riding the ocean.</li>



<li><strong>Wildlife sighting</strong>: Prepare to marvel at the diverse variety of wildlife that calls Shoreham Beach home. Keep your eyes peeled for curious seals poking their heads out of the water or graceful dolphins leaping through the waves. Bird watchers will be delighted by the sight of graceful herons and colorful kingfishers.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Southwick Beach</h2>



<p>Are you looking for a beach with a touch of charm and tranquility? Look no further than Southwick Beach! This hidden gem in Brighton offers a peaceful escape from the hustle and bustle of city life. With its pristine sandy shores and crystal clear waters, Southwick Beach is the perfect destination for families looking to spend quality time together.</p>



<p>Southwick Beach is known for its family-friendly activities. From building sand castles to flying kites, there is something for everyone to enjoy. The beach also offers a variety of beach facilities, including picnic areas, showers and toilets, ensuring your family&#039;s needs are well catered for.</p>



<p>Whether you want to relax in the sun, take a dip in the sea or enjoy exciting beach games, Southwick Beach has it all. So pack your sunscreen, grab your beach towel, and head to Southwick Beach for a day of fun and relaxation with your loved ones.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Portslade Beach</h2>



<p>If you&#039;re craving a beach with a lively atmosphere and plenty of activities, look no further than Portslade Beach. This vibrant seaside venue offers something for the whole family. Here are three reasons why Portslade Beach should be at the top of your list:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Facilities for the whole family: Portslade Beach has excellent facilities, including clean public toilets, convenient parking options and accessible ramps for strollers and wheelchairs. You can relax and enjoy the sun knowing that your family&#039;s needs are met.</li>



<li>Beach Activities: From building sand castles to playing beach volleyball, Portslade Beach offers a wide range of activities to keep you entertained. Grab a Frisbee and challenge your loved ones to a game or take a leisurely walk along the shore. The possibilities are endless.</li>



<li>Lively atmosphere: Portslade Beach is known for its bustling atmosphere. Join the fun by visiting during one of the festivals or events held throughout the year. Experience the freedom of being surrounded by happy faces and positive energy.</li>
</ul>



<p>Portslade Beach is the perfect destination for a day of sun, sand and smiles.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">West Pier Beach</h2>



<p>Get ready to step back in time at West Pier Beach, where history comes to life. The iconic remains of West Pier, a Victorian pleasure pier destroyed by fire, provide a fascinating backdrop for your family beach day.</p>



<p>With its family-friendly amenities, including showers, restrooms, and lifeguards, West Pier Beach ensures a comfortable and safe experience for everyone.</p>



<p>Plus, you&#039;ll find plenty of attractions and activities nearby to keep the whole family entertained.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">History of the West Pier</h3>



<p>Families can often be seen enjoying the rich history of West Pier Beach while exploring its fascinating past. The West Pier, Brighton&#039;s iconic landmark, has great historical importance, attracting visitors from all over the world.</p>



<p>Here are some interesting facts about the history of West Pier:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>The West Pier, opened in 1866, was once a bustling entertainment venue, hosting concerts, theaters and even a roller coaster.</li>



<li>Over the years, coastal erosion has taken its toll on the West Pier, resulting in its closure in 1975.</li>



<li>Despite its dilapidated state, the West Pier has a special charm, serving as a reminder of Brighton&#039;s vibrant past.</li>
</ul>



<p>Today, families can stroll along the beach, marveling at the remains of the West Pier and imagining the lively atmosphere that once graced its decks. It is a place where freedom and history intertwine, offering a glimpse into Brighton&#039;s bygone era.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Services for the whole family</h3>



<p>As you explore the family-friendly West Pier Beach, you&#039;ll find a variety of amenities to suit all ages and ensure a memorable day by the sea. The beach is equipped with top-notch facilities for families, making it a perfect destination to spend a day with your loved ones.</p>



<p>There are clean, well-maintained bathrooms, comfortable changing rooms, and ample parking spaces. You&#039;ll also find a variety of food stalls and cafes offering delicious snacks and refreshing drinks.</p>



<p>But that&#039;s not all, West Pier Beach goes above and beyond to provide entertainment for children. There are play areas with swings, slides and climbing structures, as well as designated areas for beach volleyball and soccer. Your little ones will have fun building sand castles, flying kites and splashing in the shallow waters.</p>



<p>West Pier Beach truly has everything you need for a fun-filled family day at the beach.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Nearby attractions and activities</h3>



<p>As you explore West Pier Beach, you&#039;ll discover a variety of nearby attractions and activities to add even more excitement to your family day at the beach. Here are some highlights:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Nearby Shopping Options</strong>: Just steps from the beach, you will find a variety of charming shops and boutiques. From trendy clothing stores to unique souvenir shops, there is something for everyone. Take a leisurely walk and explore the local offerings, or enjoy a meal at one of the many cafes and restaurants in the area.</li>



<li><strong>Outdoor recreational activities</strong>: If you&#039;re looking for adventure, West Pier Beach has what you need. You can rent bikes and explore the scenic coastal trails, or try stand-up paddleboarding or kayaking in the crystal-clear waters. For those who prefer a more relaxed pace, there are many picnic spots and green areas where you can relax and enjoy the beautiful surroundings.</li>
</ul>



<p>With these nearby attractions and activities, your family day at West Pier Beach is sure to be full of fun, adventure, and unforgettable memories. So grab your sunscreen and get ready to make the most of your time in Brighton!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Black Rock Beach</h2>



<p>Located just steps from the lively Brighton Pier, Black Rock Beach offers a picturesque, family-friendly setting to enjoy a day of fun in the sun.</p>



<p>This beautiful sandy beach is perfect for building sandcastles, playing beach volleyball, or just relaxing and enjoying the sun.</p>



<p>Black Rock Beach is known for its vibrant atmosphere and is a popular location for various events throughout the year. From live music performances to beach parties, there&#039;s always something exciting happening in Black Rock.</p>



<p>The beach also has excellent facilities for families, including clean, well-maintained toilets, outdoor showers and ample parking spaces.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Kemp Town Beach</h2>



<p>Get ready to discover the family charm of Kemp Town Beach! This stretch of sand offers a variety of kid-friendly amenities, making it the perfect place to spend a day of fun in the sun.</p>



<p>From playgrounds and beach volleyball courts to ice cream stands and snack kiosks, there is something for everyone here.</p>



<p>Plus, with a variety of restaurant options nearby, you won&#039;t have to go far to satisfy your hunger after a day of beachside adventures.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Services available for children</h3>



<p>Enjoy a variety of kid-friendly amenities at Kemp Town Beach, making it the perfect destination for families looking to have a fun-filled day by the sea. Here are some of the fantastic features that will keep your little ones entertained:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Playground</strong>: Let your kids unleash their energy at the beachside playground, complete with swings, slides and climbing frames. They will have fun while you relax nearby.</li>



<li><strong>Splash Area</strong>: Cool off on those hot summer days with the splash pad. Watch your children laugh with joy as they run between the fountains and water jets.</li>



<li><strong>Beach Games</strong>: From building sand castles to beach volleyball, there are countless games available for your family to enjoy. Challenge each other to friendly competition or just have fun playing together.</li>
</ul>



<p>At Kemp Town beach you will find endless opportunities for your children to have an unforgettable day by the sea. So grab your sunscreen, pack a picnic, and get ready for a day full of laughter and joy.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Nearby restaurant options.</h3>



<p>Looking for a place to eat near Kemp Town Beach? You&#039;re lucky! There are many dining options available, from beachfront restaurants to family-friendly cafes.</p>



<p>If you&#039;re in the mood for delicious seafood with a stunning view, head to one of the beachfront restaurants. These establishments offer a wide variety of fresh seafood dishes, from succulent fish and chips to delicious grilled prawns.</p>



<p>For those with young children, family cafes are the perfect choice. These cafes not only cater to the tastes of both adults and children, but also offer a cozy and relaxed atmosphere. You can enjoy a hearty breakfast, a light lunch or treat yourself to some sweets while the kids have a play area to entertain themselves.</p>



<p>No matter what you&#039;re craving, Kemp Town Beach has something for everyone. So go ahead and satisfy your hunger while enjoying the beautiful beach views.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Frequent questions</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Are dogs allowed on the beaches mentioned in the article?</h3>



<p>Yes, dogs are allowed on the beaches mentioned in the article. You&#039;ll love the clean beaches and amenities available for your furry friend. Feel free to bring them and enjoy the sun and sand together.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">What are the parking facilities like at each of the beaches mentioned?</h3>



<p>Parking at the aforementioned beaches is easy and convenient. You will find a lot of availability and the cost is reasonable. If you prefer public transportation, there are options nearby to make your trip hassle-free. Enjoy your day at the beach!</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Are there any water sports or activities available for children on these beaches?</h3>



<p>Looking for water sports and beach activities for your kids? Brighton&#039;s best family beaches have you covered! From surf lessons to beach volleyball, there is something for everyone to enjoy in the sun and on the sand.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Are there any nearby attractions or monuments worth visiting while you&#039;re on these beaches?</h3>



<p>While you&#039;re on these family-friendly beaches, you&#039;ll find nearby attractions and landmarks worth visiting. From the stunning Royal Pavilion to the vibrant Brighton Pier, there is something for everyone to enjoy and explore.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Are there any restrictions on barbecues or picnics on the beaches mentioned?</h3>



<p>Are there restrictions on barbecues or picnics on the beaches mentioned? Enjoy the freedom of having a barbecue or picnic on these family-friendly beaches in Brighton. Bring your favorite grill and spread out your picnic blanket without any regulation.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h2>



<p>So if you&#039;re looking for a day full of sun, sand and smiles, Brighton&#039;s family-friendly beaches have everything you need.</p>



<p>From lively Brighton Beach to quiet Ovingdean Beach, there is something for everyone to enjoy.</p>



<p>With easy access and a variety of amenities, these beaches provide the perfect setting for a fun family outing.</p>



<p>So grab your sunscreen, pack a picnic and head to one of Brighton&#039;s best beaches for a day of seaside adventure.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/family-friendly-sandy-beaches-in-brighton-and-hove/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>