<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>Valencia, Spain &#8211; The Fun Plan</title>
	<atom:link href="/en/destinations/spain/valencia/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/en</link>
	<description>Crafting Moments, Creating Memories: Your Guide to Flawless Events.</description>
	<lastbuilddate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 03:24:51 +0000</lastbuilddate>
	<language>in-GB</language>
	<sy:updateperiod>
	hourly	</sy:updateperiod>
	<sy:updatefrequency>
	1	</sy:updatefrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/09/favi.png</url>
	<title>Valencia, Spain &#8211; The Fun Plan</title>
	<link>/en</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Original Summer Plans In Valencia</title>
		<link>/en/original-summer-plans-in-valencia/</link>
					<comments>/en/original-summer-plans-in-valencia/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 10:00:30 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Valencia, Spain]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=2600</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Todos hemos oído en alguna ocasión que Nueva York nunca duerme, pero la verdad es que cuando empieza el buen tiempo comienzan a surigir nuevos y originales&#160;planes de verano en Valencia. &#160;Y es que desde primera hora del día hasta la última de la noche,&#160;Valencia ofrece multitud de actividades&#160;y eventos para que el verano sea...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We have all heard at some point that New York never sleeps, but the truth is that when the good weather begins, new and original ones begin to emerge.&nbsp;<strong>summer plans in Valencia</strong>. And from the first hour of the day until the last hour of the night,&nbsp;<a href="/en/journey/" target="_blank" data-type="page" data-id="815" rel="noreferrer noopener">Valencia offers a multitude of activities</a>&nbsp;and events to make the summer unforgettable.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">The Nights of the Oceanográfic</h3>



<p>The show lasts 40 minutes, and the museum will be open until 00:00.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">A lake of concerts</h3>



<p>What better way to start your Friday night than with a music concert?</p>



<p>From May to October, the south lake of the Science Museum brings together unforgettable performances called a concert lake where the protagonists are the&nbsp;<strong>Berklee campus students</strong>.</p>



<p>If you want to get away from reggaeton for an hour, in these open-air concerts you can listen to jazz, rock and roll, funk, folk or Mediterranean music.</p>



<p>A great plan to leave the stress of the week behind and start the weekend in the best way.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Sports in Malvarrosa</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>Relax looking at the sea or explore it by snorkeling. The&nbsp;<a href="/en/best-beaches-in-valencia/" target="_blank" data-type="link" data-id="/mejores-playas-de-valencia/" rel="noreferrer noopener">beaches and coves of Valencia</a>&nbsp;They offer a lot of fun plans to do throughout the day.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>The city of Valencia is willing to break the beach and beach bar routine in the&nbsp;<strong>Malvarrosa beach</strong>&nbsp;with its new “Physical Activity and Health” program so if you have never been encouraged to practice sports such as yoga, tai chi, Latin fitness or cross training among others, this is the time!</p>



<p>Also... as soon as we feel hot, take a dip in the water!</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/original-summer-plans-in-valencia/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Best Restaurants Near the City of Arts and Sciences in Valencia, Spain</title>
		<link>/en/restaurants-near-the-city-of-arts-and-sciences/</link>
					<comments>/en/restaurants-near-the-city-of-arts-and-sciences/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 14:59:17 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Valencia, Spain]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=1233</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[¿Buscas una aventura gastronómica cerca de la vibrante Ciudad de las Artes y las Ciencias en Valencia, España? Prepárate para deleitar tus papilas gustativas con una variedad de opciones deliciosas. Desde restaurantes informales y relajados hasta experiencias gastronómicas de alta gama, este paraíso culinario lo tiene todo. Disfruta de la cocina tradicional española, explora sabores...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Looking for a gastronomic adventure near the vibrant City of Arts and Sciences in Valencia, Spain? Get ready to delight your taste buds with a variety of delicious options.</p>



<p>From casual, relaxed restaurants to high-end dining experiences, this culinary paradise has it all. Enjoy traditional Spanish cuisine, explore international flavors or choose healthy and vegetarian options.</p>



<p>Don&#039;t miss the freshest seafood specialties and the vibrant atmosphere of the local tapas bars.</p>



<p>Get ready to taste the freedom of a food lover&#039;s paradise.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Main points to take into account</h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Valencia&#039;s culinary scene offers a wide variety of dining options, from traditional Valencian restaurants to modern fusion venues.</li>



<li>The city is known for its vibrant and affordable food options, allowing visitors to enjoy delicious meals without spending a lot.</li>



<li>Valencia is home to several Michelin-starred restaurants, offering high-end dining experiences for those who wish to delight in the art of gastronomy.</li>



<li>Visitors can explore traditional Spanish cuisine, including seafood dishes such as paella, as well as tempting tapas that showcase the diversity of Spanish cuisine.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Casual Dining Options</h2>



<p>You&#039;ll find several casual dining options near the City of Arts and Sciences in Valencia, Spain. Valencia is known for its vibrant food scene, and there are many affordable restaurant options for you to explore. The city is jumping on the casual dining trends, offering a variety of relaxed places where you can enjoy delicious food without breaking the bank.</p>



<p>A popular option is La Pepica, a traditional Valencian restaurant that has been serving paella since 1898. Its charming beachfront location and authentic cuisine make it a must-visit for any food lover.</p>



<p>If you feel like something more contemporary, go to Cañitas Mañas. This trendy spot offers a fusion of Mediterranean and Asian flavors, creating a unique and exciting dining experience.</p>



<p>Whether you&#039;re looking for traditional or innovative cuisine, Valencia&#039;s casual restaurant scene has something for everyone. So go ahead and enjoy the city&#039;s diverse culinary offerings without worrying about your budget.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Haute cuisine experiences</h2>



<p>To fully immerse yourself in Valencia&#039;s culinary scene near the City of Arts and Sciences, be sure to experience the fine dining options available. Here are some top recommendations for a memorable fine dining experience:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Ricard Camarena Restaurant</strong>: Enjoy modern gastronomy at this Michelin-starred restaurant, where chef Ricard Camarena creates innovative dishes using locally sourced ingredients. The elegant atmosphere and impeccable service enhance the entire dining experience.</li>



<li><strong>Quique Dacosta Restaurant</strong>: Get ready to marvel at the culinary creations of chef Quique Dacosta, whose restaurant has three Michelin stars. The avant-garde dishes are inspired by the traditions and ingredients of the region, resulting in a truly unique dining experience.</li>



<li><strong>Vertical</strong>: Located on the 24th floor of the Hospes Palau de la Mar Hotel, this Michelin-starred restaurant offers stunning views of the city skyline. Enjoy a fusion of Mediterranean and international flavors, expertly prepared by chef Jorge de Andrés.</li>



<li><strong>Saiti</strong>: Experience a fusion of traditional Valencian cuisine with a modern twist at this Michelin-starred gem. The intimate atmosphere and meticulous attention to detail create a truly unforgettable culinary journey.</li>
</ul>



<p>Enjoy these haute cuisine experiences and savor the art of Valencia&#039;s gastronomic scene.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Traditional Spanish cuisine</h2>



<p>Explore the rich flavors and culinary traditions of Spain with traditional Spanish cuisine near the City of Arts and Sciences in Valencia.</p>



<p>Enjoy a gastronomic journey while savoring authentic dishes full of regional flavors. Valencia, being a coastal city, offers an abundance of seafood delicacies. Dive into a bowl of paella, a renowned rice dish cooked with saffron and a variety of ingredients such as shrimp, mussels and chicken.</p>



<p>For meat lovers, try the succulent Jamón Ibérico, a cured ham that melts in your mouth. Don&#039;t miss the tempting tapas, small portions of delicious bites that showcase the diversity of Spanish cuisine. From patatas bravas to chorizo in wine, each tapa is a delightful explosion of flavors.</p>



<p>Immerse yourself in the vibrant culinary scene and discover the true essence of Spanish cuisine.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">International flavors</h2>



<p>Get ready to embark on a culinary journey that transcends borders.</p>



<p>Valencia&#039;s food scene offers a variety of global culinary experiences, where international flavors collide and create a fusion of cultural tastes.</p>



<p>From Asian-inspired dishes to Latin American delicacies, you&#039;ll find diverse international menus to satisfy your adventurous palate.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Global culinary experiences</h3>



<p>Discover a wide variety of international flavors in the best restaurants near the City of Arts and Sciences in Valencia, Spain. Immerse yourself in a culinary adventure that will transport your taste buds to different corners of the world.</p>



<p>Here are some global culinary experiences you must try in Valencia:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Indulge in spicy and aromatic Indian dishes at the vibrant and colorful Indian restaurant, where you can savor authentic curries and fragrant biryanis.</li>



<li>Sample the delicious delights of Mexican street food at lively taquerias, where you can indulge in tasty tacos, quesadillas and guacamole.</li>



<li>Experience the delicate and intricate flavors of Japan at the elegant sushi bar, where you can enjoy fresh sashimi, perfectly rolled sushi, and hot bowls of ramen.</li>



<li>Explore the rich and exotic spices of Morocco at the cozy Moroccan restaurant, where you can savor aromatic tagines, fluffy couscous and sweet pastries.</li>
</ul>



<p>Embark on a culinary journey and let your taste buds travel the world, right here in Valencia.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Fusion of cultural tastes</h3>



<p>Immerse yourself in a charming fusion of cultural flavors at the best restaurants near the City of Arts and Sciences in Valencia, Spain. As you embark on a gastronomic exploration, you will encounter a symphony of international flavors that will delight your palate and transport you to different corners of the world.</p>



<p>Valencia&#039;s vibrant food scene embraces the concept of cultural fusion, uniting diverse culinary traditions to create unique and unforgettable culinary experiences. From Spanish-Mexican fusion to Mediterranean-Asian fusion, these innovative restaurants offer a harmonious blend of ingredients and techniques from different cultures.</p>



<p>Enjoy dishes that combine bold Indian spices with fresh Mediterranean seafood or savor the fusion of Japanese and Peruvian cuisine. These best restaurants near the City of Arts and Sciences truly celebrate the art of cultural fusion.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Diverse international menus</h3>



<p>Continue your gastronomic exploration near the City of Arts and Sciences in Valencia, Spain, as you immerse yourself in the diverse international menus offering a variety of irresistible international flavors. Whether you&#039;re vegetarian or vegan, these best places to eat have what you need. Here are the highlights:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Vegetarian options</strong>: From Mediterranean-inspired salads to tasty vegetarian sandwiches, these restaurants offer a wide range of delicious options that will satisfy your vegetarian cravings.</li>



<li><strong>vegan cuisine</strong>: Enjoy the tasty world of vegan cuisine with plant-based dishes that are nutritious and delicious. From vegan sushi to vegan burgers, these places pride themselves on creating innovative and irresistible vegan options.</li>



<li><strong>Global culinary delights</strong>: Experience a culinary journey around the world with international menus showcasing flavors from different regions. From Mexican tacos to Thai curries, these restaurants offer a diverse selection of dishes that will transport your taste buds to distant lands.</li>



<li><strong>Exquisite fusion dishes</strong>: Get ready to tempt your taste buds with fusion dishes that combine the best of different cuisines. From Japanese-Mediterranean fusion to Asian-Latin fusion, these spots offer unique and unforgettable flavor combinations that will leave you craving more.</li>
</ul>



<p>No matter what your food preferences are, these best places to eat near the City of Arts and Sciences in Valencia will satisfy your cravings for diverse international flavors.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Healthy and vegetarian options</h2>



<p>You can find several restaurants near the City of Arts and Sciences in Valencia, Spain, offering a variety of healthy and vegetarian options. Whether you follow a plant-based diet or simply enjoy incorporating more vegetables into your meals, these restaurants have you covered. With their focus on using organic ingredients, you can enjoy delicious food while also prioritizing your health and well-being.</p>



<p>A popular restaurant in the area is Verde Bio, a cozy cafe that specializes in plant-based options. Its menu has a wide variety of dishes made with fresh and locally sourced ingredients. From vibrant salads to nutritious bowls, you&#039;ll find plenty of nutritious options to satisfy your cravings.</p>



<p>Another great option is La Tastaolletes, a vegetarian restaurant known for its creative and tasty dishes. They pride themselves on using organic products to create innovative and delicious meals that satisfy both vegetarians and vegans.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Seafood specialties</h2>



<p>Enjoy delicious seafood specialties offered by restaurants near the City of Arts and Sciences in Valencia, Spain. Valencia is known for its fresh and tasty seafood, and the restaurants in this area are no exception.</p>



<p>Here are four seafood delicacies you must try:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Grilled Octopus: Tender and juicy, grilled octopus is a true treat for seafood lovers. The smoky flavors and tender texture make it a popular choice in many restaurants near the City of Arts and Sciences.</li>



<li>Seafood paella: This traditional Valencian dish is a seafood lover&#039;s dream. Packed with mussels, clams, shrimp, and squid, the seafood paella showcases the best of Valencia&#039;s seafood.</li>



<li>Seafood Markets: Visit the bustling seafood markets near the City of Arts and Sciences to experience the vibrant atmosphere and purchase the freshest catch of the day.</li>



<li>Seafood Festivals: Valencia hosts several seafood festivals throughout the year, where you can enjoy a variety of seafood dishes while enjoying live music and entertainment.</li>
</ul>



<p>With these tempting options, seafood enthusiasts will find themselves in seafood heaven in Valencia.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Local tapas bars</h2>



<p>Are you looking for the best tapas in Valencia? Do not look any further! Valencia is home to some hidden tapas bars that are sure to delight your taste buds.</p>



<p>From traditional Spanish flavors to innovative creations, these local tapas bars offer a wide variety of small plates that showcase the city&#039;s vibrant culinary scene.</p>



<p>Get ready to enjoy a gastronomic adventure like no other!</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Best tapas in Valencia</h3>



<p>Discover the tantalizing flavors of Valencia&#039;s local tapas bars near the City of Arts and Sciences. Immerse yourself in the vibrant culinary scene and enjoy the best tapas the city has to offer. Here are some top recommendations for unique tapas that showcase traditional recipes:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>The Pilareta</strong>: This iconic tapas bar is known for its delicious &#039;esgarraet&#039;, a dish made with roasted peppers and salt-cured cod.</li>



<li><strong>Mountain House</strong>: Delve into the history of this centuries-old tavern and savor its famous &#039;patatas bravas&#039;, crispy potatoes served with a spicy tomato sauce.</li>



<li><strong>The Rall</strong>: Experience the fusion of traditional and modern flavors with their innovative &#039;prawn bikini&#039;, a sandwich filled with prawns and melted cheese.</li>



<li><strong>The Gourmet Tavern</strong>: Let yourself be surprised by their &#039;tuna tartare&#039;, a delicate tuna tartare that perfectly balances flavors and textures.</li>
</ul>



<p>Embark on a tapas adventure and let your taste buds rejoice in the freedom of exploring Valencia&#039;s culinary treasures.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Hidden gem tapas.</h3>



<p>You can continue your tapas adventure near the City of Arts and Sciences in Valencia by discovering hidden gem tapas bars that offer unique and delicious culinary experiences. These local tapas bars pride themselves on using authentic recipes and local ingredients, ensuring you can taste the true flavors of Valencia.</p>



<p>Delve into these hidden treasures and be greeted by the warm, lively atmosphere that locals love. Each bite of the tapas will transport you to a world of bold and vibrant flavors. From crispy croquettes filled with creamy béchamel sauce to succulent patatas bravas with spicy aioli, each dish is a work of art.</p>



<p>Join the locals as they gather around the bar, sipping glasses of vermouth and sharing stories about delicious tapas dishes. These hidden gem tapas bars are a true treasure waiting to be discovered.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Frequent questions</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Are there any restaurants near the City of Arts and Sciences that offer vegan or vegetarian options?</h3>



<p>Looking for the best vegan and vegetarian restaurants near the City of Arts and Sciences in Valencia? You&#039;re lucky! There are several healthy food options that offer delicious plant-based dishes.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Which tapas bars near the City of Arts and Sciences are known for their authentic Spanish dishes?</h3>



<p>Popular tapas bars near the City of Arts and Sciences in Valencia, Spain, offer a variety of traditional Spanish dishes that you must try. Enjoy the authentic flavors of Spain while enjoying the vibrant atmosphere of these gastronomic venues.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Can you recommend fine dining options near the City of Arts and Sciences that accommodate special dietary restrictions, such as gluten-free or lactose-free?</h3>



<p>Looking for the best restaurants near the City of Arts and Sciences in Valencia, Spain? You&#039;ll be happy to know that there are fine dining options available that accommodate special dietary restrictions such as gluten-free or lactose-free.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Are there any restaurants near the City of Arts and Sciences that specialize in seafood and offer a wide selection of fresh fish?</h3>



<p>Looking for seafood restaurants near the City of Arts and Sciences in Valencia, Spain? You&#039;re lucky! There are many establishments that specialize in fresh seafood and offer a wide selection.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Do any of the casual dining options near the City of Arts and Sciences offer international cuisine, such as Italian or Asian dishes?</h3>



<p>Are there any casual dining options near the City of Arts and Sciences that offer international cuisine such as Italian or Asian dishes? Do any of these restaurants combine different international flavors to create fusion cuisine?</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h2>



<p>As you explore the vibrant city of Valencia, don&#039;t miss the culinary delights near the City of Arts and Sciences.</p>



<p>From casual dining options to fine dining experiences, from traditional Spanish cuisine to international flavours, and from healthy and vegetarian choices to seafood specialties, there is something for everyone.</p>



<p>So, let your taste buds fly and embark on a gastronomic adventure that will leave you wanting more. Remember, food is the spice of life, so let your senses enjoy every bite.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/restaurants-near-the-city-of-arts-and-sciences/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ideas for a Bachelorette Party in Valencia</title>
		<link>/en/bachelorette-party-valencia/</link>
					<comments>/en/bachelorette-party-valencia/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 09:34:10 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Valencia, Spain]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=59</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[¿Y si cambiamos el rebujito por la paella? Una despedida con nuestras amigas de toda la vida por todo lo alto en la Ciudad de las Artes y las Ciencias (Valencia) ¿quién se apunta? Ha llegado el momento de acercarnos a la playa y a un clima totalmente mediterráneo. Y ¿por qué no? De organizar...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What if we change the rebujito for paella? A farewell with our lifelong friends in style in the City of Arts and Sciences (<strong>Valencia</strong>) who&#039;s signing up? The time has come to get closer to the beach and a totally Mediterranean climate. And why not? To organize a<strong>&nbsp;bachelorette party in Valencia</strong>! Furthermore, if we see that we are short of imagination we can always review these&nbsp;<strong>ideas for a bachelorette party in Valencia</strong>&nbsp;and let&#039;s see if the light bulb lights up!</p>



<p>And since surprises must be in order, what do you think if we review these&nbsp;<a href="/en/bachelorette-party-ideas/" target="_blank" data-type="link" data-id="/ideas-para-despedida-de-soltera/" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>10 original ideas for a bachelorette party</strong></a>?</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Boat tour&nbsp;</h2>



<p>What do we see that both the bride and we want a more aquatic party? So, our tailored plan to celebrate the end of being single is a&nbsp;<strong>Boat tour.&nbsp;</strong>The best way to welcome the arrival of good weather, what do you think? Without a doubt, the bride will adore us and we will not forget this day. A little cava or champagne, sunbathe, try the best food on board and why not? A little adventure, launching into the sea! And if we want the spiciest point, then a stripper on board cannot be missing!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Karts</h2>



<p>From raising the flag on the high seas to docking and approaching the beach, in one jump! In Valencia all this and much more is possible! Who&#039;s going to put the pedal to the metal?<strong>&nbsp;kart in a group race</strong>?<br>You will see in its purest form the most competitive part of some of your friends and also the most cautious part of others... pure spectacle!<br>If you like strong emotions, this is a way to go from 0 to 100 😀</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Dance studio</h2>



<p>That we are more dancers and we dance to any type of music they play for us? So, our best plan for a bachelorette party is a<strong>dance studio</strong>! For an hour and a half we will be moving our hips to the rhythm of the best oriental or Tahitian music (depending on what we feel like). And there will be no excuse not to go out and give it your all.&nbsp;<a href="/en/best-nightclubs-valencia/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>the best clubs in Valencia</strong></a>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Pole Dance</h2>



<p>And if you like different and risky things more than exotic things, we changed the oriental or Tahitian dance workshop that we mentioned before for spins and pirouettes on the pole. Just as it sounds! The latest fashion in farewells to try the&nbsp;<strong>pole dance</strong>.<br>Although at first it may seem a little strange... you will see that in a matter of minutes you already control basic turns. Once you learn the steps, it is time to create a choreography. Ready?</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">dinner night</h2>



<p>A more comical night? Or a spicier night? How do we prefer it to be ours?&nbsp;<strong>dinner with show</strong>? The perfect combination of good food, some beers, an unforgettable show and ending up giving it your all at a nightclub. Never has a dinner been so unforgettable, different and original! Furthermore, if we want to keep the bride blushing all night, we can always add some costumes, a private room or venue and organize it to the bride&#039;s liking!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">beauty party</h2>



<p>Manicure, pedicure, a little makeup... and toast with a glass of champagne. Getting away from the busy work life has never been better! Furthermore, both the bride and we deserve to pamper ourselves a little (quite a bit) from time to time and that is why, and because feeling Carrie Bradshaw is unbeatable, that a&nbsp;<strong>beauty party</strong>&nbsp;It is one of the best options for a farewell party!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Catamaran party</h2>



<p>Aquatic plans are the order of the day! And if it is one&nbsp;<strong>catamaran party</strong>&nbsp;with food along the coast of Valencia is a real joy! Music, catering and drinks, the best choice to celebrate a farewell, get tanned and welcome the summer as you deserve it! And to keep things going, we will have a DJ who will entertain and encourage us throughout the day.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Photoshoot</h2>



<p>Stolen and posed! You were clear that when one of your friends got married, the farewell would be epic, so... what better than being the focus of all the flashes 🙂<br>Prepare your best outfits because we are going to do one of the most trendy activities... A professional photographer will take the best photos of you in the best-known places in Valencia but also in the most secret ones!<br>The&nbsp;<strong>Photo sessions</strong>&nbsp;They are increasingly in demand at farewell parties... because... how long has it been since you took quality photos with your best friends? Who can say no to a plan like that?</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">private sailboat</h2>



<p>We recognize it! We love the&nbsp;<strong>private sailboats</strong>. Go out, sail, swim, eat while looking at the coast and try a little snorkeling... Sailboats have a multitude of opportunities.<br>It is a perfect way to get away from the busy beaches and anchor in impressive coves that are impossible to reach except by boat.<br>Sun, music, sea and good company. Can you really miss a farewell?</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Private spa</h2>



<p>The best remedy for nights of debauchery, without a doubt! Because what better idea than to relax in a jacuzzi, enjoy a massage or take advantage and have a slightly more special treatment to return home like a rose.<br>An intimate place for you to have a post-farewell gathering. How many new anecdotes will come out of this private spa?</p>



<p>Other ideas for bachelorette parties at:</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><a href="/en/bachelorette-party-madrid/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Madrid</a></li>



<li><a href="/en/bachelorette-party-barcelona/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Barcelona</a></li>



<li><a href="/en/bachelorette-party-in-ibiza/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Ibiza</a></li>



<li><a href="/en/bachelorette-party-malaga/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Malaga</a></li>



<li><a href="/en/bachelorette-party-seville/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Seville</a></li>



<li><a href="/en/bachelorette-party-bilbao/" target="_blank" data-type="link" data-id="/despedida-de-soltera-bilbao/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Bilbao</a></li>



<li><a href="/en/bachelorette-party-in-las-palmas-de-gran-canaria/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Gran Canaria</a></li>



<li><a href="/en/majorca-bachelorette-party/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Majorca</a></li>



<li><a href="/en/bachelorette-party-alicante/">Alicante</a></li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/bachelorette-party-valencia/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>