<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>Lyon Parks &#8211; The Fun Plan</title>
	<atom:link href="/en/tag/lyon-parks/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/en</link>
	<description>Crafting Moments, Creating Memories: Your Guide to Flawless Events.</description>
	<lastbuilddate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 09:06:02 +0000</lastbuilddate>
	<language>in-GB</language>
	<sy:updateperiod>
	hourly	</sy:updateperiod>
	<sy:updatefrequency>
	1	</sy:updatefrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/09/favi.png</url>
	<title>Lyon Parks &#8211; The Fun Plan</title>
	<link>/en</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>6 hidden gems for the perfect picnic in the parks of Lyon</title>
		<link>/en/picnic-spots-in-lyon-parks/</link>
					<comments>/en/picnic-spots-in-lyon-parks/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Sat, 14 Oct 2023 03:31:48 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lyon, France]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lyon Parks]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=1294</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[¿Buscando la escapada definitiva del ajetreo y bullicio de Lyon? Descubre seis joyas escondidas que satisfarán tu ansia de libertad. Imagínate descansando en un tranquilo rincón junto al río o disfrutando de la tranquilidad de un oasis escondido. Sumérgete en las impresionantes vistas de un prado idílico o encuentra consuelo en un refugio apartado en...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Looking for the ultimate escape from the hustle and bustle of Lyon? Discover six hidden gems that will satisfy your desire for freedom.</p>



<p>Imagine relaxing in a quiet corner by the river or enjoying the tranquility of a hidden oasis. Soak in the stunning views of an idyllic meadow or find solace in a secluded retreat amidst nature.</p>



<p>With historic charm and romantic appeal, these hidden picnic spots are waiting to be explored.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Main points to take into account</h2>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li>Parc de la Feyssine – a hidden oasis with lush greenery, perfect for a serene and tranquil picnic experience.</li>



<li>Vieux Lyon – a UNESCO World Heritage Site with Renaissance buildings, offering a historic and picturesque spot for a picnic.</li>



<li>Parc de la Tête d&#039;Or – A beautiful park with picturesque views of the lake, ideal for a scenic and romantic picnic.</li>



<li>Fourvière Hill – A hill with panoramic views of the city and the Basilica of Notre-Dame de Fourvière, offering a historic and picturesque spot for a picnic.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Quiet picnic spot by the river</h2>



<p>For a quiet picnic experience, you can often find yourself enjoying a quiet riverside spot in Lyon&#039;s parks. Imagine this: a gentle breeze rustles the leaves of the trees around you, the sound of rushing river water calms your senses, and warm sunlight filters through the branches, creating a tranquil atmosphere.</p>



<p>This riverside picnic spot offers the perfect escape from the hustle and bustle of the city. As you lay your blanket on the grassy shore, you can&#039;t help but feel a sense of freedom and relaxation. The gentle flow of the river adds a relaxing soundtrack to your meal, as you feast on delicious food and soak up the beauty of nature around you.</p>



<p>It is the ideal place to relax, reconnect and enjoy a quiet picnic in the parks of Lyon.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Quiet oasis in the heart of Lyon</h2>



<p>Looking to escape the hustle and bustle of the city? Lyon offers some hidden gems that serve as quiet oases in the heart of the city.</p>



<p>These best picnic spots are perfect for a quiet afternoon surrounded by nature. With park amenities and local food options nearby, you can relax and enjoy a delicious picnic amidst Lyon&#039;s vibrant atmosphere.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Best picnic spots</h3>



<p>Discover five quiet places for a picnic in the heart of Lyon.</p>



<p>When it comes to finding the perfect picnic spot, Lyon offers a multitude of secluded retreats that will transport you to a world of serenity. Whether you&#039;re looking for a quiet getaway or a romantic date, these hidden gems will satisfy all your picnic needs.</p>



<p>Start your adventure at Parc de la Tête d&#039;Or, a sprawling park with lush vegetation and a tranquil lake.</p>



<p>Next, head to the Jardin des Chartreux, a beautiful garden hidden in the heart of the city.</p>



<p>For a stunning view, head to Fourvière Hill and find a spot overlooking the city.</p>



<p>Les Berges du Rhône and Parc de Gerland are perfect for those looking for a riverside picnic experience.</p>



<p>Don&#039;t forget to pack your picnic essentials and immerse yourself in these tranquil picnic oases in Lyon.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">park services</h3>



<p>As you explore these peaceful picnic spots in Lyon, you&#039;ll delight in the park&#039;s amenities that enhance your picnic experience. Here are four picnic essentials you can enjoy while taking in the beauty of Lyon&#039;s parks:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li>Picnic tables: Many parks in Lyon offer picnic tables for your convenience. Spread your feast and enjoy the delicious food you have prepared.</li>



<li>BBQ Grills: If you&#039;re in the mood for a barbecue, some parks offer designated areas with grills where you can cook to your heart&#039;s content. Bring your favorite meats and vegetables and enjoy a delicious meal outdoors.</li>



<li>Picnic shelters: In case the weather turns bad, don&#039;t worry. Some parks have picnic shelters where you can take shelter and continue enjoying your picnic without interruptions.</li>



<li>Picnic Games: Make your picnic even more fun by bringing some games. Whether it&#039;s a game of Frisbee, a friendly game of soccer, or a classic card game, these games will add an extra dose of excitement to your outing.</li>
</ol>



<p>With these park amenities, your picnic in Lyon will be truly unforgettable. So grab your picnic essentials and head to one of these hidden gems in Lyon&#039;s parks for an enjoyable, relaxing day.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Local food options</h3>



<p>Enjoy the local food options available in Lyon&#039;s quiet park oases to enhance your picnic experience.</p>



<p>Lyon is known as the gastronomic capital of France, and its parks offer a variety of delights to satisfy your palate.</p>



<p>Start your picnic with a selection of regional cheeses, such as creamy Brie or tangy Roquefort, accompanied by a crusty baguette. For a heartier option, try traditional Lyonnaise sausage, served with Dijon mustard.</p>



<p>Don&#039;t forget to try the local charcuterie, including cured meats and pâté. To add a touch of sweetness to your picnic, enjoy some local pastries such as the famous praline cake or a delicate macaron.</p>



<p>For a refreshing drink, opt for a glass of local Beaujolais wine or a refreshing glass of pink lemonade.</p>



<p>These local food options will elevate your picnic in Lyon&#039;s tranquil park oases to a new level of culinary delight.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Idyllic meadow with stunning views</h2>



<p>You can find an idyllic meadow with stunning views in the parks of Lyon. Imagine relaxing on a soft blanket, surrounded by vibrant flowers and the soft rustle of tall grass. Here, the beauty of nature unfolds before your eyes, offering a feeling of peace and tranquility. Allow yourself to be captivated by the stunning views that stretch before you, as if painted by an artist&#039;s brush. This meadow provides the perfect backdrop for a picnic and soaking in the beauty of Lyon&#039;s parks.</p>



<p>Here are four reasons why this idyllic meadow is a must-see:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li>Panoramic views: The meadow offers panoramic views of the Lyon landscape, showcasing the city&#039;s charm and natural splendor.</li>



<li>Serene Environment: The peaceful atmosphere of the meadow allows you to escape the bustle of city life and embrace a sense of freedom.</li>



<li>Abundant wildlife: Keep your eyes open to see butterflies fluttering and birds flying overhead, adding to the enchanting atmosphere.</li>



<li>Perfect for relaxing: Lie back and enjoy the sun, read a book or simply appreciate the beauty of your surroundings. This meadow is a refuge for those seeking solace.</li>
</ol>



<p>Head to the parks of Lyon and discover this hidden gem for yourself. Let the idyllic meadow and its stunning views inspire your sense of freedom and joy.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Secluded Picnic Shelter in the Middle of Nature</h2>



<p>Escape the bustling city and immerse yourself in the tranquil beauty of Lyon&#039;s secluded picnic spots, surrounded by nature.</p>



<p>These peaceful picnic spots offer a peaceful haven where you can relax and unwind surrounded by the calming sounds of chirping birds and rustling leaves.</p>



<p>Discover nature&#039;s hidden gems and make lasting memories at these peaceful picnic hideaways.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Quiet places to have a picnic.</h3>



<p>Discover peaceful picnic spots nestled in the natural beauty of Lyon&#039;s parks. Escape the bustle of the city and find your own secluded retreat to enjoy a quiet meal in nature.</p>



<p>Here are four serene picnic spots that will transport you to a world of serenity and freedom:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Jardin de la Grande Côte</strong>: This peaceful garden is a hidden gem, with its colorful flowers, shady trees and quiet corners. Find a cozy spot under a flowering tree and enjoy the tranquility.</li>



<li><strong>Parc de la Tête d&#039;Or</strong>: Head to the picturesque lakefront in this spacious park. Spread your picnic blanket next to the sparkling water and enjoy the soothing sounds of ducks swimming and birds singing.</li>



<li><strong>Gerland Park</strong>: This park offers a serene setting along the banks of the Rhône River. Set up your picnic near the river and watch the sun set over the water, creating a golden glow around you.</li>



<li><strong>Parc de la Feyssine</strong>: Escape to this hidden oasis, located just outside the city center. Enjoy a picnic surrounded by lush greenery and the serene presence of Lake Feyssine.</li>
</ol>



<p>Relax, unwind and embrace the freedom of nature at these serene picnic spots in Lyon&#039;s parks.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Quiet shelters for picnics in nature.</h3>



<p>Find your own secluded retreat amidst the natural beauty of Lyon&#039;s parks for a peaceful picnic experience.</p>



<p>As you stroll through the parks, keep your eyes open for hidden picnic spots where you can escape the hustle and bustle of the city and find peace in nature.</p>



<p>One such place is located along the riverbank in the Parc de la Tête d&#039;Or, where the sound of flowing water and singing birds create a symphony of serenity.</p>



<p>Another peaceful picnic setting is found at Parc de Gerland, where shady woods offer a respite from the sun and a sense of seclusion.</p>



<p>To find a true hidden gem, head to Parc de la Feyssine, a sprawling nature reserve with secluded glades and winding trails leading to unspoiled picnic spots.</p>



<p>Take advantage of the freedom that nature offers and create your own peaceful retreat for the perfect picnic experience.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Charming picnic spot with historic charm</h2>



<p>You can enjoy a delicious picnic in the parks of Lyon while soaking in the historical charm of a charming picnic spot. Lyon is known for its rich history and cultural significance, and there are several picnic spots that allow you to experience it firsthand. Here are four historic picnic spots in Lyon that will transport you back in time:</p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li>Parc de la Tête d&#039;Or: This sprawling park is not only home to beautiful gardens and a tranquil lake, but is also home to the historic Rose Garden, where you can relax and enjoy a picnic surrounded by fragrant flowers.</li>



<li>Fourvière Hill: Take a short hike up Fourvière Hill and you&#039;ll find yourself in a picturesque setting with panoramic views of the city. This historic site is also home to the Basilica of Notre-Dame de Fourvière, adding a touch of grandeur to your picnic experience.</li>



<li>Place des Terreaux: Located in the heart of Lyon, this historic square is surrounded by stunning architecture, including the Town Hall and the Museum of Fine Arts. Place your picnic blanket here and enjoy the atmosphere of a centuries-old history.</li>



<li>Vieux Lyon: Explore the narrow cobblestone streets of Vieux Lyon, a UNESCO World Heritage Site, and find a cozy corner to enjoy your picnic. This area is filled with Renaissance buildings and hidden courtyards, providing a unique historical backdrop for your outdoor meal.</li>
</ol>



<p>Immerse yourself in the history of Lyon while enjoying a delicious picnic in these charming places.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Hidden gem for a romantic picnic getaway.</h2>



<p>Enjoy an intimate picnic experience in the middle of Lyon&#039;s parks, where serenity and romance intertwine.</p>



<p>To discover a hidden gem that promises a truly romantic getaway, head to Parc de la Tête d&#039;Or. This charming park offers a tranquil setting with its lush greenery, a tranquil lake and a picturesque rose garden. Place your picnic blanket in the shade of a tree and enjoy the peaceful atmosphere.</p>



<p>To make your romantic picnic even more memorable, consider some creative picnic ideas. Pack a bottle of champagne or your favorite sparkling wine, along with gourmet cheeses, fresh fruits, and a selection of decadent chocolates. Don&#039;t forget to bring a Bluetooth speaker to enjoy soft music in the background.</p>



<p>With these essential items in your picnic basket, you are sure to create a romantic and unforgettable experience in the parks of Lyon.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Frequent questions</h2>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Are there any picnic spots suitable for large groups or family gatherings?</h3>



<p>Looking for picnic spots for large groups or family gatherings? You&#039;re lucky! Lyon&#039;s parks offer many hidden gems where you can enjoy picnic activities and try delicious picnic food ideas.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Can I bring my own grill or barbecue equipment to these picnic spots?</h3>



<p>You can bring your own grill or barbecue equipment to these picnic spots, but be aware of grilling regulations and safety precautions. Make sure you follow the rules and take necessary steps to ensure everyone&#039;s safety.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Are there any restrictions on alcohol consumption in the picnic areas?</h3>



<p>Yes, you can enjoy a glass of wine or a cold beer at the best picnic spots in Lyon&#039;s parks. There are no restrictions on alcohol consumption, so you can relax and enjoy your picnic experience.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Is parking available near these hidden picnic spots?</h3>



<p>Looking for the perfect picnic spot in the parks of Lyon? Do you want to know if parking is available? You&#039;ll be happy to know that there is parking near these hidden gems, making them ideal for a day of relaxation.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Are pets allowed in these picnic areas?</h3>



<p>Pets are welcome at these hidden picnic spots! As you explore Lyon&#039;s parks, don&#039;t forget to bring your furry friend. Just be sure to follow the picnic rules and regulations to ensure freedom and enjoyment for everyone.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h2>



<p>So pack your picnic basket and venture into the hidden treasures of Lyon&#039;s parks. These serene and calm places are like oases in the middle of the hustle and bustle of the city. With stunning views, historic charm, and romantic getaways, they give you the opportunity to connect with nature and create unforgettable memories. Let these hidden treasures be your secret hideaways, where the simple act of having a picnic becomes a metaphorical journey of discovery and renewal.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/picnic-spots-in-lyon-parks/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>