<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" >

<channel>
	<title>Blog – The Fun Plan</title>
	<atom:link href="/en/destinations/blog/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/en</link>
	<description>Crafting Moments, Creating Memories: Your Guide to Flawless Events.</description>
	<lastbuilddate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 11:35:59 +0000</lastbuilddate>
	<language>in-GB</language>
	<sy:updateperiod>
	hourly	</sy:updateperiod>
	<sy:updatefrequency>
	1	</sy:updatefrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.1</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/09/favi.png</url>
	<title>Blog – The Fun Plan</title>
	<link>/en</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Annual San Fermin Festival in Pamplona</title>
		<link>/en/annual-san-fermin-festival-in-pamplona/</link>
					<comments>/en/annual-san-fermin-festival-in-pamplona/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 11:29:53 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=2635</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Este sábado día 6 dan comienzo los Sanfermines 2023, con&#160;el chupinazo&#160;que tendrá lugar a las 12,00h en la Plaza Consistorial de Pamplona. La fiesta debe su nombre Fermín de Amiens, nacido en Pompaelo (la actual&#160;Pamplona) que fue misionero cristiano, primer obispo&#160;de Amiens(cuya iglesia mandó construir) y fue decapitado a los 31 años de edad. Una...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This Saturday the 6th, the Sanfermines 2023 begins, with&nbsp;<strong>the &quot;chupinazo</strong>&nbsp;which will take place at 12:00 p.m. in the Plaza Consistorial of Pamplona.</p>



<p>The festival is named after Fermín de Amiens, born in Pompaelo (present-day Pamplona) who was a Christian missionary, first bishop of Amiens (whose church he ordered to be built) and was beheaded at the age of 31. A mistaken belief is to think that San Fermín is the patron saint of Pamplona exclusively, when he is the patron saint of all of Navarra.</p>



<p>The celebrations begin with the launching of the chupinazo and end at midnight on July 14 with the&nbsp;<strong>farewell song “Poor me”.</strong></p>



<p>The most famous activities of San Fermines are&nbsp;<strong>the confinements,</strong>&nbsp;which consist of an 849m route in front of the bulls that ends in the bullring. They take place every day between July 7 and 14 at 8:00 a.m., with an average duration of two to three minutes.</p>



<p>The Sanfermines have an origin that dates back to the Middle Ages, although their worldwide fame is a recent phenomenon, also linked to the dissemination that Ernest Hemingway gave them through his book “Fiesta”.</p>



<p>Three independent celebrations take place during these days in which the population of Pamplona goes from 190,000 inhabitants to more than 1,000,000 people:</p>



<p>* Religious acts in honor of San Fermín</p>



<p>* Trade fairs</p>



<p>* Bullfights</p>



<p>This year, the SanFermines will have 437 events that you can see in detail in this&nbsp;<a href="https://sanferminespamplona.es/" target="_blank" data-type="link" data-id="https://sanferminespamplona.es/" rel="noreferrer noopener">Web page</a>.</p>



<p>Do you dare to go to&nbsp;<a href="/en/journey/" target="_blank" data-type="page" data-id="815" rel="noreferrer noopener">the confinements</a>&nbsp;of San Fermin? If the answer is yes, here are some&nbsp;<a href="https://www.sanfermin.com/es/" target="_blank" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.sanfermin.com/es/" rel="noreferrer noopener">tips</a>&nbsp; to be able to enjoy the party without suffering any altercations 😉</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/annual-san-fermin-festival-in-pamplona/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Requirements for traveling with minors</title>
		<link>/en/requirements-for-traveling-with-minors/</link>
					<comments>/en/requirements-for-traveling-with-minors/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Sat, 28 Oct 2023 10:37:58 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=2613</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Estamos acostumbrados a viajar solos, con grupos de amigos, pero ¿y con niños? En The Fun Plan sabemos lo estresante que puede llegar a ser planificar un viaje con menores de edad y por ello te queremos echar un cable. Si estás organizando un&#160;viaje escolar con tus alumnos&#160;o por el contrario es un viaje familiar...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are used to traveling alone, with groups of friends, but what about with children? At The Fun Plan we know how stressful it can be to plan a trip with minors and that&#039;s why we want to help you out.</p>



<p>If you are organizing a&nbsp;<a href="/en/journey/" target="_blank" data-type="page" data-id="815" rel="noreferrer noopener">school trip with your students</a>&nbsp;or on the contrary, it is a family trip, it is normal for certain doubts to arise, such as: What documentation does the minor need? What things can&#039;t I forget? Below we provide you with all the information about the&nbsp;<strong>requirements for traveling with minors</strong>&nbsp;in Spain or abroad, and the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.aena.es/es/pasajeros/documentacion-visados/documentacion-para-viajar.html" target="_blank" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.aena.es/es/pasajeros/documentacion-visados/documentacion-para-viajar.html" rel="noreferrer noopener">travel documentation</a>&nbsp;essential that you should not forget.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Travel within Spain and the EU</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>Although the DNI is not mandatory until they are 14 years of age, minors can obtain the National Identity Document from the moment they are born, as long as one of the parents accompanies them to the corresponding office to pay the fees.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Minors under 14 years of age may fly only within national territory without ID as long as they are accompanied by their parents and they carry the Family Book with them. If flying outside of Spain, minors will need a DNI for the countries of the European Union and a Passport for the rest of the countries that do not belong to the EU.</p>



<p>Minors under 14 years of age may not travel alone in any case, however, those between 14 and 16 years of age may travel alone by hiring assistance at the airport. This assistance means that the minor will be accompanied at all times.&nbsp;<strong>From the age of 16, minors may travel alone</strong>, as long as they have authorization from their parents to travel, which must be formalized in writing at any Civil Guard post.</p>



<p>It is recommended to travel within the EU&nbsp;<a href="https://sede.seg-social.gob.es/wps/portal/sede/sede/Ciudadanos" target="_blank" data-type="link" data-id="https://sede.seg-social.gob.es/wps/portal/sede/sede/Ciudadanos" rel="noreferrer noopener">European sanitary card</a>. This document certifies the right of its holder to receive health benefits in the Member States of the European Union, in the rest of the countries of the European Economic Area and in Switzerland. It is valid for one year, and can be processed online or at a Social Security office.</p>



<p>If you need to travel with medications, there is nothing to worry about! Liquid medications are exempt from liquid transportation restrictions. The regulations allow you to travel from any airport in the European Union with medications. It is recommended to always carry them in your hand luggage and accompanied by your prescription or the corresponding medical prescription.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">Traveling abroad outside the EU</h3>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>Travel by and with minors is subject to specific restrictions. The border police, both inside and outside the Schengen area, have the specific mandate to pay special attention to minors, whether they are traveling accompanied or not, they will need the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.exteriores.gob.es/es/Paginas/index.aspx" target="_blank" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.exteriores.gob.es/es/Paginas/index.aspx" rel="noreferrer noopener">authorization for minors to travel abroad</a>.</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Those minors traveling outside EU countries will need to present their Passport to border agents. For&nbsp;<a href="https://www.policia.es/_es/index.php" target="_blank" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.policia.es/_es/index.php" rel="noreferrer noopener">apply for the passport</a>&nbsp;The same procedure is required as for the DNI, with the difference that the minor&nbsp;<strong>must be accompanied by both parents or, failing that, by their legal guardians</strong>.</p>



<p>If there is only one parent or guardian, this must be justified through sentences, birth certificates, death certificates or any other document in which it is stated and can be demonstrated that only one exists.</p>



<p>Furthermore, when we plan to travel to other countries, we must know if the destination country requires any type of&nbsp;<strong>Visa or Health Certificate</strong>. If this is the case, you must consult the embassy of the destination country about the requirements to request it. Each country imposes its conditions and price of issuance fees, as well as some allow the obtaining of group or family visas.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong><em>Minors traveling alone</em></strong></li>
</ul>



<p>Those minors traveling alone must justify to border agents that they do not leave the national territory against the will of their parents or legal guardians.</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong><em>Minors traveling accompanied</em></strong></li>
</ul>



<p>In the event that minors travel accompanied, the requirements and necessary documentation to present at the customs of the destination country will depend on:</p>



<p><em>–&nbsp;<strong>If you travel accompanied by 1 of your parents</strong>:&nbsp;</em>They must request the express authorization of the other absent parent or legal guardian. If there is no other, it will be useful to have documents such as judgments, birth certificates or death certificates to prove that only one exists.</p>



<p>–<em><strong>If the minor&#039;s parents are divorced&nbsp;</strong></em></p>



<ol class="wp-block-list">
<li>The divorce decree must be reviewed and ensure that it allows traveling abroad with the minor.</li>



<li>Present authorization from the other parent or legal guardian giving their consent.</li>



<li>If one of the parties objects to the minor traveling outside the country, a lawyer will have to be consulted, thus requesting judicial authorization. It is advisable to add the minor&#039;s round-trip plane tickets to this application.</li>
</ol>



<p><em>–&nbsp;<strong>If you travel accompanied by adults who are not your parents</strong>:&nbsp;</em>They will need to justify to border agents that custody of the minor has not been unlawfully deprived. To do this, an authorization must be formalized in writing, which must be requested at a Civil Guard office.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/requirements-for-traveling-with-minors/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Havana in one day</title>
		<link>/en/havana-in-one-day/</link>
					<comments>/en/havana-in-one-day/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 05:43:13 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=1603</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[La Habana, ese destino soñado por muchos y que puede ser posible con The Fun Plan. La&#160;capital de Cuba&#160;y su centro político y financiero es uno de los&#160;imprescindibles&#160;en un viaje por el país del&#160;Caribe, aunque a veces puede ser que el tiempo para recorrer sus calles sea limitado. Es por ello que os traemos una...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Havana</strong>, that destination dreamed of by many and that can be possible with The Fun Plan. The&nbsp;<strong>capital of cuba</strong>&nbsp;and its political and financial center is one of the&nbsp;<strong>essential</strong>&nbsp;on a trip through the country of&nbsp;<strong>Caribbean</strong>, although sometimes the time to explore its streets may be limited. That is why we bring you a series of&nbsp;<strong>recommendations</strong>&nbsp;for&nbsp;<a href="/en/journey/" target="_blank" data-type="page" data-id="815" rel="noreferrer noopener">visit&nbsp;<strong>Havana in one day</strong></a>&nbsp;and not miss the&nbsp;<strong>most emblematic places</strong>. Shall we begin?</p>



<p><strong>Recommended Tours</strong></p>



<div data-gyg-href="https://widget.getyourguide.com/default/activities.frame" data-gyg-locale-code="es-ES" data-gyg-widget="activities" data-gyg-number-of-items="2" data-gyg-cmp="titanic_belfast_post" data-gyg-partner-id="0IM174M" data-gyg-q="havana%20cuba"></div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">In the morning</h2>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img  fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="599" height="337"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/1-calles-habana-e1475145310552.jpg"  alt="Havana Streets" class="wp-image-1626" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/1-calles-habana-e1475145310552.jpg 599w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/1-calles-habana-e1475145310552-300x169.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/1-calles-habana-e1475145310552-18x10.jpg 18w" sizes="(max-width: 599px) 100vw, 599px" /></figure></div>


<p>He&nbsp;<strong>historic helmet</strong>&nbsp;of the city is reduced to 4 square kilometers of special corners, museums,&nbsp;<strong>monuments</strong>&nbsp;and charming streets that will make you fall in love without a doubt. However, if you only have one day to visit, it is recommended&nbsp;<strong>organize a route</strong>&nbsp;with the most important places since seeing everything will be practically impossible. Starting with the&nbsp;<strong>mythical neighborhood of Old Havana</strong>, the most restored area, you can have a coffee in the well-known&nbsp;<strong>Artists Cafe</strong>&nbsp;to gain strength and mark the points you want to see. In this sense, you can visit the famous&nbsp;<strong>Cathedral Square</strong>, the&nbsp;<strong>Main Square</strong>, that of&nbsp;<strong>San Francisco</strong>&nbsp;and the&nbsp;<strong>Old Square</strong>. And it is that walking during the day through its&nbsp;<strong>four colonial squares</strong>, connected to each other by narrow streets and charming cobblestones, is priceless.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Where to eat</h2>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img  decoding="async" width="599" height="471"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/dsc04026-e1475145284251.jpg"  alt="" class="wp-image-1627" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/dsc04026-e1475145284251.jpg 599w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/dsc04026-e1475145284251-300x236.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/dsc04026-e1475145284251-15x12.jpg 15w" sizes="(max-width: 599px) 100vw, 599px" /></figure></div>


<p>A recommended option is&nbsp;<strong>visit the paladares</strong>, small Cuban restaurants that are spread throughout Havana, such as San Cristóbal. Although the gastronomic offer is not very high, the truth is that the flavor is impressive, so they are worth a visit. Among the typical dishes, you cannot leave Cuba without trying its&nbsp;<strong>Old clothes</strong>, the most representative Cuban dish, as well as the&nbsp;<strong>Moors and Christians</strong>: In this case, the black beans are served with fluffy white rice. Furthermore, for vegetarians the option of&nbsp;<strong>yucca</strong>&nbsp;and a special sauce&nbsp;<strong>mojo</strong>&nbsp;It&#039;s interesting.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">In the afternoon</h2>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img  decoding="async" width="599" height="400"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/El-Malecon-de-La-Habana-e1475145379597.jpg"  alt="" class="wp-image-1629" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/El-Malecon-de-La-Habana-e1475145379597.jpg 599w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/El-Malecon-de-La-Habana-e1475145379597-300x200.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/El-Malecon-de-La-Habana-e1475145379597-18x12.jpg 18w" sizes="(max-width: 599px) 100vw, 599px" /></figure></div>


<p>After leaving Old Havana behind, it is time to approach the&nbsp;<strong>Havana Center</strong>&nbsp;to discover other unique places. Mandatory are the stops in the&nbsp;<strong>University of Havana</strong>&nbsp;and the&nbsp;<strong>Revolution Square</strong>&nbsp;with the famous mural of&nbsp;<strong>Che Guevara</strong>&nbsp;and the&nbsp;<strong>Memorial to José Martí</strong>. However, by speeding up your pace a little you can enter the&nbsp;<strong>National Capitol of Cuba</strong>, one of the most emblematic buildings in the city, very similar to the Washington Capitol. Additionally, you can stop by&nbsp;<strong>Museum of the Revolution</strong>&nbsp;and that of<strong>&nbsp;Fine arts</strong>&nbsp;to admire the&nbsp;<strong>Cuban history and culture</strong>. Towards sunset, it is advisable to walk through the&nbsp;<strong>Pier</strong>&nbsp;to observe one of the best sunsets of your lives. Its almost 8 kilometers in length will seem eternal, but each of its corners will hide a different story.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">At night</h2>



<p>In Cuba there will never be a lack of&nbsp;<strong>party and fun</strong>, so the nightly offering will be very varied. It will not even be necessary to step into a bar, since in many cases&nbsp;<strong>music moves to the streets</strong>&nbsp;through scheduled or improvised concerts. However, some recommended sites are&nbsp;<strong>Tropicana</strong>, an open-air cabaret with Cuban music and lots of color, or<strong>&nbsp;The Turquino</strong>, the best place to wear out our hips dancing salsa all night.</p>



<p>If you are willing to dance salsa and fall in love with Ropa Vieja,&nbsp;<strong>Cuba is waiting for you on the other side of the pond</strong>. What are you waiting for?</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/havana-in-one-day/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What to See in Buenos Aires in One Day</title>
		<link>/en/what-to-see-in-buenos-aires-in-one-day/</link>
					<comments>/en/what-to-see-in-buenos-aires-in-one-day/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 05:42:09 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=1601</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Aprovechando que el año pasado estuve viviendo en Buenos Aires cerca de dos meses y que dos buenos amigos han decidido visitar Argentina en su luna de miel ¡Ana y Juan felicidades! me he puesto a revisar mis anotaciones y fotos. De todo eso parten las siguientes recomendaciones de&#160;qué ver en Buenos Aires en un...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Taking advantage of the fact that last year I was living in Buenos Aires for about two months and that two good friends have decided to visit Argentina on their honeymoon. Ana and Juan, congratulations! I have started to review my notes and photos. The following recommendations are based on all of this:&nbsp;<strong>what to see in Buenos Aires in one day</strong>.</p>



<p><strong>Recommended Tours</strong></p>



<div data-gyg-href="https://widget.getyourguide.com/default/activities.frame" data-gyg-locale-code="es-ES" data-gyg-widget="activities" data-gyg-number-of-items="2" data-gyg-cmp="titanic_belfast_post" data-gyg-partner-id="0IM174M" data-gyg-q="Buenos%20Aires"></div>



<p>Buenos Aires is a city that is too big to be summarized in one day, so the task is complex. A good piece of advice that they gave me (although I didn&#039;t follow it hehe) and that I make applicable is to take (sorry, forbidden word in your Argentine stay; take) the typical tourist bus on the first day. Another great tip to find my way around the city that Fabri, a friend who lived there for two years, gave me is to take into account the online map of Buenos Aires.</p>



<p>To put ourselves in a situation, the city has about 3 million inhabitants and Greater Buenos Aires has about 13 million. The most typical neighborhoods are Palermo, Recoleta, Retiro, Congreso y Tribunales, El Centro, San Telmo, La Boca and Puerto Madero.</p>



<p>Each neighborhood needs more than one day to get to know it, so for this post to be useful to both you and Juan and Ana, I will focus on&nbsp;<strong>what to see in Palermo in one day</strong>&nbsp;and to mention at least one essential site for each of the remaining neighborhoods.</p>



<p>Where to start in Palermo? I would dedicate the morning to visiting MALBA, the Latin American Museum of Buenos Aires, where you can see some of the best works by classical and contemporary Latin American artists. If you haven&#039;t had breakfast, it has a good cafeteria to have a coffee with the delicious Argentine croissants. I would continue the morning with a walk through the Japanese garden. If it&#039;s time for lunch and you like sushi, inside the garden is one of the&nbsp;<strong>best sushi restaurants in Buenos Aires</strong>.</p>



<p>As you already know, for Argentinians the best pizzas are made there. Very close to the Japanese garden is Guido&#039;s Bar, an Italian restaurant with a long history in the city. There you can check if the saying about Argentine pizzas is true. However, since I am more of a meat type, I would go to Don Julio, what a wonderful restaurant! From time to time I dream about their meats and their extraordinary winery.</p>



<p>After lunch is a good time to take a walk to the area of&nbsp;<strong><a href="https://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Palermo_Soho" target="_blank" data-type="link" data-id="https://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Palermo_Soho" rel="noreferrer noopener">Palermo Soho</a>&nbsp;</strong>and at the same time lower the food. Palermo Soho is one of the two parts of the area called Palermo Viejo. It is a recently renovated area where there are numerous craft and fashion stores, galleries and restaurants full of design. Ideal for doing some shopping! You can continue the path along the&nbsp;<strong>Armenia Square</strong>&nbsp;and have a coffee, mojito or similar in the place you like the most, there is no shortage of cool places.</p>



<p>Since to get to know a city you have to walk around it, mid-afternoon is a good time to go to&nbsp;<a href="https://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Palermo_Hollywood" target="_blank" data-type="link" data-id="https://es.wikipedia.org/wiki/Palermo_Hollywood" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Palermo Hollywood</strong></a>. On the way there is a very charming bar-bookstore, Crack-Up, at Costa Rica 4767. Palermo Hollywood is the perfect place to see some alternative theater in Buenos Aires. If that is your plan, there are countless cool places to dine in the area, although I am clear that I would dine at Club Eros, the typical traditional place with good prices and a spectacular chorizo steak!!! I have to thank Ana and Martín, some friends who live there, for showing it to me.</p>



<p>To end the day (or start the night, depending on how you look at it) what better way to go than to Serrano, a couple of “blocks” beyond Club Eros. In Serrano Square there are a lot of lively places and for those who want to go clubbing in the area later there are plenty. In this link of clubs in Buenos Aires you can see some, I don&#039;t dare to recommend because I was only in one. But if anyone who reads us knows, we appreciate suggestions.</p>



<p>What can&#039;t you miss in the other Baires neighborhoods?</p>



<ul class="wp-block-list">
<li><strong>Recoleta</strong>. Visit the generic Floralio. Highly recommended guided tour of the Recoleta cemetery with Eduardo Lazzari, an expert historian in Buenos Aires and, of course, the El Ateneo bookstore.</li>



<li><strong>Congress and Courts</strong>. Visit the Teatro Colón.</li>



<li><strong>Withdrawal</strong>. I wouldn&#039;t highlight anything to visit, it is a cool but dangerous area.</li>



<li><strong>San Telmo</strong>. A must visit on Sundays to its market.</li>



<li><strong>Microcenter</strong>. A coffee or even a tango at Café Tortoni, one of the most famous and beautiful cafes in the world.</li>



<li><strong>Boca neighborhood</strong>. El Caminito and the Boca stadium. If you can&#039;t see a match live, at least visit its museum.</li>



<li><strong>Madero Port</strong>. Explore it on foot, passing through the Puente de la Mujer and as a recommended restaurant (thanks Flavio Bastos) go to Cabaña las Lilas.</li>
</ul>



<p>Have you been to Buenos Aires? What would you add to what has been discussed here?</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/what-to-see-in-buenos-aires-in-one-day/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bangkok in a Day</title>
		<link>/en/bangkok-in-one-day/</link>
					<comments>/en/bangkok-in-one-day/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 05:40:57 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=1596</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bangkok es la capital de Tailandia y una ciudad enorme con una oferta inmesa. Recorrer sus calles en un sólo día parece todo un reto, pero es posible si nos organizamos bien y si nos conformamos con ver lo imprescindible. Así, si nos calzamos las deportivas podemos visitar por la mañana la Zona Antigua y...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bangkok is the capital of Thailand and a huge city with an immense offer. Walking its streets in a single day seems like a challenge, but it is possible if we organize ourselves well and if we settle for seeing what is essential. Thus, if we put on our sneakers we can visit the Old Town and the Temples of Bangkok in the morning, while we will make a stop at the Canal Walk and the Night Market to close the day. Ready?</p>



<p><strong>Recommended Tours</strong></p>



<div data-gyg-href="https://widget.getyourguide.com/default/activities.frame" data-gyg-locale-code="es-ES" data-gyg-widget="activities" data-gyg-number-of-items="2" data-gyg-cmp="titanic_belfast_post" data-gyg-partner-id="0IM174M" data-gyg-q="Bangkok"></div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">In the morning&nbsp;</h2>



<p>We will start the day strong, so have a good breakfast and get psyched for an intense day. We will first set foot in the Grand Palace, one of the most emblematic symbols of the city. It dates back to 1782 and served as the official residence of the King of Thailand for 200 years. Inside you can discover the wonderful Wat Phra Kaeo, home of the Emerald Buddha. It is the most revered Buddha image in all of Thailand, so remember to show respect in the Temple. Later there is the option of visiting Wat Pho, the oldest temple in Bangkok built in the 16th century.</p>



<p>Once you have visited the main temples, one possibility is to take the ferry at Tha Tien Pier to cross to the other great temple in the city, Wat Arun. In addition, in the port there are numerous fish and craft stalls with very interesting things. From there you can reach the famous Temple of Dawn, one of the most famous monuments in Bangkok.<strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img  loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="770" height="511"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/7419257196_9e677a5cf6_k-770x511-1.jpg"  alt="" class="wp-image-1619" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/7419257196_9e677a5cf6_k-770x511-1.jpg 770w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/7419257196_9e677a5cf6_k-770x511-1-300x199.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/7419257196_9e677a5cf6_k-770x511-1-768x510.jpg 768w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/7419257196_9e677a5cf6_k-770x511-1-18x12.jpg 18w" sizes="(max-width: 770px) 100vw, 770px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Photo: Mark Fischer</figcaption></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Where to eat</h2>



<p>Taking advantage of the fact that we are in Thailand, we cannot miss the opportunity to enjoy Thai food. There are numerous local businesses where you can eat at a very affordable price. Whether rice or chicken, fried pork or noodles, you will find them very tasty. You can find these types of stalls all over Bangkok, although taking advantage of the fact that you have just taken the ferry, in that less touristy area they will offer you a more interesting menu.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">In the afternoon</h2>



<p>Well fed, it&#039;s time to fly across the China Town pier, Bangkok&#039;s Chinatown. From there it is a good option to continue to the Pahurat Market to have some souvenirs from Thailand. In addition, you can take the opportunity to continue along the route of Sampang Lane, Wat Mangkon Kamalawat and Wat Traimit.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full" id="attachment_26362"><img  loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="599" height="387"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/16742665464_b20901419e_k-e1476951334429.jpg"  alt="" class="wp-image-1620" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/16742665464_b20901419e_k-e1476951334429.jpg 599w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/16742665464_b20901419e_k-e1476951334429-300x194.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/16742665464_b20901419e_k-e1476951334429-18x12.jpg 18w" sizes="(max-width: 599px) 100vw, 599px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Photo: Bernard Spragg. NZ</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Finally, if you feel like doing some shopping in the most famous shopping center, you can stop by the MBK. However, if you prefer something more authentic in the Silom area, one option is the famous Patpong night market.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">At night</h2>



<p>With the sunset it is a good opportunity to take a walk along the busy and lively Khao San Road. It is a very authentic neighborhood with many live music venues. Thailand has a lot to offer in this sense, so you can&#039;t leave Bangkok without a beer in a traditional place. The people will be very friendly, especially in this tourist area, so take advantage of their hospitality to discover the real Thailand.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/bangkok-in-one-day/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/F4-3ORm-vEw" medium="video" width="1280" height="720">
			<media:player url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/F4-3ORm-vEw" />
			<media:title type="plain">Bangkok in 1 day. Tour</media:title>
			<media:description type="html"><![CDATA[Lo mejor de Bangkok en 1 día.En el vídeo de hoy os contamos nuestro tour de 1 día por Bangkok. Si tenéis pocos días en esta gran ciudad os dejamos esta opció...]]></media:description>
			<media:thumbnail url="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/The-Chao-Phraya-River-as-it-passes-through-Bangkok-thailand.jpg" />
			<media:rating scheme="urn:simple">nonadult</media:rating>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zagreb in a DAY</title>
		<link>/en/zagreb-in-one-day/</link>
					<comments>/en/zagreb-in-one-day/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 05:39:52 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=1594</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cuando elegí la capital de Croacia&#160;como mi destino Erasmus, muchas cosas se pasaban por mi cabeza. Cómo sería la gente, la cultura, el clima, la forma de vida… Y lo cierto es que esta aventura en la que me sumergí hace un par de meses ha conseguido cautivarme y ha hecho que dentro de mí...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I chose the capital of Croatia as my Erasmus destination, many things were going through my head. What would the people be like, the culture, the climate, the way of life... And the truth is that this adventure that I immersed myself in a couple of months ago has managed to captivate me and has made me have a little bit of Hrvatska inside me. Ready to discover&nbsp;<strong>Zagreb in one day</strong>&nbsp;from the hand of an intrepid Galician?</p>



<p><strong>Recommended Tours</strong></p>



<div data-gyg-href="https://widget.getyourguide.com/default/activities.frame" data-gyg-locale-code="es-ES" data-gyg-widget="activities" data-gyg-number-of-items="2" data-gyg-partner-id="0IM174M" data-gyg-q="Zagreb%20croatia"></div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">IN THE MORNING</h2>



<p>The first stop for any foreigner is Bana Josipa Jelačića Square, famous for its large statue and clock. Both points are used by young people to meet since it is the heart of the city. From there, we can move in any direction since&nbsp;<strong>The size of the historic center allows us to visit practically all the monuments in one morning</strong>.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><strong>My recommendation is to go up in the direction of Tkalčićeva Ulica, the street with the highest proportion of bars and pubs per square meter. It is a pedestrian street made up only of this type of establishments, so if you need to gain strength with a coffee, it is the best option.</strong></p>
</blockquote>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img  loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="599" height="449"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Iglesia-de-San-Marcos_Zagreb.jpg"  alt="St. Mark&#039;s Church_Zagreb" class="wp-image-1614" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Iglesia-de-San-Marcos_Zagreb.jpg 599w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Iglesia-de-San-Marcos_Zagreb-300x225.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Iglesia-de-San-Marcos_Zagreb-16x12.jpg 16w" sizes="(max-width: 599px) 100vw, 599px" /></figure></div>


<p>Furthermore, if you walk to the end of the street, you will see&nbsp;<strong>a small fritu stand</strong>, small typical Croatian buns served with Nutella or sugar (wonderful). Continue towards the upper part of the city to reach the famous church of San Marcos, whose roof delights tourists. However, do not delay too long because&nbsp;<strong>The best is behind the Kula Lotršćak bell tower: you will fall in love with the views of the entire city</strong>. Finally, you can take the opportunity to visit the Museum of Broken Relationships which is located in that part of Zagreb and go down the stairs on the left to reach the Cathedral.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">WHERE TO EAT</h2>



<p>A good option is to visit&nbsp;<strong>the Dolac</strong>, the municipal market, and discover typical Croatian products through its stalls. It is located very close to the Cathedral, so you will have no problem finding it. Right next door you will see several restaurants and at the end of everything,&nbsp;<strong>a small white tiled shop that only sells burek, one of the typical foods along with Ćevapi and Pljeskavica</strong>&nbsp;(although these two are more Serbian than Croatian). Choose between meat, cheese or apple and enjoy the fat flowing down into your stomachs! But if you are in a healthy mode, you can always pay a little more and enjoy a good fish or a well-prepared meat dish. Many times eating out is even cheaper than cooking at home, so do your research, 😉</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">IN THE AFTERNOON</h2>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img  loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="599" height="449"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Vistas-Zagreb.jpg"  alt="Views Zagreb" class="wp-image-1615" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Vistas-Zagreb.jpg 599w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Vistas-Zagreb-300x225.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Vistas-Zagreb-16x12.jpg 16w" sizes="(max-width: 599px) 100vw, 599px" /></figure></div>


<p>With a full stomach you can have a coffee at Vincek, whose cakes will surprise you. On this occasion, walk in the opposite direction to that in the morning to reach Tomislava Square. There is the Arts &amp; Crafts Museum, a beautiful building both inside and out. If you continue straight you will come across&nbsp;<strong>Glavni Kolovdor, the large train station from which you will have a good perspective to take a souvenir photo</strong>. Additionally, I recommend visiting the National Theater; You can say that you are art students and they may let you see some work for free standing up. Worth!</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><strong>If all this were not enough, take a tram to Maksimir Park and walk among its lakes to relax your body and mind.</strong></p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">AT NIGHT</h2>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img  loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="599" height="449"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Pepermint-Zagreb.jpg"  alt="Peppermint Zagreb" class="wp-image-1616" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Pepermint-Zagreb.jpg 599w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Pepermint-Zagreb-300x225.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Pepermint-Zagreb-16x12.jpg 16w" sizes="(max-width: 599px) 100vw, 599px" /></figure></div>


<p>The nightlife in Zagreb is very varied. Thus, everything will depend on your tastes. If you like the&nbsp;<strong>rock</strong>, don&#039;t leave without having a beer in Alcatraz. One of my favorite bars both for its decoration, its location and its music. If you are more than&nbsp;<strong>jazz</strong>, you are in luck. Bacchus, Melin and Booze and Blues will be your favorite destinations. Remember to review the events (there are many every week) and choose the one you like the most. If he&nbsp;<strong>techno</strong>&nbsp;It&#039;s your thing, one of the best underground areas of Zagreb is home to several buildings converted into clubs. You will love Depo and Museum Katran.</p>



<p>Finally, for those who do not have such defined tastes, any bar in Tkalčićeva is good to start the night and you can end up at Pepermint or History Village. Yes indeed,&nbsp;<strong>Ziraffa is a mandatory stop whatever your plans are</strong>. The cheapest place in Zagreb to have a drink!</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/zagreb-in-one-day/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<media:content url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Upv9EeQpYK8" medium="video" width="1280" height="720">
			<media:player url="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Upv9EeQpYK8" />
			<media:title type="plain">Zagreb from a bicycle view</media:title>
			<media:description type="html"><![CDATA[¡Vídeo para The Fun Plan para ilustrar la capital de Croacia!]]></media:description>
			<media:thumbnail url="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Art-Pavilion-zagreb-croatia.jpg" />
			<media:rating scheme="urn:simple">nonadult</media:rating>
		</media:content>
	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rome in a Day</title>
		<link>/en/rome-in-a-day/</link>
					<comments>/en/rome-in-a-day/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 05:37:00 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=1592</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ciao viajeros! Haced las maletas porque, ¡nos vamos a Roma! La capital italiana es una de las quince ciudades más visitadas del mundo y es que, además de tener mucha historia, es una de las paradas obligatorias en cualquier&#160;crucero por el Mediterráneo&#160;o circuito por Europa. Seguro que si estáis preparando vuestro viaje, tenéis una interminable...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Ciao travelers! Pack your bags because we&#039;re going to Rome! The Italian capital is one of the fifteen most visited cities in the world and, in addition to having a lot of history, it is one of the obligatory stops in any&nbsp;<a href="/en/mediterranean-cruises-end-of-year-trip/" data-type="link" data-id="/cruceros-mediterraneo-viaje-fin-de-curso/">Mediterranean cruise</a>&nbsp;or circuit through Europe. Surely if you are preparing your trip, you have an endless list of things to do in Rome, but how are you going to organize yourself? So that you don&#039;t go without seeing anything, Héctor and Cris have given us the best recommendations to see&nbsp;<strong>Rome in a day</strong>.</p>



<p><strong>Recommended Tours</strong></p>



<div data-gyg-href="https://widget.getyourguide.com/default/activities.frame" data-gyg-locale-code="es-ES" data-gyg-widget="activities" data-gyg-number-of-items="2" data-gyg-partner-id="0IM174M" data-gyg-q="rome%20italy"></div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">In the morning</h2>



<p>Do you like coffee? If the answer is yes, you can start the day with a cappuccino, espresso, macchiato... Which is your favorite? You have many to choose from! You can take the opportunity to have a good breakfast because a very busy day awaits you.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-full"><img  loading="lazy" decoding="async" width="700" height="525"  src="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Roma-en-un-dia.jpg"  alt="" class="wp-image-1610" srcset="https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Roma-en-un-dia.jpg 700w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Roma-en-un-dia-300x225.jpg 300w, https://thefunplan.b-cdn.net/uploads/2023/10/Roma-en-un-dia-16x12.jpg 16w" sizes="(max-width: 700px) 100vw, 700px" /></figure></div>


<p>We begin our route through the&nbsp;<strong>Coliseum</strong>, also known as the Flavian Amphitheater. If you want to have a good view,&nbsp;<strong>We recommend that you get there via the Via del Colosseo</strong>, since this way you will be able to see it in its entirety and take the best photographs, we want to see them all! You can purchase the ticket on the same day you go to visit, but we recommend that you arrive early as there is usually a bit of a wait. The schedules vary depending on the month you go, so it is best to check them here. If you have a student card, don&#039;t forget it! In Rome, if you are students, in some of the monuments you will have discounts of up to 50%.</p>



<p>After seeing the stage where the famous fights of gladiators and wild beasts were once held, it is best that you go to the<strong>&nbsp;Roman Forum,</strong>&nbsp;the most important archaeological zone of the city. Although it is very well maintained, you will need some imagination to get an idea of what it was like in the past, since it was the place in the city where commercial, political and religious life took place.&nbsp;<strong>The entrance is the same as the Colosseum, don&#039;t forget to save it to continue using it!</strong></p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><strong>Did you know that the Romans gave their constructions an important propaganda and communicative function with the intention of producing a mix of effects between wonder and fear?</strong>&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>We will continue going through Plaza Venezia, where you will find a building that will catch your attention due to its size and how white it is. It is known as Vittoriano and from its terraces you will have a 360º view of the city: from the Colosseum and the Imperial Forums, to the historic center, the Tiber River, the Jewish ghetto or the modern EUR neighborhood.</p>



<p>After our stop along the way, we arrived at the&nbsp;<strong>Campidoglio square</strong>, still considered one of the most elegant squares in Europe today. From the back of the square you will have one of the best views of the Forum and in the square itself is access to the&nbsp;<strong>Capitoline Museums</strong>. Art lovers, you have arrived at one of your temples! Sculptures such as the Capitoline Wolf, paintings by Bellinni and Caravaggio and statues such as Marcus Aurelius are just some of the works that you will find. You will also find it very curious to see the different portraits of the emperors of Rome. We recommend that before you go, you choose which works you are most interested in seeing. This way you won&#039;t be left without seeing any of the essential ones and you won&#039;t need too much time to find them.</p>



<h3 class="wp-block-heading">To Eat</h3>



<p>If we continue our route towards&nbsp;<strong>the Pantheon area and the Plaza de la Rotonda where you will find various trattorias and restaurants</strong>&nbsp;where you can taste delicious pasta dishes and rest for a while. As in many other cities, you will find many Italians outside restaurants with special menus for tourists, usually consisting of pasta or bruschetta as a starter and pizza as a main course. If you want to try the best artisanal pasta, we recommend that you do not get carried away by them and choose a place that, although less economical, gives you the guarantee that it has a careful and homemade kitchen.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">In the afternoon</h2>



<p>After a good meal we will go to the&nbsp;<strong>Pantheon</strong>, one of the most impressive temples of all time dedicated to all the gods. Currently it serves as a reference and meeting point, so it is the perfect time for you to meet other groups or have a drink while you enjoy one of the&nbsp;<strong>street shows</strong>&nbsp;which there usually is.</p>



<p>The&nbsp;<strong>Navona Square</strong>&nbsp;It is the most beautiful and traditional in all of Rome. It is surrounded by narrow streets that you will love to walk through and you will be amazed by its size and the buildings and sculptures that make it up. If you like postcards and engravings, it is the perfect time for you to get some, since&nbsp;<strong>There are usually numerous painters and artists around the square.</strong>. As you will have had time to lower the food a little, you can also take the opportunity to try one of the best ice creams of your life in the&nbsp;<strong>Mariotti ice cream parlor.</strong></p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><strong>There are ice creams of all the flavors you can imagine and up to seven different types of chocolates! Will you be able to choose just one?</strong>&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>We continue our journey going towards&nbsp;<strong>Spain Square</strong>, we cannot go to a European city and not see “our” square! It is a garden area where there is also a lot of atmosphere during the day and where all the haute couture fashion stores in Rome come from, so you can go for a walk to see the latest models or sit on the steps of the square to do a stop along the way and, at the same time, feel what Italian life is like.</p>



<p>To end our afternoon, we recommend that you head towards Vía Poli to reach the&nbsp;<strong>Fontana di Trevi</strong>. Upon arriving along this street, the impression of seeing the Fontana will be much greater since we see little by little how we are getting closer to it.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><strong>Tradition says that you have to take a coin and throw it into the fountain with your back to it while making a wish. Will it be fulfilled for you?</strong>&nbsp;</p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">At night</h2>



<p>Did you think the day was already over? We still have to discover the Italian night! Path of the&nbsp;<strong>Trastevere neighborhood</strong>, you can stop in the&nbsp;<strong>Mouth of Truth</strong>. Legend has it that if you tell a lie while you have your hand in your mouth, it will close. Will it be true?</p>



<p>Since we don&#039;t want to check it, we prefer to go in search of&nbsp;<strong>one of the best pizzas in Rome</strong>&nbsp;at the Carlo Menta restaurant. You will find pizzas at a very affordable price and a good size for all tastes.</p>



<p>When you finish dinner, we recommend that you take a walk through this neighborhood and take the opportunity to sit on one of its terraces to have a drink and enjoy the night like true Italians.</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/rome-in-a-day/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rennes in a Day</title>
		<link>/en/rennes-in-a-day/</link>
					<comments>/en/rennes-in-a-day/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 05:35:32 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=1589</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dicen de Bretaña que es la Galicia francesa, pero os prometo que es aún más bonita… No sólo lo digo por ser de allí, sino que es el&#160;segundo destino más elegido por los franceses&#160;para pasar sus vacaciones. Hoy os llevo a Rennes, o&#160;Roazhon&#160;en bretón. Aunque sea la capital de Bretaña, Rennes se puede visitar en...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>They say about Brittany that it is French Galicia, but I promise you that it is even more beautiful... I am not just saying this because I am from there, but it is the&nbsp;<strong>second destination most chosen by the French</strong>&nbsp;to spend your vacation. Today I&#039;m taking you to Rennes, or&nbsp;<em>Roazhon</em>&nbsp;in Breton. Although it is the capital of Brittany, Rennes can be visited in one day since its historic center is very concentrated. If I had to compare it with any Spanish city, I would say that it is built more or less like Malaga, so everything essential can be done on foot. Will you accompany me?</p>



<p><strong>Recommended Tours</strong></p>



<div data-gyg-href="https://widget.getyourguide.com/default/activities.frame" data-gyg-locale-code="es-ES" data-gyg-widget="activities" data-gyg-number-of-items="2" data-gyg-partner-id="0IM174M" data-gyg-q="rennes%20france"></div>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">In the morning</h2>



<p>We started the day with breakfast on the terrace of La Kitchenette, located on Rue Jules Simon, right next to the central market of Rennes. The place is cozy and warm, as are the two managers.<strong>&nbsp;All products are made by local companies</strong>, among which you can try toast with salted butter and homemade jam or delicious cakes with artisanal juice.</p>



<p>Go up the street and pass under the arches of the Palacio del Comercio and you will arrive at the Plaza de la República. If you continue going up, you will find yourself in the central square of Rennes: the Town Hall. On the left, you can admire the&nbsp;<strong>Municipal Chamber, built after the great fire of 1720</strong>, and to the right is the&nbsp;<a href="https://www.opera-rennes.fr/fr" data-type="link" data-id="https://www.opera-rennes.fr/fr" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rennes Opera</a>. The opera building is part of an ambitious real estate project, it includes accommodation and shopping galleries, protected by glass. Its other peculiarity is that it adapts to the shape of the Municipal Chamber: the projection of this building responds to the opening of the town hall. A little further up you will find yourself on Rue Le Bastard, a pedestrian and commercial street.</p>



<p>After this, we will go to Place Sainte-Anne, surely the most famous square in the city, since it is the meeting place for all the&nbsp;<em>rennais</em>. It has lost a bit of its charm since it is under construction due to the construction of the second metro line. It surely catches your attention to see so many punks with mohawks surrounded by dogs! These are part of the landscape&nbsp;<em>rennais</em>.&nbsp;<strong>You can go visit the Saint-Aubin Church which is in the square, or if it is Saturday, take a walk to the&nbsp;<em>Marché des Lices</em>, the third market in France that has existed since 1622.</strong></p>



<p>It&#039;s time to eat! In France, meal time is around 12:30 or 1:00 p.m. On Rue de Penhoët is one of the best crêperies in Rennes, La Rozell.&nbsp;<strong>I recommend trying the L&#039;Armorique galette, with scallops and mushrooms, without forgetting to order a bowl of Breton cider. And finish with a banana crêpe with melted chocolate and coconut shavings!</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">In the afternoon</h2>



<p>In the mood for a nap? There is no better place than Thabor Park, one of the most beautiful gardens in France that covers 10 hectares in the heart of the city. You can take a walk through its French and English gardens, its rose gardens, its statues, its aviary, its kiosk... You will love it!</p>



<p>After digestion with the walk through the park, you have the possibility of visiting the&nbsp;<strong>Parliament of Brittany</strong>. It is an impressive monument drawn by the architect of the Luxembourg Palace and marked by the most important times in the region: the sealed paper revolt or the fight against royal absolutism. The Great Chamber is the jewel of Parliament.</p>



<p>If you fancy a beer (Breton, of course!), you can choose one of the terraces on the Place du Champ Jacquet. If you look at the houses that surround the square, you will discover the most typical characteristics of the architecture of this city.</p>



<p>To end the afternoon, you can take a walk around the&nbsp;<strong>old town, without forgetting to pass through the Rue du Chapitre, the Portes Mordelaises with its drawbridge, rue Vasselot, the Cathédrale St-Pierre, etc.</strong>.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">At night</h2>



<p><strong>For dinner, I recommend the mussels from L&#039;Abri du Marché</strong>&nbsp;above the Place des Lices, but if you prefer to eat something quickly, head to Rue Saint-Michel, the street of bars, renamed “thirst street” by the&nbsp;<em>rennais</em>, and ask for a&nbsp;<em>galette-saucisse</em>&nbsp;at Alex&#039;s Taverne bar, the city&#039;s specialty.</p>



<p>You are now in the heart of the party! Keep in mind that here the bars close a little earlier than in Spain (around one in the morning), but then you can go to “night bars”, which close around three or spend the night at a club. The most picturesque is, without a doubt,<strong>&nbsp;le Delicatessen, the building was a former prison from the 15th century!</strong></p>



<p>It&#039;s time to return to your hotel. And when you get up the next day, take the train to Saint-Malo to spend your hangover on the beach in the city of corsairs!</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/rennes-in-a-day/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>BUDAPEST, CITY OF SPAS</title>
		<link>/en/budapest-city-of-spas/</link>
					<comments>/en/budapest-city-of-spas/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 05:28:57 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=1582</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Cuesta imaginar el lugar que se ha convertido en todo un símbolo de la capital de Hungría. Fiestas en aguas termales, luces de colores y la música tecno ilumina el ambiente. Los&#160;balnearios de la ciudad de Budapest&#160;son todo un símbolo de la historia reconvertido en una seña de identidad de la cultura hípster europea. ¿La...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It is difficult to imagine the place that has become a symbol of the capital of Hungary. Parties in hot springs, colorful lights and techno music light up the atmosphere. The&nbsp;<a href="/en/journey/" target="_blank" data-type="page" data-id="815" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Budapest city spas</strong></a>&nbsp;They are a symbol of history converted into a hallmark of European hipster culture.</p>



<p>The latest fashion? Not at all. The baths where the so-called Magic Bath or CineTrip are now held were already in the spotlight during Roman and Ottoman times. He wasn&#039;t the last successful DJ who was DJing, his success lay in therapeutic powers, pure magic.&nbsp;<strong>Budapest</strong>&nbsp;It was the place of worship for those who suffered from congenital, traumatological or degenerative diseases, since its waters tempered their pain and the minerals, the material that keeps them standing, healed the wounds - body and mind - of everyone who gave in to dive.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><strong>No traveler can resist the pleasure of swimming in the warm waters, especially if you visit the city during winter with temperatures hovering around minus 37 degrees.</strong></p>
</blockquote>



<p>Decade after decade, in 1934 Budapest was proclaimed&nbsp;<em>City of Spas</em>. Around 70 million liters of water every day that satisfy the appetite of 118 springs. A pleasure that Romans, Ottomans, and Austro-Hungarians have enjoyed and that today is appreciated by the city&#039;s inhabitants, who make the most of it.</p>



<p>All the inhabitants? Exceptionally. It was not until the middle of the 20th century that women could begin to use it, a pleasure until now only reserved exclusively for men. What must it be like to experience one more step towards the right to equality? Even today, many spas only allow “mixed” entry on weekends and during the BathParty, during the week it is exclusively for men only or only for women.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p><strong>From a game of chess to a late-night party surrounded by a neo-Gothic building, everything is possible in the heat of spas like Széchenyi from 1913.</strong></p>
</blockquote>



<p>The MagicBath experience must be incredible, but more incredible, from my point of view, must be the experience of feeling that you are enjoying and soaking your body in the place that Roman women were deprived of due to their condition, no. so to men. Places that were a meeting center for intellectuals like Lucacks Bath, what could not be debated between baths!</p>



<p>A different and completely alternative vision of the city separated by the Danube, the mountains, the plain and its parliament. Immersing yourself in its thermal baths means reliving the history of Hungary, past and present marked by its water springs and why not? The best way to end&nbsp;<strong>Budapest </strong><strong><a href="/en/budapest-in-one-day/" target="_blank" data-type="link" data-id="/budapest-en-un-dia/" rel="noreferrer noopener">and</a></strong><strong>n one day</strong>!</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/budapest-city-of-spas/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Most Famous Nightclubs in Warsaw</title>
		<link>/en/most-famous-nightclubs-in-warsaw/</link>
					<comments>/en/most-famous-nightclubs-in-warsaw/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[marcellones]]></dc:creator>
		<pubdate>Sun, 15 Oct 2023 05:18:28 +0000</pubdate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<guid ispermalink="false">/?p=1574</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[¿Queréis saber cuál es el plato fuerte de Varsovia? Exacto chicos,&#160;¡su fiesta!&#160;La vida nocturna de esta ciudad polaca ha mejorado considerablemente con el paso de los años. Podréis empezar con una copa en cualquier bar y acabar liándoos hasta tarde por la diversidad de clubs, pubs y discotecas que encontraréis a lo largo de sus...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Do you want to know what the highlight of Warsaw is? Exactly guys,<strong>&nbsp;his party!&nbsp;</strong>The nightlife of this Polish city has improved considerably over the years. You can start with a drink in any bar and end up partying until late in the diversity of clubs, pubs and discos that you will find along its streets. Definitely,&nbsp;<strong>guaranteed fun!</strong>&nbsp;What we like! And that is why today we bring you the&nbsp;<strong>Most famous nightclubs in Warsaw.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">HYBRYDY KLUB</h2>



<p>ZLOTA 7/9</p>



<p>If what you are looking for is the typical place where you can meet more university people, Erasmus students, etc., then this is your club!&nbsp;<strong>Hybrydy Klub&nbsp;</strong>It is one of the best-known nightclubs in Warsaw as well as one of the most frequented by all tourists. Besides,<strong>&nbsp;Opens every day!</strong>&nbsp;Yeah! You heard right! And of&nbsp;<strong>9pm to 4am</strong>&nbsp;, so you can take advantage of the night, without going to bed too late and without having to suffer a horrible hangover the next day. Not only that, but it is also one of the clubs with the most atmosphere and you will always see people in this club.</p>



<p>As for music, what you will mainly listen to will be commercial music so you can dance and sing until you are exhausted!</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">ENKLAWA KLUB</h2>



<p>MAZOWIECKA 12</p>



<p>One of the most fashionable clubs in the Polish capital and mostly frequented by all the young people of the city. Decorated with a modern touch based on marble pillars with great lighting around it in a light fuchsia tone that gives a lot of color to the entire room. Likewise, the furniture it has, along with the lighting we have talked about, gives the place a very elegant touch. Open almost every day,<strong>&nbsp;Tuesday to Saturday from 10 p.m. to 4 a.m.&nbsp;</strong>In addition, it organizes great events and celebrations almost every day, which is why we recommend it as one of the<strong>&nbsp;Essential nightclubs you should go to!</strong></p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>For all of you who do not want to miss any detail of all the&nbsp;<a href="http://www.enklawa.com/" target="_blank" data-type="link" data-id="http://www.enklawa.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Eve</strong></a><strong><a href="https://enklawa.com/" target="_blank" data-type="link" data-id="https://enklawa.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener">n</a></strong><a href="http://www.enklawa.com/" target="_blank" data-type="link" data-id="http://www.enklawa.com/" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>cough made&nbsp;</strong></a></p>
</blockquote>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">ROOM 13 CLUB</h2>



<p>MAZOWIECKA 13</p>



<p>If, on the other hand, what you are thinking about most is the desire you have to get ready and put on your best clothes, then you have to go to Room 13. The true most fashionable club in the entire city, frequented mostly by all the people pretty from there. In addition, you can find the best DJs there making you enjoy the best of your nights.</p>



<p>Likewise, in terms of hours, this club is open fewer days than the others, so&nbsp;<strong>Thursday to Sunday from 10 p.m. to 4 a.m.</strong>, but don&#039;t worry, because if there is one thing this club guarantees, it is that you will have the night of your lives and also, the girls will be able to enjoy a large amount of alcohol&nbsp;<strong>free!</strong></p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">SKETCH NITE</h2>



<p>MAZOWIECKA 11</p>



<p>Located in the heart of the city&#039;s nightlife, this club offers two very different plans within the same building. On the first floor, you will find a&nbsp;<strong>large bar area</strong>&nbsp;so that you can warm up your engines and then go up to the second, where you can move your navel<strong>&nbsp;everything you want and more!&nbsp;</strong>This club is only open&nbsp;<strong>Fridays and Saturdays</strong>&nbsp;but following a very Spanish rhythm,&nbsp;<strong>11:45 p.m. to 6 a.m.&nbsp;</strong>A complete non-stop! Likewise, although it may seem like a high-priced club, we must tell you that the opposite is true, and that is that entry costs nothing more than&nbsp;<strong>5 euros!&nbsp;</strong>Have a good time at outrageous prices? That&#039;s what Warsaw is known for!</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow">
<p>Ready to take a getaway to the Polish capital? Looking for party, nap, repeat? Here we bring you the&nbsp;<strong>best accommodations</strong>&nbsp;so you can recharge your batteries and continue!</p>
</blockquote>



<p>If you are able to find a space to explore the Polish capital, we leave you a link to our post&nbsp;<a href="/en/warsaw-in-one-day/" target="_blank" data-type="link" data-id="/varsovia-en-un-dia/" rel="noreferrer noopener"><strong>Warsaw in one day</strong></a>, where you will find the best recommendations so that not only the party is a 10, but the entire day! We fly?</p>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentrss>/en/most-famous-nightclubs-in-warsaw/feed/</wfw:commentrss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>